<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Quarto Blog</title>
<link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.2.269</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 07:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Gift from Above</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230223 gift from above/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Received another round of gift from above – moisture – in the form of mixed precipitation or sleet.</p>
<section id="magical-winter-scenes" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="magical-winter-scenes">Magical Winter Scenes</h2>
<p>Earlier in the month, wife asked,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Are you getting tired of removing snow from the sidewalk?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I could have agreed with her, Instead I said,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I enjoy shoveling snow.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Since each snowflakes are unique Each storm brings, slightly different type of snow. Each snow removing session is also unique and a strategy driven event.</p>
<p>Use the <code>shovel-and-throw-over-shoulder</code> approach or the <code>plow-until-you-can't-push</code></p>
<p>It is magical how snow reaches the ground and covers everything.</p>
<ul>
<li>How are layers of snow deposited on surfaces?
<ul>
<li>It it temperature driven?</li>
<li>Is there a industrial equivalence?</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Which factors determine rain, freezing rain and snow?</li>
</ul>
<p>[Not only the scene but the sound changes after snow, things are more serene and quieter.]</p>
<p>There are short term decisions. Where to dine, which country to visit, who to date.</p>
<p>Then there are longer term decisions. Which food to avoid and how much to intake, which neighborhood to set up home, who to commit to and live this life together.</p>
<p>The decision to live in Utah, with its long and snowy winter, was made decades ago.</p>
<p>Decided to take spring wild flowers, summer heat, fall foliage, as well as the winter storms.</p>
<p>(Thus gladly accepting inches of gift of moisture in a high desert),</p>
<p>Rather than judging a place by short visits, there are many who made decisions to make Utah their home.</p>
<p>As well as those that have decided that desert southwest will be their home - year round.</p>
<p>As my sister in Arizona says,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Arizona have summer monthss, and Utah has its winter months, as burdens to bear.</p>
</blockquote>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230223 gift from above/images/20230320_073227-01 (1).jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Arizona in the Winter, 2023</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>[But if one avoids the place, job, relationship because of limited exposure to extremes or based on rumors or writings on internet, then one misses out on the opportunity to see and experience the abundance of nature, a chance for an advancement and expanding and enriching friendship]</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230223 gift from above/images/IMG_7738.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Snow Patrol, Provo December 2007.</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>There was time when I wished for snow.</p>
<p>Having a snow plow equipped, 4-wheeler meant, snow removal was something to look forward to.</p>
<p>Now days, if someone offered to clean my sidewalk, wonder how I would respond.</p>
<ul>
<li>how would I spend the time saved</li>
<li>lose out on the opportunity to exercise</li>
</ul>
<p>It is a great feeling to see the clean sidewalk, that would take less than 30 minutes to clear.</p>
<p>The warm weather is most effective means of snow removal.</p>
<p>One develops sense of when to pick up the shovel, or wait on benevolence of neighbors or nature.</p>
<p>As I grow older, hope that I have the strength and fortitude of this gentleman in Park City.</p>
<p>[Vic, in his 90s, is a former miner that lives near the ski area]</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230223 gift from above/images/IMG_1052.CR2.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Vic of Park City, March 2019</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>gratitude</category>
  <category>neighbors</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230223 gift from above/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230223 gift from above/IMAG0997.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mom’s Early Days : In her own words</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230219 mom history/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="excerpts-from-moms-early-days-written-by-mom." class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="excerpts-from-moms-early-days-written-by-mom.">Excerpts from <code>Mom's Early Days</code>, written by mom.</h2>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230219 mom history/images/Epson_02192023180029(1).jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Mom’s Early Days</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>우리 엄마 사정을 본 이모는 한 명을 데려가서 공부를 시키겠다고 했다.</p>
<p>처음에는 내가 갈 예정이었는데 엄마가 싫어해서 동생 현숙 이를 보냈다.</p>
<p>그리고는 1947년인지 48년인지 기억이 잘 안 난다.</p>
<p>그럼 몇 번 소식을 들었다.</p>
<p>그렇게 헤어지고 이때까지 보지도 듣지도 못 했다.</p>
<p>지금은 얼굴조차 잘 생각이 안 난다.</p>
<p>너무너무 보고 싶은 내 동생 현숙이,</p>
<p>내가 어찌 잊을 수 있겠는지</p>
<p>쌍둥이 같이 자랐고</p>
<p>눈물이 많아 같이 울고</p>
<p>고생도 같이한 내 동생 현숙이가 아닌가</p>
<p>너무 너무 보고싶고 그립다</p>
<p>내가 죽기 전에 꼭 한 번이라도 만나 봤으면 얼마나 좋겠는지</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>하나님 아버지 꼭 한 번이라도 만날 수 있도록 해 주세요</p>
<p>정말 정말 부탁합니다</p>
<p>진심으로 기도합니다</p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="a-recording-of-my-mom-recounting-her-familys-address" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-recording-of-my-mom-recounting-her-familys-address">A recording of my mom, recounting her family’s address</h2>
<figure class="figure">
<figcaption class="figure-caption">
Mom was 89 at the time
</figcaption>
<audio controls="" src="Mom recals address.mp3">
Your browser does not support the <code>audio</code> element.
</audio>
</figure>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230219 mom history/IMG_2293.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>recollection</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230219 mom history/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230219 mom history/20230217_180419-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Birthday Remembrance</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Want to thank my parents for taking away the fear and stigma associated with getting old and facing death.</p>
</blockquote>
<section id="birth-week" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="birth-week">Birth Week</h2>
<p>Mom and dad were born this week.</p>
<p>Even though we know their birthdays were Lunar Calendar based, we remembered their lunar birthdate on the Solar Calendar Date.</p>
<p>For example, my dad’s birtday is listed as February 12th, which would be March 11th. Still we had the celebration on February 12th.</p>
<p>Likewise, my mom’s would be celebrated on February 20th, instead of March 26th.</p>
<p>[My mom’s birthday would be 26 March 1932, and my dad’s would be 11 March 1930]</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/IMG_0510.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">March 2019</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Want to thank my parents for taking away the fear and stigma associated with getting old and facing death.</p>
<p>Our family was small growing up, on my mother and father’s side. Most family members stayed in North Korea, because everyone thought the War and the separation will be short lived.</p>
<p>Growing up, I saw funeral procession on the street or on TV for one of the relatives of the last monarch.</p>
<p>Most everyone I knew were young and vibrant.</p>
<p>Then our family moved to United States, where I was further removed from pain and suffering associated with death. After turning 20 did I learn that some of the relatives have passed away.</p>
</section>
<section id="maternal-grandmother-5-february-1914---25-november-1999" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="maternal-grandmother-5-february-1914---25-november-1999">Maternal Grandmother (5 February 1914 - 25 November 1999)</h2>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/kim_granma.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>First death of a family member, that I attended, was in the year I turned 37.</p>
<p>At the time I was working in Daegu and my grandmother lived in Incheon.</p>
<p>My maternal grandmother passed away at aged 87, who lived without her husband for nearly 60 years, after suffering from dementia. My aunt lovingly took care of her at home and she looked happy and well taken care of until her passing.</p>
<p>Felt the sorrow of 4 surviving sisters. My mother is the oldest and one that knows, intimately challenges of growing up fatherless. Adding to the sorrow was that her only son passed away when he was in his 40s.</p>
<p>Took on some of the male role that would be handled by male heirs. Felt the sorrow of family members as she was laid to rest.</p>
<p>The ceremony was done according to Christian traditions.</p>
</section>
<section id="paternal-grandmother-20-july-1911---2-may-2003" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="paternal-grandmother-20-july-1911---2-may-2003">Paternal Grandmother (20 July 1911 - 2 May 2003)</h2>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/kang_granma.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>My father’s mom, passed away a year after we returned to US.</p>
<p>My father’s youngest brother and his wife, took care of her for nearly 30 years. (it helped that uncle’s in-laws were trained nurses, they took care of grandmother before she became ill)</p>
<p>Similar to Kim Grandma, my grandmother also lost her husband, and lived alone for nearly 55 years.</p>
<p>My grandmother loved to farm and hike nearby mountains. She passed away at age 92. It was thought that, had she lived in the country, she would have lived another 10 years.</p>
<p>Through family connections, they were able to secure a proper burial place in the mountain. This is important in old Korean culture.</p>
<p>Was able to visit the grave site, two years later.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/IMG_0707.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="my-parents" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="my-parents">My Parents</h2>
<p>Both of my parents lived to be 90 years of age.</p>
<p>I am grateful that my parents, not only lived a full, long life but that they were able to communicate to us, until last days of their sojourn.</p>
<p>They were independent until the end.</p>
<p>They expressed their love and appreciation.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/IMG_0742.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">March 2016</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>There were no fear of passing through to the next life. Only sorrow at the separation from loved ones.</p>
<p>Learned through their lives that living and passing on is both necessary yet beautiful part of the Plan. The Plan that enables us to be born again.</p>
<p>No longer fearful about the as-of-yet not revealed part of life and death.</p>
<p>For my parents and my grandmothers have shown how to live courageously and face death peacefully.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/IMG_7159.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>recollections</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/20221206_085703.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Thou Shalt Rise! My Dust, Thou Shalt Arise</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230127 resurrection/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>26 그리고 나 야곱은 내가 반드시 곧 나의 무덤으로 내려갈 것임을 알아, 나의 아들 이노스에게 이르기를, 이 판을 맡으라 하고, 또 나의 형 니파이가 나에게 명한 것을 그에게 말하였더니, 그가 명에 복종할 것을 약속하였느니라. 이제 나는 이 판에 나의 기록함을 마치노니, 그 기록한 것이 작았을지라도 많은 나의 형제들이 내 말을 읽기를 바라며, 읽는 자에게 작별을 고하노라. 형제들아 잘 있으라.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>26 And it came to pass that I, Jacob, began to be old; and the record of this people being kept on the other plates of Nephi, wherefore, I conclude this record, declaring that I have written according to the best of my knowledge, by saying that the time passed away with us, and also our lives passed away like as it were unto us a dream, we being a lonesome and a solemn people, wanderers, cast out from Jerusalem, born in tribulation, in a wilderness, and hated of our brethren, which caused wars and contentions; wherefore, we did mourn out our days</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Jacob 7:26, Book of Mormon</p>
<p>My parents’ and my wife’s parents’ lives were as if a dream. They lived their lives mostly in solitary, lonesome world for them.</p>
<p>Through much tribulation, they tried their utmost against life’s challenges and left us a far better life.</p>
<section id="mourning-practice-in-old-korea" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="mourning-practice-in-old-korea">Mourning Practice in Old Korea</h2>
<p>When I was little, it was common to see those lost their parents to wear a marker on their clothes or on their hair. It was made from a particular clothes and shaped like a small bow tie.</p>
<p>In the olden days, a son was to build a shack by the tomb and spend 3 years of his life by the deceased. The logic was to pay back to parents what they did when we were little. 3 years of raising us, therefore spend 3 years of caretaker by the grave.</p>
<p>This type of reasoning did not survive the modern Korean thinking.</p>
<p>The introduction of Christianity and perhaps the increased practice of cremation may have brought about the certain demise of this practice.</p>
</section>
<section id="a-story-about-regrets" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-story-about-regrets">A story about regrets</h2>
<p>A well know story about not listening to one’s parents is told through a story about a wayward green frog.</p>
<p>There was a green frog that did exactly the opposite of what he was told. The mother frog tried to change the son, time and again she failed. She turned old and was about to die.</p>
<p>She made her final request.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“When I die, please bury me on the bank of a river”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When she died, the son followed her words this time.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“I always did the opposite of what she told me when she was alive,” he said to himself, “but now I will do exactly as she told me.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The green frog sat in the pouring rain by the river bank, crying and crying for his mother. And that is why, to this day, the green frogs cry when it rains.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sejongsociety.org/korean_theme/korean_folk_tales/green_frog.html#:~:text=Long%20ago%2C%20the%20green%20frog,go%20up%2C%20he%20went%20down.">Korean Folk Tales</a></p>
</section>
<section id="personal-regrets" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="personal-regrets">Personal Regrets</h2>
<p>2 things on my mind,</p>
<ul>
<li>Why didn’t I spend more time with them?</li>
<li>Why wasn’t I more kind to them when I was with them?</li>
</ul>
<p>The belief in Christianity and faith on Christ brings some solace.</p>
</section>
<section id="thou-shalt-rise-my-dust-thou-shalt-arise---1764" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="thou-shalt-rise-my-dust-thou-shalt-arise---1764">Thou Shalt Rise! My Dust, Thou Shalt Arise - 1764</h2>
<ul>
<li>Frederick Gottlieb Klopstock</li>
<li>1724-1803</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://hymnary.org/text/thou_shalt_rise_my_dust_thou_shalt_arise#pagescans">Thou shalt rise!</a></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Thou shalt rise! my dust, thou shalt arise!</p>
<p>Not always closed thine eyes:&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thy life's first Giver&nbsp;</p>
<p>Will give thee life forever,&nbsp;</p>
<p>Hallelujah!</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Sown in darkness but to blossom again,</p>
<p>When after winter's reign,</p>
<p>Jesus is reaping&nbsp;</p>
<p>The seed now quietly sleeping,&nbsp;</p>
<p>Hallelujah!</p>
<p><br>
</p>
<p>Day of praise! for thee, thou wondrous day,</p>
<p>In my own grave I stay;</p>
<p>And when I number&nbsp;</p>
<p>My days and nights of slumber,&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thou wakest me!</p>
<p><br>
</p>
<p>Then , as they who dream, we shall arise</p>
<p>With Jesus to the skies,</p>
<p>And find that morrow;</p>
<p>The weary pilgrim's sorrow</p>
<p>All past and gone!</p>
<p><br>
</p>
<p>Then shall I the path to Holiest tread,</p>
<p>By my Redeemer led,</p>
<p>Through heaven soaring,</p>
<p>His holy name adoring</p>
<p>Eternally!</p>
<p><br>
</p>
<p><a href="https://www.evangeliums.net/lieder/lied_auferstehn_ja_auferstehn_wirst_du.html">Auferstehn, ja auferstehn wirst du</a></p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="urlict-1892" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="urlict-1892">Urlict (1892)</h2>
<p>Primordial light</p>
<p>English Translation © Richard Stokes</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>O red rose, Man lies in direst need, Man lies in direst pain, I would rather be in heaven. I then came upon a broad path, An angel came and sought to turn me back, Ah no! I refused to be turned away. I am from God and to God I will return, Dear God will give me a light, Will light my way to eternal blessed life.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Translation © Richard Stokes, author of The Book of Lieder (Faber, 2005)</p>
<p>Urlicht</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>O Röschen rot, Der Mensch liegt in grösster Not, Der Mensch liegt in grösster Pein, Je lieber möcht ich im Himmel sein. Da kam ich auf einen breiten Weg, Da kam ein Engellein und wollt mich abweisen, Ach nein ich liess mich nicht abweisen. Ich bin von Gott und will wieder zu Gott, Der liebe Gott wird mir ein Lichtchen geben, Wird leuchten mir bis an das ewig selig Leben.</p>
</blockquote>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>faith</category>
  <category>resurrection</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230127 resurrection/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230127 resurrection/Thursday_Sunset.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>records of thy fathers</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230126 kang family records/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“That search may be made in the book of the records of thy fathers:…”</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Ezra 4:15, King James Version</li>
</ul>
<p>I have never met my grandfather.<br>
We don’t have a photograph of my grandfather.<br>
We don’t have any records of my family, beyond my grandfather.</p>
<p>We know his name, Kang Hyun Yong</p>
<p>He was an only child and when his mom re-married, he almost assumed a new family name, Shin. However, even though he was not even a teenager, he wanted to and kept his original surname of Kang.</p>
<p>My mom told me that when she was expecting me she had a dream. In that dream, she met a bearded man in a mountain setting.</p>
<p>The man handed my mom a book. The book seemed to be a record. A record of the Kang Family.</p>
<section id="kang-family-records" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="kang-family-records">Kang Family Records</h2>
<p>My sons do not have 2 character names. Left them blank in case we determine 항렬(行列)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>항렬(行列)은 같은 씨족 안에서 상하의 차례를 분명히 하기 위하여 만든 서열이다</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>is a sequence made to clarify the order within the same clan</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My uncle’s search for his lineage met its dead end.</p>
<p>There are siblings that share the 항렬(行列).<br>
However since my grandfather was all alone, we could figure out his generations</p>
<p>Families that originated from North Korea were allowed to register their family records in 1957. Since many of the families had either left records behind, or some families may not have had family records.</p>
<p>My father assumed the role of the family head.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230126 kang family records/Original_KangFamily_Record_Page_1.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Excerpt from the family record, created in 1957</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>To my uncle’s estimate we belong to Eun Youl Clan 은열공파 (殷烈公派 :파조 민첨), 27th generation<sup>1</sup>.</p>
</section>
<section id="yu-president" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="yu-president">YU President</h2>
<p>One day, was driving to meet June for lunch.<br>
Heard a voice on the classical FM station.<br>
The voice had characteristics not often heard in these parts yet the message was familiar and soothing.</p>
<p>The speaker spoke of the death of his father.</p>
<p>They were memorializing the eternal resting place, at the same time, recognizing that his father was not in that place but in the heart of that son.</p>
<p>Likewise fathers carrying grandfathers in his heart before him.</p>
<p>I needed to hear this personalized message.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230126 kang family records/511841291_520995.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="a-family-of-abraham" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-family-of-abraham">A family of Abraham</h2>
<p>That YU speaker recounted how the entire Jewish Family has a common heritage.</p>
<ul>
<li>Fathers: Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob.</li>
<li>Mothers: Sarah, Rebekah, Leah, and Rachel.</li>
</ul>
<p>I only know my father and know the name of my grandfather. We have been told that the all of the Kang family can trace their lineage back to General Kang of the 6th Century AD<sup>2</sup>.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>진주 강씨(晋州 姜氏) 시조 강이식(姜以式)은 고구려 병마도원수이다<sup>3</sup></p>
</blockquote>
<p>I am not able to confirm if we started out as a Kang family. Perhaps we started our journey as many other families did — no surnames.<br>
Maybe we were indentured servants, bound to the land or authorities.</p>
<p>(My wife can trace their family back to China. An emissary from China stayed in Korea and became a predecessor)</p>
<p>I hope there will come a time when we have a full access to the family records. If that doesn’t happen in this lifetime, we will ponder on these words,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>And think not to say within yourselves, We have Abraham to our father: for I say unto you, that God is able of these stones to raise up children unto Abraham.</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Matthew 3:9, King James Version</li>
</ul>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://m.blog.naver.com/o1o38oo86oo/221797060004↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>https://www.wikiwand.com/ko/%EA%B0%95_(%EC%84%B1%EC%94%A8)↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>http://www.findroot.co.kr/%EC%84%B1%EC%94%A8%EC%B0%BE%EA%B8%B0/%E3%84%B1/%EA%B0%95-2/%EC%A7%84%EC%A3%BC-%EA%B0%95/↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>records</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230126 kang family records/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230126 kang family records/20221221_171422-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>7 Steps Up - 14 Steps Down</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230125 7 steps up/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>For the last 12 years of her life, my mother lived in a white brickhouse.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230125 7 steps up/IMG_6003 (1).JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The house was built on a slight slope, so that the east side of the house sat higher than the west.</p>
<p>It also meant, front of the house had 7 stair steps, where as it took 14 stairs to get to the basement. The basement opens up to the ground level on the west side.</p>
<p>From her kitchen, she could see the Y-Mountain. Mount Timpanogos can be seen from the living room.</p>
<p>Mother and Father would convert a yard with grass into a gardening area that produced vegetables year around, except for the winter.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230125 7 steps up/IMG_8081.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>It contradicted what I envisioned as a retired person. In fact, my mother farmed until the very last, worked during the season of growing.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230125 7 steps up/LND_56A554AC-0CA4-4A0C-8F24-B8782149DB42.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>She was very independent. She would not use a wheel chair, no walker and definitely no canes for her.</p>
<p>However, during the last few months of her life, she could not negotiate those steps. In addition, the snowfall made it dangerous for her to walk to the curbside.</p>
<p>One option was for her to move downstairs. Basement had a direct access to outisde and the driveway, thus no stairs involved.</p>
<p>However, she would miss the sunlight that main level provided, especially on those cold winter days.</p>
<p>We discussed further.</p>
<p>The thought of sending mother to an assisted living was never brought up, since the thought never crossed our minds. We were united in keeping our mother at her home.</p>
<p>Then, my wife suggested the following.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“…I will carry her on my back…”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My mother is a small person, but still carrying a person down a flight of stairs is no simple task. Not to mention going back up those same 14 steps while carrying a person on the back.</p>
<p>In a small measure, we were able to give back all that our parents provided over the years.</p>
<p>Perhaps in a very small means, we were able to do unto others, things they are not able to do on their own.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>recollections</category>
  <category>independence</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230125 7 steps up/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230125 7 steps up/IMG_7719 (1).JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>father’s messages</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>My father didn’t express his feelings much. Like most men from his generation, less words the better.</p>
<p>Was surprised to discover journals kept by him, in his 80s.</p>
<p>My father spent 36 years in Maryland area. Then in summer of 2010, he sold his home and moved to Provo to be close to the grandchildren.</p>
<p>His life in Utah centered around the family and his God.</p>
<p>Daily activites were with the family and for the family. When good things happened, big or small, he thanked the source of all blessings - our God</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/Epson_01252023194746_3.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Journal Entry from April 2011</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/EPSON044-02.jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">In Đà Nẵng</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>It has been said “a picture is worth thousand words”<br>
However the original quote refers to deed or action</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“A thousand words leave not the same deep impression as does a single deed.” Source: theidioms.com</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Henrik Ibsen</li>
</ul>
<p>Then it is possible that a single act or deed can inspire a multitude of imagery or words.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/IMG_0286.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Dad in his 80s</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>There are multiple ways of living a record or legacy.</p>
<p>A visual medium such as video has multiple codec.<br>
A audio format has even more ways to encode data.</p>
<p>However, how many of these will survive and be interpreted by future generations.</p>
<p>The engraved or written record may be the most simple yet most enduring - precisely because of its simplicity.</p>
<p>While the world may search for the most accurate depiction of its surroundings and everyday occurrence, perhaps the most potent and effective means of preserving and passing on the values from one generation to another is used by the young and old alike – writing down the feelings of each moment.</p>
<p>Because, it is not the amount nor the accuracy that ultimately matters, but the feelings that the message conveys, and the impressions or imagery the message conjures up.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/IMG_9527 (3).JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Dad in his late 80s</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Thanks dad for keeping the journal for us to remember your good life.</p>
<p>It reminds me to be industrious, do good, and give thanks, until the very end.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>records</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/20230201_172340-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>We are all Alone</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230123 We are All Alone/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p><em>"When you’re happy, you enjoy the music but when you’re sad, you understand the lyrics"</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>― Frank Ocean<br>
</p>
<p>I have been contemplating lyrics lately.</p>
<p>Not necessarily because I am sad but because of my age and reflection on the days of our existence.</p>
<p>At a recent wedding, the couple danced to the music that accompanies these lines</p>
<p><em>I know your eyes in the morning sun</em></p>
<p><em>I feel you touch me in the pouring rain</em></p>
<p><em>And the moment that you wander far from me</em></p>
<p><em>I wanna feel you in my arms again</em></p>
<p>(How deep is your love?, Bee Gees 1977)</p>
<p>This was played during my high school days.</p>
<p><br>
A corollary to Frank Ocean's statement might be,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p><em>When young, one dances to the music</em></p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p><em>When old, one contemplates memories invoked by lyrics.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p><br>
</p>
<p>During high school days, we owned a record album called “Silk Degrees”<br>
</p>
<p>It produced 4 singles and the album peaked at #2 on Billboard charts.</p>
<p>Back then, listened to who controlled the radio station playlist.</p>
<p>(Also there were no way of finding the official version of the lyrics. At times, it may be advantageous to leave the lyrics ambiguous. Used to think, <code>learn not to pretent</code>, instead of <code>learn how to pretend</code>)</p>
<p>While the hit singles were up-beat and dance-ready, the one that I recall and listen now is</p>
<p><code>We are all Alone</code><br>
</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Outside the rain begins And it may never end<br>
So cry no more, on the shore a dream<br>
Will take us out to sea<br>
Forevermore, forevermore</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Close your eyes and dream<br>
And you can be with me<br>
’Neath the waves, through the caves of hours<br>
Gone, forgotten now<br>
We’re all alone, we’re all alone</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Close the window, calm the light<br>
And it will be all right<br>
No need to bother now<br>
Let it out, let it all begin<br>
Learn how to pretend</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Once a story’s told It can’t help but grow old<br>
Roses do, lovers too, so cast Your seasons to the wind<br>
And hold me dear, oh, hold me dear</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Close the window, calm the light<br>
And it will be all right<br>
No need to bother now<br>
Let it out, let it all begin<br>
All’s forgotten now<br>
We’re all alone, all alone</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Close the window, calm the light<br>
And it will be all right<br>
No need to bother now Let it out, let it all begin<br>
Owe it to the wind, my love, hold me dear</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>All’s forgotten now, my love<br>
We’re all alone</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230123 We are All Alone/20220826_183105-01.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Boz Scaggs - 1976</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>gratitude</category>
  <category>nostalgia</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230123 We are All Alone/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230123 We are All Alone/IMG_0597-EFFECTS_Original (2).jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Life’s Discrepancies</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230121 Discrepancies/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>On official records, my mother’s birthday is listed as <code>20 February 1935</code></p>
<p>That is incorrect.</p>
<p>The year should be 1932 and furthermore, the date is according to the Lunar Calendar.</p>
<p>So the actual date, according to the Julian Calendar is 26 March 1932. <a href="https://www.hko.gov.hk/en/gts/time/calendar/pdf/files/1932e.pdf">HK Observatory</a></p>
<p>My father’s birthday is recorded as, 12 February 1930, we believe the year is correct.<br>
So his Gregorian calendar birthday is 11 March 1930. <a href="https://www.hko.gov.hk/en/gts/time/calendar/pdf/files/1930e.pdf">1930</a></p>
<p>The difference in birthday is due to 2 reasons.</p>
<p>First, the impact of man-made war.<br>
Second, a tradition of using old, agriculture, focused lunar calendar.</p>
<p>When North Korean refugees were allowed to re-register in South Korea, many chose to and amended their birth year. 2-3 years was common since that was the length of the Korean War<sup>1</sup></p>
<p>In addition my mother was known as 황현실 黃賢實<sup>2</sup> until she was 42 years old.<br>
Then she was know as 강현실 姜賢實 until the latter part of her life.<br>
She then became 황현실 黃賢實 again, for the last dozen years, as she associated with fellow Koreans.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230121 Discrepancies/Epson_01022023180751-01.jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Year 1994</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>She has navigated through changes, some that were catastrophic, in this life. As well as variations in counting years and birthdays and a place to call a home.</p>
<p>Although she didn’t talk in detail, there must have been times when she struggled</p>
<ul>
<li>because she was a stranger,</li>
<li>with a language barrier, and</li>
<li>because she was fatherless.</li>
</ul>
<p>But to us and to the Hwang Family, she never changed.</p>
<p>To Hwang clan, she was a daughter, grand daughter, and a great grand daughter.<br>
For us, she was a wife, our mother, a grandmother and a great-grandmother.</p>
<p>In the end, all of struggles and discrepancies were swallowed up and wiped away and her essence is what remains.</p>
<p>A daughter of God, sent to Hwang Family as the eldest daughter.<br>
To help them through the occupation, communism and the war times.</p>
<p>A faithful follower of Christ, married into the Kang Family.<br>
To guide them through the post war poverty, to search and find the truth, and to re-establish the family in the land of promise.</p>
<p>Thank you, God in Heaven for sending our dear mother.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230121 Discrepancies/20220810_073251-01.jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Rock Canyon in Summer</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>June 1950 to July 1953↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Koreans retain maiden names↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>recollections</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230121 Discrepancies/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230121 Discrepancies/514691694.610559.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Remembrance of My Parents</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230122 Oral Traditions/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Communication between two parties can yield varying results.</p>
<p>Because of differing experiences and readiness, the difference between the transmitted and intended message may vary greatly.</p>
<p>My sisters often talked to our mother on different subjects and with different approaches or angles. Thus they had a different understanding and recollection of the same event.</p>
<p>There are times we rely on oral recollections over written versions.</p>
<ul>
<li>How do we resolve these differences.</li>
<li>How critical are these differences.</li>
</ul>
<section id="lessons-from-our-parents" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="lessons-from-our-parents">Lessons from our parents</h2>
<p>First we learn from parents by observing how they decide. We learn about the outcome of their decision and action.</p>
<p>Then we formulate our own direction in life based on their examples.</p>
<p>In recent memorial for our mother, all 3 siblings prepared remarks. Not one of us delivered the prepared message.</p>
<p>(The order of delivery also affected what messages needed to be filtered, since it was covered by other speakers)</p>
<p>Instead we all delivered another version of the message that we felt was more appropriate.</p>
<p>Learned the following</p>
<ul>
<li>prepare all you can beforehand</li>
<li>rely on the guidance from above</li>
<li>adjust the content and delivery to fit the promptings, the current audience and the latest situations.</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230122 Oral Traditions/20230111_171424-01.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>This was the prepared message for Mom’s Memorial.</p>
<p>My mother’s life can be categorized into 3 areas.</p>
<ul>
<li>There is Beauty All Around</li>
<li>Truth Shall Make You Free</li>
<li>I can do all things through Christ which strengtheneth me.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="there-is-beauty-all-around" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="there-is-beauty-all-around">There is Beauty All Around</h2>
<p>As a hymn suggests, we see the beauty all around us when we have love as a foundation.</p>
<p>She had a deep faith in Christ and we felt her love from the very early years in life.</p>
<p>Mother recognized beauty in all of God’s creations she witnessed or the people came in contact with.<br>
She loved people and things as they were and what they could become. No detail was too small or insignificant to her.</p>
<p>She created beauty, even when the environment was chaotic or unorganized.<br>
We had a loving home with order and cleanliness.<br>
She knitted numerous creations, she could see a picture and create a sweater, a hat or warm piece for your neck. We are sure all of you have at least one of her latest creation, the dish scrubber(scouring pad) or <a href="https://namu.wiki/w/%EC%88%98%EC%84%B8%EB%AF%B8">수세미</a></p>
<p>She could out produce any farmers, she and father would turn a patch of lawn into a plot of land any farmer would grade as A+</p>
<p>My sister and I were sent in search of wild onions or Dal Rae <a href="https://ko.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/%EB%8B%AC%EB%9E%98">달래</a> We went to Rock Canyon and climbed up rocks and risked our lives and we found them She planted wild onions on her farm and we were able to taste wild onions.</p>
<p>Still can taste the lettuce that she grew in spring and into the summer. By wrapping around any food and putting the special sauce she created, the taste was something that we all would cherish.</p>
<p>We didn’t dine out much when growing up. We thought it was because we were poor, and we were. But learned later on that our mom was well-known as a connoisseur and a creator of Northern Korean cuisine.</p>
</section>
<section id="truth-shall-make-you-free" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="truth-shall-make-you-free">Truth Shall Make You Free</h2>
<p>Mother had a tremendous curiosity for all things, especially people.</p>
<p>Recently while organizing her things.<br>
We found a number journals and logbooks that she detailed, well into her 80s;</p>
<p>her study of the gospel as a Sunday School teacher Also she chronicled her love of cooking in a recipe book.</p>
<p>She sought for the foundational knowledge on all she encountered She didn’t want to rely on others, she was independent thinker</p>
<p>She learned truth by study and from inspiration and she became free.</p>
<p>She took a special interest in all she met and especially the young and babies. She used to say, you know you have been around for a while when you can remember 3 generations that came before you and can see in person 3 generations that will carry on the legacy.</p>
<p>She would make that <code>special sound of joy</code> that only she can make whenever she met young people or babies.</p>
<p>She was able to think clearly and make quick and correct decisions. Amazed that she maintained this ability to the very end,</p>
</section>
<section id="i-can-do-all-things-through-christ-which-strengtheneth-me." class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="i-can-do-all-things-through-christ-which-strengtheneth-me.">I can do all things through Christ which strengtheneth me.</h2>
<p>She believed in Christ. She lived as a follower of Christ. She lifted and reminded others that they are children of a Heavenly Father.</p>
<p>Not only did she make us feel loved and important but that we can accomplish anything.</p>
<p>When I was struggling in school and without direction and felt like quitting. She would tell me how she carried on even through the death of her father and the Korean War. She was telling me you can do this with faith in Christ.</p>
<p>Visited with our uncle, my father’s youngest brother who is 13 years younger than my father. He mentioned how mom elevated his status as a human being. She insisted that he finish college when only 20% of the population had college degree Also the per capita income in Korea at that time was $100 USD per person<sup>1</sup>.</p>
<p>Through means only she could have figured out, She encouraged my uncle and he was able to finish his studies and he is indebted to our mother as we are</p>
<p>She showed us by being a wonderful mother, a faithful wife, and loving Grandmother.</p>
<p>She endured and showed us how to live this life fully and we must follow in her footsteps.</p>
<p>In the name of Jesus Christ</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/NY.GDP.PCAP.CD?locations=KR↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>recollections</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230122 Oral Traditions/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230122 Oral Traditions/20230107_152010-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Faith of My Mother</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230120 faith of mom/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>From <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christianity_in_Korea">Wikipedia</a></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Catholicism was first introduced during the late Joseon Dynasty period by Confucian scholars who encountered it in China. In 1603, Yi Gwang-jeong, a Korean diplomat, returned from Beijing carrying several theological books written by Matteo Ricci, an Italian Jesuit missionary to China<sup>1</sup>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>According to my sister, mom’s family attended a synagogue, participated in the Baptist congregation, and joined a Prebysterian faith, by the time mom’s father was of age.</p>
<p>Hwang Family were always searching for the truth.</p>
<p>Even as the country turned ideologically communist, Christians and my mom’s family maintained their faith in God</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230120 faith of mom/DSCN0272 1.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">with a cousin at BaekRyung Island</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>My other sister told me about an uncle who escaped a firing squad. Communists gathered religious leaders and they were to face death as a group.</p>
<p>The uncle fell and pretended to be dead before the bullets hit the prisoners.</p>
<p>As other prisoners fell by the bullet, they wound up on top of him. He thought he had escaped death, until the bayonet check almost cost him his life.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230120 faith of mom/EPSON128.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">A Presbyterian Congregation in Incheon</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>After 20 years of participating in Presbyterian faith, my mom, as her family before, was still searching.</p>
<p>My father met missionaries as they were street contacting in Incheon.</p>
<p>My mother had many questions that were answered by missionaries, a visit by Elder Harold B. Lee.</p>
<p>One day, as she was studying scriptures, she dreamed.</p>
<p>In that dream, she saw 2 books on a table. One was the <code>Bible</code> and the other was the <code>Book of Mormon</code> A hand was also shown and as the hand was waved between 2 books, a voice was overheard.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>These 2 books are equivalent</p>
</blockquote>
<p>All these experiences along with her faith enabled to accept the gospel as thought by the Church of Jesus Christ of Latte-Day Saints.</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>KIM Han-sik, ‘The Influence of Christianity’, Korean Journal XXIII, 12, December 1983, p.&nbsp;5.↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>mother</category>
  <category>faith</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230120 faith of mom/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230120 faith of mom/20230101_083104.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Songs of My Parents</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230119 trot spotify/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Recently gave up my access to Spotify Premium</p>
<p>Earlier, my son offered to include me in his Spotify Premium Plan.<br>
I was excited to explore a new music source.<br>
Thought I would learn about dozens of new artists and listen to 100s of new songs.</p>
<p>That didn’t happen.</p>
<p>I ran out of memory<br>
Or more accurately,<br>
I no longer have memories that matches current songs</p>
<p>Realized that musical experience is not only an investment in learning songs and lyrics, as well as the artist, but also matching songs to one’s life’s memory</p>
<p>옛 사랑</p>
<p>남들도 모르게 서성이다 울었지<br>
지나온 일들이 가슴에 사무쳐<br>
텅빈 하늘 밑 불빛들 켜져가면<br>
옛사랑 그 이름 아껴 불러보네<br>
찬바람 불어와 옷깃을 여미우다<br>
후회가 또 화가 나 눈물이 흐르네<br>
누가 물어도 아플 것 같지 않던<br>
지나온 내 모습 모두 거짓인가</p>
<p><a href="https://lyricstranslate.com/en/yes-salang-old-love.html">Translated lyrics</a></p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230119 trot spotify/Epson_01162023180616_2.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">My Uncle in the Middle School, 1960s</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><code>Old Love</code></p>
<p>Alone, wandered and cried.<br>
Past events that won’t let go<br>
Open skies and man-made lights aglow</p>
<p>Remember an old name and a face<br>
Cold wind makes me tighten coat collars<br>
Remembering the past makes me regret, angered</p>
<p>Used to think looking back would be pain-free.<br>
Was that memory real?</p>
<section id="music-listening-pattern" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="music-listening-pattern">Music Listening Pattern</h2>
<p>I mostly listen to songs from my parent’s generation up to the time when I was in my 20s. (1940s-1980s)</p>
<p>They are about topics I understand and the music I can follow along and sing.</p>
<p>Recently found out that what I listen to has a name, it is called <code>Trot</code> (as in Foxtrot), Similar to Enka <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enka">演歌</a></p>
<p>It is a well defined genre among Koreans, According to Wikipedia, its 2 main themes are:</p>
<ul>
<li>love and parting,</li>
<li>longing for a home</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="trot-beginning" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="trot-beginning">Trot Beginning</h2>
<p>Recount the love, sorrow, separation in the past</p>
</section>
<section id="trot-middle" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="trot-middle">Trot Middle</h2>
<p>The account from several angles, including regional legends.</p>
</section>
<section id="trot-close" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="trot-close">Trot Close</h2>
<p>Hope for a closure or redemption.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230119 trot spotify/IMG_1935.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">山寺, 山号 宝珠山</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</section>
<section id="transition-to-modern-k-pop" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="transition-to-modern-k-pop">Transition to Modern K-Pop</h2>
<p>In 1990 when I visited Korea after marriage. My uncle commented,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“why is it that everyone is emphasizing dancing over singing…”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(I should have put my money on those talent agencies that cater to dancers.)</p>
<p>One element of Korean songs is a feeling of resentment; deep sorrow: A feeling of bitterness, deep resentment or sorrow that builds up in one’s mind from an unfair or regretful event.</p>
<p>Didn’t fully realize these singers are singing more than just songs but a longing or yearning for a place, time, or a person they once met but no longer able to.</p>
<p>In essence, trot songs are K-Drama presented in a 5 minute segment. Feelings, aspirations, and disappoints of each generation.</p>
<p>Within that longing lies a hope that one day will be realized. Until then, my generation will sing those songs not found on Spotify.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>remembrance</category>
  <category>music</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230119 trot spotify/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230119 trot spotify/IMG_1671.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Abide with Me</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230118 abide with me/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Swift to its close ebbs out life’s little day.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Earth’s joys grow dim; its glories pass away.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Change and decay in all around I see;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>O thou who changest not, abide with me!</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong><em>Henry F. Lyte, 1793–1847</em></strong></p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230118 abide with me/20230118_171718-01.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>remembrance</category>
  <category>alone</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230118 abide with me/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230118 abide with me/20230118_172057-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Đà Nẵng Years</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>From April of 1966 to January of 1970 my father worked in Đà Nẵng, Vietnam.</p>
<p>The employer was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RMK-BRJ">RMK-BRJ</a></p>
<p>The initial contract was for 36 months and he renewed for another 6 months afterwards.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/Epson_01152023103739_4.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>He was able to come home after 18 months, for a well-earned, 휴가, return home.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/Epson_01152023092338_3.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Not only did the work compensation allowed the family to be debt-free but it also enabled my father to deposit money at the Bank of America.</p>
<p>(this allowed him to apply for an employment at an US company without financial backing)</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/Epson_01152023103739_2.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Dad would say later that this crucible was the financial and spiritual base that we desperately needed.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/Epson_01152023091240_3.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>In many ways, Đà Nẵng, Vietnam, was our Egypt and we are very grateful to God and to our father.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>dad</category>
  <category>work</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/danang_cover.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Old Memories : A Family Recollection</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230115 old folks/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>A visit with old persons leaves one with,</p>
<ul>
<li><p>something to think about</p></li>
<li><p>a resolution to improve</p></li>
<li><p>something you never knew - about your self or life.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>Especially, if that person lives far away and haven’t talked to you in years.</p>
<p>As part of the Lunar (Chinese) New Year celebration, mom and I called some of the relatives in Korea.</p>
<p>As my mom and her younger sister spoke, they started to sound just like characters from CLOY (Crash Landing on You).</p>
<p>Mom explained that my father’s family came down to South Korea nearly a decade early so they had a chance to pick up the Southern Accent.</p>
<p>My mom’s family, on the other had, came during the War so they didn’t have a chance to assimilate as a teenager.</p>
<section id="section" class="level5">
<h5 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section"></h5>
<p>Then my uncle, who is 13 years younger than my father, began to re-live the old days in Incheon area.</p>
<p>The house we lived in during my growing up years, faced a busy road, but it was situated about 2 meters below the road.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230115 old folks/511842537.951056.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">the house at the lower right corner</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>One day, a truck owned by the US military<sup>1</sup> ran off the road and crashed into our house.</p>
<p>My uncle and I were sitting near a portable stove <a href="https://namu.wiki/w/%EB%82%9C%EB%A1%9C">난로(暖爐)</a> in an extension of rooms called <a href="https://folkency.nfm.go.kr/topic/detail/8320?pageType=search&amp;keyword=%EB%A7%88%EB%A3%A8">마루</a>.</p>
<p>As the truck crashed into the house, its axle rested near the extended floor and my uncle and I were inches from the tire and the axle.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230115 old folks/Epson_01082023145722.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">The house at the time of the accident, upper left corner</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>My mother was traumatized by the experience and couldn’t remember this had happened.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level5">
<h5 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-1"></h5>
<p>Hearing this story affected me for days.</p>
<p>Not only, was I grateful that our lives were spared. But also that my life may have a purpose that I need to work on.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Early in this section, Mr.&nbsp;Gladwell invokes the World War II bombing of London as a valid David and Goliath mismatch: German efforts to intimidate the British created the “remote miss,” a survivor’s exhilaration, in some who lived through weeks of bombardment.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2013/10/03/books/david-and-goliath-by-malcolm-gladwell.html">From a NYT review of Malcolm McDowell’s book</a></p>
<p>Felt that God protects our lives so that we can finish the work we were assigned in this life.</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>there was a military base nearby↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>recollections</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230115 old folks/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230115 old folks/20230111_171308-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Wanderer</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230114 Displaced Person/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230114 Displaced Person/IMG_2156.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I learned a new phrase.</p>
<p>실향민<sup>1</sup> - a displaced person.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>They are people who are blocked from returning to their hometown freely after leaving their hometown. Refugees are also included.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I am a son of a displaced person.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>오늘도 걷는다마는 정처 없는 이 발길 지나 온 자죽마다 눈물 고였다 선창 가 고동 소리 옛 님이 그리워도 나그네 흐를 길은 한이 없어라</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>타관 땅 발벗어 돈지 십 년 넘어 반평생 사나이 가슴속엔 한이 서린다 황혼이 찾어들면 고향도 그리워져 눈물로 꿈을 불러 찾어도 보네</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>낯익은 거리다마는 이국보다 차워라 가야 할 지평선엔 태양도 없어 새벽 별 찬 서리가 뼈 골에 스미는데 어데로 흘러가랴 흘러갈 소냐</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This was my father’s favorite song. He would sing out loud and I would sing along as well. I learned the melody even as a young person</p>
<p>Now that I am older, I read the lyric and understand some of the sowrrow of being a displaced person. A stranger in a new part of Korea and a foreigner in a new continent.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Today I continue to walk (wander) Walk aimlessly Tears welled up at every passing person.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>There is no rest for the wanderer</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230114 Displaced Person/IMG_3950.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I am grateful that my parents were able to meet and establish a home in a new land. That we are able to follow in their footsteps.</p>
<p>My father during 1960s would travel to Hong Kong, Taiwan, and Kyushu, Japan on his way to and from Vietnam. Many years later, I was able to visit these same region and my children also spent time at those locations.</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>실향민(失鄕民)은 고향을 떠난 후 고향에 자유로이 돌아갈 길이 막힌 사람들이다. 난민도 포함된다.↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>divided</category>
  <category>future</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230114 Displaced Person/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230114 Displaced Person/Epson_08152020104334 Copy Copy.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Given Vocation in Life</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230110 thank you dad/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>I felt a renewed appreciation and love for my father one morning.</p>
<p>I was thinking how many times he went to work when he preferred to be elsewhere.<br>
And while working, wishing he had a different vocation.</p>
<p>He never once hinted that his work was hard or difficult.<br>
He was a crane operator.<br>
He was able to separate the work from home.</p>
<p>Compartmentalize out of necessity.</p>
<p>When he talked about his Korean War days, we thought he was reliving a period of his life. Only recently we learned that it is one of the traits of a PTSD – not being able to let go or escape certain events or trials.</p>
<p>Thought of his stay in Vietnam during the 1960s as a work-vacation.<br>
Forgetting that nation was in a civil war.</p>
<p>He always mentioned it as a crucible and a mean God has chosen to free us from the worldly debt and introduce us to American culture and a gateway to finding the gospel.</p>
<p>If greatness is defined as being true to one’s responsibility, my father had it – in abundance.</p>
<p>Recently, my mom, told me how proud he was of me.</p>
<p>He rarely expressed it in words, but I felt it growing up.<br>
Even now, I feel his love and guidance.</p>
<p>I love you too, Dad.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230110 thank you dad/images/EPSON068-01.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>gratitude</category>
  <category>parent</category>
  <category>work</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230110 thank you dad/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230110 thank you dad/IMG_3944.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>가거라 三八線 Part 2</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230112 38th Parallel Pt 2/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><a href="http://encykorea.aks.ac.kr/">Encyclopedia of Korean Culture</a><sup>1</sup> defines hometown or 고향(故鄕) as</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>태어나서 자라고 살아온 곳 또는 마음속 깊이 간직한 그립고 정든 장소.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>or</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>A place where you were born, raised and lived, or a place you miss and love deeply in your heart</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My mother was born and raised at</p>
<p>황해도 장영군 후남면 남호리 291.</p>
<p>Google search of her hometown yields<br>
<strong>Google Maps can’t find…</strong></p>
<p>My mother’s family is originally from Pyong Yang (평양, 平壤) area.</p>
<p>Her family went through occupation by Japanese and Russians.<br>
Learned about communism, firsthand.<br>
A war between Koreas, lost her father at age 14.<br>
Then escaped to South Korea.</p>
<p>All this before she turned 20 years old</p>
<section id="life-under-the-japanese-occupation-1932-1945" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="life-under-the-japanese-occupation-1932-1945">Life under the Japanese Occupation (1932-1945)</h2>
<p>Mother’s family owned land and buildings.<br>
They owned a local hub for merchandise called 협성상회協成商会.<br>
They also distributed Mainichi Daily 毎日新聞</p>
<p>Grandfather often traveled to Incheon to trade and would bring back latest merchandise home.</p>
<p>Life was not idyllic but they were well off for the time and place.</p>
<p>One day, grandfather took mom aside and showed their holdings and commented.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“all this land belongs to us. orchard and rice fields, plus buildings”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Looking back, my mother observed. Life wasn’t easy but no one starved, necessary items were plentiful, and even fish was visible in the stream.</p>
</section>
<section id="life-after-liberation-communism-and-russian-occupation-1945-1950" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="life-after-liberation-communism-and-russian-occupation-1945-1950">Life after liberation : Communism and Russian occupation (1945-1950)</h2>
<p>Communists took everything, putting red stickers on all of mom’s belongings.<br>
Former workers brought food for a year, until no one had private food.</p>
<p>There was no longer incentive to work harder.<br>
Everyone got same amount.<br>
(They would count grains to give same amount)</p>
<p>Mom had to gather woods, using an ‘A’ Frame, or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jige">지게</a>, she was 13 and the oldest.</p>
<p>She was trained to use guns and military drills - using Russian words and techniques.</p>
<p>Communists turned parents against children. By forcing children to report against parents and vice versa.</p>
<p>(Compare Malachi 4:6)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>And he shall turn the heart of the fathers to the children, and the heart of the children to their fathers, lest I come and smite the earth with a curse</p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="separation-of-hwang-family-1945-1950" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="separation-of-hwang-family-1945-1950">Separation of Hwang Family (1945-1950)</h2>
<p>Our grandfather passed away in 1945, the same year that his only son was born. With death of the father, the life became increasingly difficult for the family.</p>
<p>Once asked mom how she survived bombings during the war. She responded simply,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>we had a bunker built next to the kitchen. when the air-raid siren sounded, we all took refuge in the bunker</p>
</blockquote>
<p>With battle for the control of 38th Parallel continuing around the area, family elders arranged for an escape.</p>
<p>As mother left her home, the family hid the ancestral records underneath wood paneling that separated living area from the house foundation.</p>
<p>Many of the elderly stayed because because the evacuation was temporary</p>
<p>45 person boat was arranged however only half the boat was filled. (Mom’s family almost didn’t make it to the rendevouz point).</p>
<p>One lady had a baby on the boat. The family got extra rations, since there were 5 children with a single mother.</p>
</section>
<section id="a-family-member-left-behind" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-family-member-left-behind">A family member left behind</h2>
<p>Additional tragedy, and one that hasn’t been resolved to this day, was that one of the siblings didn’t get on that boat.<br>
Originally, my mother was chosen to spend time with an aunt (grandma’s sister) in Wonsan. (Husband of the aunt was killed in an industrial accident and she had become a minister in a church)</p>
<p>But grandma Kim objected and insisted that her oldest daughter stay with her. As a compromise, the second oldest went to stay with the aunt. However, the bombing of roads and bridges meant that she couldn’t get back in time to join the family.</p>
<p>My aunt, <code>Hyunsook</code> 현숙, was left behind. And we don’t know whether she is still living.<br>
The last contact was over 70 years ago.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230112 38th Parallel Pt 2/images/IMG_8252 Copy.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Surviving Hwang Sisters</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>아~~ 꽃필 때나 오시려느냐</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>아~~~~ 눈올 때나 오시려느냐</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>보따리 등에 메고 넘던 고개길</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>산새도 나와 함께 울고 넘었지</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>자유여 너를 위해 자유여 너를 위해</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>이 목숨을 바친다</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Will you return when flowers bloom<br>
Or when snow covers fields<br>
Recall when we escaped with essentials on our back<br>
Even birds sang mournfully through mountain passages<br>
Freedom, I re-dedicate my life</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>한국민족문화대백과사전, 韓国民族文化大百科辞典↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>divided</category>
  <category>future</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230112 38th Parallel Pt 2/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230112 38th Parallel Pt 2/IMG_3143.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Deers of Rock Canyon</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230109 rock canyon deers/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>At first significant snowstorm, each fall, my dad would look towards Timpanogos and ask,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“Wonder where deers go for their food…”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Since I didn’t know, I couldn’t answer so we moved on to a different topic.</p>
<p>Our family lived in Provo for nearly 40 years.</p>
<p>We have hiked Rock Canyon as a family.<br>
All of my children graduated from Rock Canyon Elementary.</p>
<p>This is our neighborhood and we know all there is to know about it.</p>
<p>That was an incorrect reasoning.</p>
<p>One afternoon, after parking the car at the Rock Canyon Park, I started a hike up to the Bonneville Shoreline Trail.</p>
<p>Noticed a truck with a scope pointed at a spot above the trail. My curiosity was piqued.</p>
<p>I didn’t have to ask much, the man anticipated my queries and explained in detail about the feeding pattern, places to watch, best times to see.</p>
<p>He knew so much about the deer herd of Rock Canyon. He showed me when to look (during mealtime), where to look (30-40 feet above the trail), and what to look for (herd of deer).</p>
<p>I had never seen a deer herd before meeting this man with a scope.<br>
Since meeting with and coaching from the man, I can’t avoid seeing the herd.</p>
<p>One day, during a snowstorm, I saw a group of deer, moving together on a well-defined path, along the south edge of the Squaw Peak, about 200 feet above where I was.</p>
<p>So what seemed like a rhetorical question by my dad, turned into a specific teaching moment for me about the survival of deer in the wintertime.</p>
<p>(Perhaps my dad, who has passed away, was gently influencing the man with the scope to teach me a thing or two)</p>
<p>So in this life, it seems, that one can pose a question or raise an issue and others may solve it for us. Or one can jump in and try to find, not only the answer, but also implement the solution once found.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Ask, and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find; knock, and it shall be opened unto you:</p>
</blockquote>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230109 rock canyon deers/20220306_075930.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Rock Canyon Deer Herd</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>For every one that asketh receiveth; and he that seeketh findeth; and to him that knocketh it shall be opened.</p>
</blockquote>



 ]]></description>
  <category>compassion</category>
  <category>guidance</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230109 rock canyon deers/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230109 rock canyon deers/20221112_171117-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Lord Delivers</title>
  <dc:creator>Young Irvine</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230105 My Family Escape/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><code>Talk given at Seneca Stake, Spring 2022</code></p>
<p>Hello brothers and sisters,</p>
<p>My topic today is <strong>Jesus Christ is my Deliverer</strong>, which is taken from <strong><em>Come Follow Me, Exodus Chapters One to Two</em></strong>.</p>
<p>There are many ways the Lord can deliver His children from the challenges in life.</p>
<p>When the ancient Israelites were in Egypt, they faced huge hardships.</p>
<p>They were slaves.</p>
<p>They were forced to do hard labor.</p>
<p>They had no hope for a better life.</p>
<p>So what did they do?</p>
<p>In Exodus Chapter 2, Verse 23, it reads,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“They cried … unto God” for help.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And the Lord answered their prayers.</p>
<p>He remembered His covenant people and sent Moses to help free them.</p>
<p>Moses was a tool to guide the children of Israel to the Promised Land. Through Moses, who received authority from the Lord to act as His prophet, there were many miracles.</p>
<p>There is the story of Moses parting of the Red Sea to escape the Egyptians.</p>
<p>There is also the story of the people of Israel receiving manna, or bread, from heaven.</p>
<p>The Lord also told Moses to split a rock to provide water to the people in the desert, which Moses did.</p>
<p>All these miracles happened along the people of Israel’s journey back to the Promised Land.</p>
<p>The Lord physically and spiritually sustained them.</p>
<p>In a very significant way, the Lord guided my family to the United States of America.</p>
<p>In Ether Chapter Two Verses 9 and 12, it reads that the Americas is “a land of promise” and a “choice land.”</p>
<p>The Lord delivers us from our struggles and bad situations.</p>
<p>How do I know this?</p>
<p>Because He delivered my mother from living under a communist regime.</p>
<p>My mother’s family were Christians for three generations, at the time, but they lived in fear in North Korea.</p>
<p>Under the government, the ultimate punishments for Christian worshippers were being sent to do time in a hard labor camp or the firing squad. She kept her faith by praying daily at night under a thick blanket.</p>
<p>She was like the people of Alma in the Book of Mormon, who prayed in their hearts to avoid punishment from their enemies. He heard my mother’s prayers and I know that He answered her prayers.</p>
<p>During the Korean War some seventy years ago, her family and other refugees were evacuated to a safer area in South Korea, thanks to the assistance from the United States Navy. <sup>1</sup></p>
<p>While the war raged on, my mother and her family rarely lost hope and constantly prayed for the peace in the land. She saw miracles on many occasions, such as when the meager rations lasted longer than expected and also when her family received help from strangers, countless times.</p>
<p>The Lord delivered my mother’s family.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230105 My Family Escape/IMG_2154.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Mom, center 2nd row, attending a Protestant Church 1960s</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>When my father was twenty years old, he was drafted into fighting for the South Korean Army during the Korean War. He was captured and tortured by the enemy on at least three different occasions.</p>
<p>However, he managed to escape from his captors and reunited with his army unit each time. He told me countless times that he was led by the powerful impressions to know when and which direction to run during his escapes.</p>
<p>One time, after being captured, the enemy soldier told my father that he was “too young to die” and he was spared from execution.</p>
<p>I am thankful to the Lord that He delivered my father from certain death.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230105 My Family Escape/IMG_2154 (1).JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Father during the late 1950s</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Having seen the horrors of war first-hand, my parents decided to emigrate to the U.S.</p>
<p>The Lord can deliver our family from difficult situations by inspiring a way to escape, in this case, emigrate to the chosen land.</p>
<p>My family has been blessed to be in this country and to be members of the Lord’s restored and true Church.</p>
<p>All of my children have served missions for the Church in Southern California and South Korea.</p>
<p>My nephews and niece have also served missions in New York City, Washington State, Taiwan, Hong Kong, and Japan.</p>
<p>Don and I are serving in the Washington, D.C. North Mission.</p>
<p>It has been a great blessing to serve among the young missionaries and the senior missionaries. We have learned so much about the inner workings of the mission and how many sacrifices are made to do the Lord’s work here in this area, and also throughout the world.</p>
<p>I would not have guessed that we would be serving a mission in our home region if you had asked me several years ago. But here we are, and we are loving this opportunity to serve the Lord in order to pay Him back for delivering us from our trials.</p>
<p>Our prayers are with those in Ukraine at this time, and we know that the Lord will deliver them during these troubled and difficult times just as He did for my family in Korea. Though many Ukrainians are not of our faith, their faith has gotten them through the difficulties of war and they have declared that God sustains and supports them.</p>
<p>As the Lord declared, “Peace I give unto you.” He will bless us with peace and He will deliver us from our trials.</p>
<p>In Doctrine and Covenants Section 84, Verse 88, the Lord told the early Saints that He will send angels to us:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“And whoso receiveth you, there I will be also, for I will go before your face. I will be on your right hand and on your left, and my Spirit shall be in your hearts, and mine angels round about you, to bear you up.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In closing:</p>
<p>I know that the Lord Jesus Christ has power to deliver me from problems and troubles just like He did with the ancient Israelites. I know my Savior lives and loves me. I know Joseph Smith is a prophet of God.</p>
<p>In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>The ship described by mom here was the LST class, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Landing_Ship,_Tank">Landing Ship Tank</a>↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>gratitude</category>
  <category>parents</category>
  <category>korean war</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230105 My Family Escape/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230105 My Family Escape/IMG_2154 (1).JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
