<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Quarto Blog</title>
<link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.2.269</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Đà Nẵng Years</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>From April of 1966 to January of 1970 my father worked in Đà Nẵng, Vietnam.</p>
<p>The employer was <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RMK-BRJ">RMK-BRJ</a></p>
<p>The initial contract was for 36 months and he renewed for another 6 months afterwards.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/Epson_01152023103739_4.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>He was able to come home after 18 months, for a well-earned, 휴가, return home.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/Epson_01152023092338_3.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Not only did the work compensation allowed the family to be debt-free but it also enabled my father to deposit money at the Bank of America.</p>
<p>(this allowed him to apply for an employment at an US company without financial backing)</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/Epson_01152023103739_2.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Dad would say later that this crucible was the financial and spiritual base that we desperately needed.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/Epson_01152023091240_3.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>In many ways, Đà Nẵng, Vietnam, was our Egypt and we are very grateful to God and to our father.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>dad</category>
  <category>work</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230116 da nang days/Epson_01152023111751_4.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Old Memories : A Family Recollection</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230115 old folks/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>A visit with old persons leaves one with,</p>
<ul>
<li><p>something to think about</p></li>
<li><p>a resolution to improve</p></li>
<li><p>something you never knew - about your self or life.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>Especially, if that person lives far away and haven’t talked to you in years.</p>
<p>As part of the Lunar (Chinese) New Year celebration, mom and I called some of the relatives in Korea.</p>
<p>As my mom and her younger sister spoke, they started to sound just like characters from CLOY (Crash Landing on You).</p>
<p>Mom explained that my father’s family came down to South Korea nearly a decade early so they had a chance to pick up the Southern Accent.</p>
<p>My mom’s family, on the other had, came during the War so they didn’t have a chance to assimilate as a teenager.</p>
<section id="section" class="level5">
<h5 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section"></h5>
<p>Then my uncle, who is 13 years younger than my father, began to re-live the old days in Incheon area.</p>
<p>The house we lived in during my growing up years, faced a busy road, but it was situated about 2 meters below the road.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230115 old folks/511842537.951056.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">the house at the lower right corner</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>One day, a truck owned by the US military<sup>1</sup> ran off the road and crashed into our house.</p>
<p>My uncle and I were sitting near a portable fireplace <a href="https://namu.wiki/w/%EB%82%9C%EB%A1%9C">난로(暖爐)</a> in an extension of rooms called <a href="https://folkency.nfm.go.kr/topic/detail/8320?pageType=search&amp;keyword=%EB%A7%88%EB%A3%A8">마루</a>.</p>
<p>As the truck crashed into the house, its axle rested near the extended floor and my uncle and I were inches from the tire and the axle.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230115 old folks/Epson_01082023145722.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">The house at the time of the accident, upper left corner</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>My mother was traumatized by the experience and couldn’t remember this had happened.</p>
</section>
<section id="section-1" class="level5">
<h5 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section-1"></h5>
<p>Hearing this story affected me for days.</p>
<p>Not only, was I grateful that our lives were spared. But also that my life may have a purpose that I need to work on.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Early in this section, Mr.&nbsp;Gladwell invokes the World War II bombing of London as a valid David and Goliath mismatch: German efforts to intimidate the British created the “remote miss,” a survivor’s exhilaration, in some who lived through weeks of bombardment.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2013/10/03/books/david-and-goliath-by-malcolm-gladwell.html">From a NYT review of Malcolm McDowell’s book</a></p>
<p>Felt that God protects our lives so that we can finish the work we were assigned in this life.</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>there was a military base nearby↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>recollections</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230115 old folks/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230115 old folks/20230111_171308-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Wanderer</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230114 Displaced Person/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230114 Displaced Person/IMG_2156.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I learned a new phrase.</p>
<p>실향민<sup>1</sup> - a displaced person.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>They are people who are blocked from returning to their hometown freely after leaving their hometown. Refugees are also included.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I am a son of a displaced person.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>오늘도 걷는다마는 정처 없는 이 발길 지나 온 자죽마다 눈물 고였다 선창 가 고동 소리 옛 님이 그리워도 나그네 흐를 길은 한이 없어라</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>타관 땅 발벗어 돈지 십 년 넘어 반평생 사나이 가슴속엔 한이 서린다 황혼이 찾어들면 고향도 그리워져 눈물로 꿈을 불러 찾어도 보네</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>낯익은 거리다마는 이국보다 차워라 가야 할 지평선엔 태양도 없어 새벽 별 찬 서리가 뼈 골에 스미는데 어데로 흘러가랴 흘러갈 소냐</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This was my father’s favorite song. He would sing out loud and I would sing along as well. I learned the melody even as a young person</p>
<p>Now that I am older, I read the lyric and understand some of the sowrrow of being a displaced person. A stranger in a new part of Korea and a foreigner in a new continent.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Today I continue to walk (wander) Walk aimlessly Tears welled up at every passing person.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>There is no rest for the wanderer</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230114 Displaced Person/IMG_3950.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I am grateful that my parents were able to meet and establish a home in a new land. That we are able to follow in their footsteps.</p>
<p>My father during 1960s would travel to Hong Kong, Taiwan, and Kyushu, Japan on his way to and from Vietnam. Many years later, I was able to visit these same region and my children also spent time at those locations.</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>실향민(失鄕民)은 고향을 떠난 후 고향에 자유로이 돌아갈 길이 막힌 사람들이다. 난민도 포함된다.↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>divided</category>
  <category>future</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230114 Displaced Person/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230114 Displaced Person/Epson_08152020104334 Copy Copy.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Given Vocation in Life</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230110 thank you dad/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>I felt a renewed appreciation and love for my father one morning.</p>
<p>I was thinking how many times he went to work when he preferred to be elsewhere.<br>
And while working, wishing he had a different vocation.</p>
<p>He never once hinted that his work was hard or difficult.<br>
He was a crane operator.<br>
He was able to separate the work from home.</p>
<p>Compartmentalize out of necessity.</p>
<p>When he talked about his Korean War days, we thought he was reliving a period of his life. Only recently we learned that it is one of the traits of a PTSD – not being able to let go or escape certain events or trials.</p>
<p>Thought of his stay in Vietnam during the 1960s as a work-vacation.<br>
Forgetting that nation was in a civil war.</p>
<p>He always mentioned it as a crucible and a mean God has chosen to free us from the worldly debt and introduce us to American culture and a gateway to finding the gospel.</p>
<p>If greatness is defined as being true to one’s responsibility, my father had it – in abundance.</p>
<p>Recently, my mom, told me how proud he was of me.</p>
<p>He rarely expressed it in words, but I felt it growing up.<br>
Even now, I feel his love and guidance.</p>
<p>I love you too, Dad.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230110 thank you dad/images/EPSON068-01.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>gratitude</category>
  <category>parent</category>
  <category>work</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230110 thank you dad/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230110 thank you dad/IMG_3944.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>가거라 三八線 Part 2</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230112 38th Parallel Pt 2/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><a href="http://encykorea.aks.ac.kr/">Encyclopedia of Korean Culture</a><sup>1</sup> defines hometown or 고향(故鄕) as</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>태어나서 자라고 살아온 곳 또는 마음속 깊이 간직한 그립고 정든 장소.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>or</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>A place where you were born, raised and lived, or a place you miss and love deeply in your heart</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My mother was born and raised at</p>
<p>황해도 장영군 후남면 남호리 291.</p>
<p>Google search of her hometown yields<br>
<strong>Google Maps can’t find…</strong></p>
<p>My mother’s family is originally from Pyong Yang (평양, 平壤) area.</p>
<p>Her family went through occupation by Japanese and Russians.<br>
Learned about communism, firsthand.<br>
A war between Koreas, lost her father at age 14.<br>
Then escaped to South Korea.</p>
<p>All this before she turned 20 years old</p>
<section id="life-under-the-japanese-occupation-1932-1945" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="life-under-the-japanese-occupation-1932-1945">Life under the Japanese Occupation (1932-1945)</h2>
<p>Mother’s family owned land and buildings.<br>
They owned a local hub for merchandise called 협성상회協成商会.<br>
They also distributed Mainichi Daily 毎日新聞</p>
<p>Grandfather often traveled to Incheon to trade and would bring back latest merchandise home.</p>
<p>Life was not idyllic but they were well off for the time and place.</p>
<p>One day, grandfather took mom aside and showed their holdings and commented.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“all this land belongs to us. orchard and rice fields, plus buildings”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Looking back, my mother observed. Life wasn’t easy but no one starved, necessary items were plentiful, and even fish was visible in the stream.</p>
</section>
<section id="life-after-liberation-communism-and-russian-occupation-1945-1950" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="life-after-liberation-communism-and-russian-occupation-1945-1950">Life after liberation : Communism and Russian occupation (1945-1950)</h2>
<p>Communists took everything, putting red stickers on all of mom’s belongings.<br>
Former workers brought food for a year, until no one had private food.</p>
<p>There was no longer incentive to work harder.<br>
Everyone got same amount.<br>
(They would count grains to give same amount)</p>
<p>Mom had to gather woods, using an ‘A’ Frame, or <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jige">지게</a>, she was 13 and the oldest.</p>
<p>She was trained to use guns and military drills - using Russian words and techniques.</p>
<p>Communists turned parents against children. By forcing children to report against parents and vice versa.</p>
<p>(Compare Malachi 4:6)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>And he shall turn the heart of the fathers to the children, and the heart of the children to their fathers, lest I come and smite the earth with a curse</p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="separation-of-hwang-family-1945-1950" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="separation-of-hwang-family-1945-1950">Separation of Hwang Family (1945-1950)</h2>
<p>Our grandfather passed away in 1945, the same year that his only son was born. With death of the father, the life became increasingly difficult for the family.</p>
<p>Once asked mom how she survived bombings during the war. She responded simply,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>we had a bunker built next to the kitchen. when the air-raid siren sounded, we all took refuge in the bunker</p>
</blockquote>
<p>With battle for the control of 38th Parallel continuing around the area, family elders arranged for an escape.</p>
<p>As mother left her home, the family hid the ancestral records underneath wood paneling that separated living area from the house foundation.</p>
<p>Many of the elderly stayed because because the evacuation was temporary</p>
<p>45 person boat was arranged however only half the boat was filled. (Mom’s family almost didn’t make it to the rendevouz point).</p>
<p>One lady had a baby on the boat. The family got extra rations, since there were 5 children with a single mother.</p>
</section>
<section id="a-family-member-left-behind" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-family-member-left-behind">A family member left behind</h2>
<p>Additional tragedy, and one that hasn’t been resolved to this day, was that one of the siblings didn’t get on that boat.<br>
Originally, my mother was chosen to spend time with an aunt (grandma’s sister) in Wonsan. (Husband of the aunt was killed in an industrial accident and she had become a minister in a church)</p>
<p>But grandma Kim objected and insisted that her oldest daughter stay with her. As a compromise, the second oldest went to stay with the aunt. However, the bombing of roads and bridges meant that she couldn’t get back in time to join the family.</p>
<p>My aunt, <code>Hyunsook</code> 현숙, was left behind. And we don’t know whether she is still living.<br>
The last contact was over 70 years ago.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230112 38th Parallel Pt 2/images/IMG_8252 Copy.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Surviving Hwang Sisters</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>아~~ 꽃필 때나 오시려느냐</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>아~~~~ 눈올 때나 오시려느냐</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>보따리 등에 메고 넘던 고개길</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>산새도 나와 함께 울고 넘었지</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>자유여 너를 위해 자유여 너를 위해</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>이 목숨을 바친다</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Will you return when flowers bloom<br>
Or when snow covers fields<br>
Recall when we escaped with essentials on our back<br>
Even birds sang mournfully through mountain passages<br>
Freedom, I re-dedicate my life</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>한국민족문화대백과사전, 韓国民族文化大百科辞典↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>divided</category>
  <category>future</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230112 38th Parallel Pt 2/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230112 38th Parallel Pt 2/IMG_3143.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Deers of Rock Canyon</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230109 rock canyon deers/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>At first significant snowstorm, each fall, my dad would look towards Timpanogos and ask,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“Wonder where deers go for their food…”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Since I didn’t know, I couldn’t answer so we moved on to a different topic.</p>
<p>Our family lived in Provo for nearly 40 years.</p>
<p>We have hiked Rock Canyon as a family.<br>
All of my children graduated from Rock Canyon Elementary.</p>
<p>This is our neighborhood and we know all there is to know about it.</p>
<p>That was an incorrect reasoning.</p>
<p>One afternoon, after parking the car at the Rock Canyon Park, I started a hike up to the Bonneville Shoreline Trail.</p>
<p>Noticed a truck with a scope pointed at a spot above the trail. My curiosity was piqued.</p>
<p>I didn’t have to ask much, the man anticipated my queries and explained in detail about the feeding pattern, places to watch, best times to see.</p>
<p>He knew so much about the deer herd of Rock Canyon. He showed me when to look (during mealtime), where to look (30-40 feet above the trail), and what to look for (herd of deer).</p>
<p>I had never seen a deer herd before meeting this man with a scope.<br>
Since meeting with and coaching from the man, I can’t avoid seeing the herd.</p>
<p>One day, during a snowstorm, I saw a group of deer, moving together on a well-defined path, along the south edge of the Squaw Peak, about 200 feet above where I was.</p>
<p>So what seemed like a rhetorical question by my dad, turned into a specific teaching moment for me about the survival of deer in the wintertime.</p>
<p>(Perhaps my dad, who has passed away, was gently influencing the man with the scope to teach me a thing or two)</p>
<p>So in this life, it seems, that one can pose a question or raise an issue and others may solve it for us. Or one can jump in and try to find, not only the answer, but also implement the solution once found.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Ask, and it shall be given you; seek, and ye shall find; knock, and it shall be opened unto you:</p>
</blockquote>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230109 rock canyon deers/20220306_075930.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Rock Canyon Deer Herd</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>For every one that asketh receiveth; and he that seeketh findeth; and to him that knocketh it shall be opened.</p>
</blockquote>



 ]]></description>
  <category>compassion</category>
  <category>guidance</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230109 rock canyon deers/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230109 rock canyon deers/20221112_171117-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Lord Delivers</title>
  <dc:creator>Young Irvine</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230105 My Family Escape/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><code>Talk given at Seneca Stake, Spring 2022</code></p>
<p>Hello brothers and sisters,</p>
<p>My topic today is <strong>Jesus Christ is my Deliverer</strong>, which is taken from <strong><em>Come Follow Me, Exodus Chapters One to Two</em></strong>.</p>
<p>There are many ways the Lord can deliver His children from the challenges in life.</p>
<p>When the ancient Israelites were in Egypt, they faced huge hardships.</p>
<p>They were slaves.</p>
<p>They were forced to do hard labor.</p>
<p>They had no hope for a better life.</p>
<p>So what did they do?</p>
<p>In Exodus Chapter 2, Verse 23, it reads,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“They cried … unto God” for help.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And the Lord answered their prayers.</p>
<p>He remembered His covenant people and sent Moses to help free them.</p>
<p>Moses was a tool to guide the children of Israel to the Promised Land. Through Moses, who received authority from the Lord to act as His prophet, there were many miracles.</p>
<p>There is the story of Moses parting of the Red Sea to escape the Egyptians.</p>
<p>There is also the story of the people of Israel receiving manna, or bread, from heaven.</p>
<p>The Lord also told Moses to split a rock to provide water to the people in the desert, which Moses did.</p>
<p>All these miracles happened along the people of Israel’s journey back to the Promised Land.</p>
<p>The Lord physically and spiritually sustained them.</p>
<p>In a very significant way, the Lord guided my family to the United States of America.</p>
<p>In Ether Chapter Two Verses 9 and 12, it reads that the Americas is “a land of promise” and a “choice land.”</p>
<p>The Lord delivers us from our struggles and bad situations.</p>
<p>How do I know this?</p>
<p>Because He delivered my mother from living under a communist regime.</p>
<p>My mother’s family were Christians for three generations, at the time, but they lived in fear in North Korea.</p>
<p>Under the government, the ultimate punishments for Christian worshippers were being sent to do time in a hard labor camp or the firing squad. She kept her faith by praying daily at night under a thick blanket.</p>
<p>She was like the people of Alma in the Book of Mormon, who prayed in their hearts to avoid punishment from their enemies. He heard my mother’s prayers and I know that He answered her prayers.</p>
<p>During the Korean War some seventy years ago, her family and other refugees were evacuated to a safer area in South Korea, thanks to the assistance from the United States Navy. <sup>1</sup></p>
<p>While the war raged on, my mother and her family rarely lost hope and constantly prayed for the peace in the land. She saw miracles on many occasions, such as when the meager rations lasted longer than expected and also when her family received help from strangers, countless times.</p>
<p>The Lord delivered my mother’s family.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230105 My Family Escape/IMG_2154.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Mom, center 2nd row, attending a Protestant Church 1960s</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>When my father was twenty years old, he was drafted into fighting for the South Korean Army during the Korean War. He was captured and tortured by the enemy on at least three different occasions.</p>
<p>However, he managed to escape from his captors and reunited with his army unit each time. He told me countless times that he was led by the powerful impressions to know when and which direction to run during his escapes.</p>
<p>One time, after being captured, the enemy soldier told my father that he was “too young to die” and he was spared from execution.</p>
<p>I am thankful to the Lord that He delivered my father from certain death.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230105 My Family Escape/IMG_2154 (1).JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Father during the late 1950s</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Having seen the horrors of war first-hand, my parents decided to emigrate to the U.S.</p>
<p>The Lord can deliver our family from difficult situations by inspiring a way to escape, in this case, emigrate to the chosen land.</p>
<p>My family has been blessed to be in this country and to be members of the Lord’s restored and true Church.</p>
<p>All of my children have served missions for the Church in Southern California and South Korea.</p>
<p>My nephews and niece have also served missions in New York City, Washington State, Taiwan, Hong Kong, and Japan.</p>
<p>Don and I are serving in the Washington, D.C. North Mission.</p>
<p>It has been a great blessing to serve among the young missionaries and the senior missionaries. We have learned so much about the inner workings of the mission and how many sacrifices are made to do the Lord’s work here in this area, and also throughout the world.</p>
<p>I would not have guessed that we would be serving a mission in our home region if you had asked me several years ago. But here we are, and we are loving this opportunity to serve the Lord in order to pay Him back for delivering us from our trials.</p>
<p>Our prayers are with those in Ukraine at this time, and we know that the Lord will deliver them during these troubled and difficult times just as He did for my family in Korea. Though many Ukrainians are not of our faith, their faith has gotten them through the difficulties of war and they have declared that God sustains and supports them.</p>
<p>As the Lord declared, “Peace I give unto you.” He will bless us with peace and He will deliver us from our trials.</p>
<p>In Doctrine and Covenants Section 84, Verse 88, the Lord told the early Saints that He will send angels to us:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“And whoso receiveth you, there I will be also, for I will go before your face. I will be on your right hand and on your left, and my Spirit shall be in your hearts, and mine angels round about you, to bear you up.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In closing:</p>
<p>I know that the Lord Jesus Christ has power to deliver me from problems and troubles just like He did with the ancient Israelites. I know my Savior lives and loves me. I know Joseph Smith is a prophet of God.</p>
<p>In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>The ship described by mom here was the LST class, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Landing_Ship,_Tank">Landing Ship Tank</a>↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>gratitude</category>
  <category>parents</category>
  <category>korean war</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230105 My Family Escape/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230105 My Family Escape/IMG_2154 (1).JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>가거라三八線</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230103 38th Parallel/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>The number 38 is significant to all Koreans.</p>
<p>But for those born north of the 38 degrees latitude, it means far more.</p>
<p>It means longing for a home, that is beyond reach, in this lifetime.</p>
<p>My father’s home is 함경도 안변군 신모면 이남리 47 about 10 miles south of present day Wonsan (원산시, 元山市) Port. Located about 150 miles northwest from Seoul.</p>
<p>My father’s family was living in this remote part of Korea, when his maternal uncle, 김동훈 traveled by foot to find the family.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230103 38th Parallel/Epson_01022023180832-01.jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img" style="width:50.0%"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Uncle 김동훈</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>The uncle convinced the family life would be better in the South.</p>
<p>My father’s family was settled in South Korea. He had a chance to work for a Japanese company</p>
<p>Few years later, when Japanese left, he became the owner of the home that belonged to a manager.</p>
<p>He was all of 15 years of age.</p>
<p>Later he was drafted in the South Korean army and was on a weekend leave when the fighting broke out on Sunday, June 25th, 1950.</p>
<p>(Father fought in major battles of Korean War and he wondered how he survived those battles)</p>
<p>Father thinks, had he remained in North Korea and had fought for the North Korean Army, he may not have survived the war.</p>
<p>Father always had appreciation for the uncle that sought out the family and led them to a freer and a land with more opportunities</p>
<p>아~~ 산이 막혀 못 오시나요<br>
아~~~~ 물이 막혀 못 오시나요<br>
다 같은 고향 (家鄉, 故郷) 땅을 가고 오련만<br>
남북이 가로 막혀 원한 천리(千里)길<br>
꿈마다 너를 찾아 꿈마다<br>
너를 찾아 삼팔선(三八線)을 탄한다</p>
<p>Ah, is the mountain in your way?<br>
Or is the river too wide?<br>
All are free to visit place of birth<br>
The blocked boundary makes mine seem a 1000 里<br>
Visit you in a dream and blame the 38th parallel</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>divided</category>
  <category>future</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230103 38th Parallel/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230103 38th Parallel/Epson_12112022170630-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>새해 다음 월요일</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230102 Tuesday Aftrernoon/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Been going through dad’s study area.</p>
<p>Letters, certificates, photos and some books.</p>
<p>Church books, <code>명상록</code> (瞑想録) by Marcus Aurelius, <code>Maxims and Proverbs of Old Korea</code> 한국속담 by Ha Tae Hung.</p>
<p>My parents had their favorite sayings.</p>
<ul>
<li>소문난 잔치에 먹을 것 없다
<ul>
<li>There is nothing to eat at a rumored feast</li>
</ul></li>
<li>젊어서 고생은 사서도 한다
<ul>
<li>people even pay for a hardship in their younger age</li>
</ul></li>
<li>양약고구(良藥苦口, 良 좋을 량, 藥 약 약, 苦 쓸 고, 口 입 구)
<ul>
<li>bad taste in mouth, good for the body.</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<p>More importantly they taught by example, not only how to handle difficult situations but teaching that life is a long journey.</p>
<p>Grateful that they shared their life’s lessons and that guided my life and made it had meaningful.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“What words of wisdom can I give them<br>
How can I help to ease their way?<br>
Now they must learn from one another<br>
Day by day”</p>
</blockquote>
<p><code>Fiddler on the Roof</code></p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230102 Tuesday Aftrernoon/20230102_133107-01.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230102 Tuesday Aftrernoon/Epson_12172022120822-COLLAGE.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>lessons</category>
  <category>snow</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230102 Tuesday Aftrernoon/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230102 Tuesday Aftrernoon/20230102_133107-03.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Adagio ma non troppo</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20221228 ma non troppo/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Life is kind, it washes away and lets us forget pains and troubles, little by little.</p>
<p>Life is cruel, it also extinguishes memories that you want to hold onto, all at once.</p>
<p>However, a small trigger, a kindness can ignite a flood of memories.</p>
<p>Each day I am more keenly aware of passage of time and an eventual end of present engagement or the assignment.</p>
<p>Hence the increased awareness and appreciation of each sunrise and sunset</p>
<p>Increased fondness for friendship and shared memories.</p>
<p>In daily, or hourly struggles,</p>
<p>Sometimes, I wish for a credit for lost weeks, months, and even years, because of things that can’t be controlled.<br>
At times, I am glad that I can’t recall, with any details those forgettable moments.</p>
<p>I am satisfied that God knows and is in charge and I must submit to my lot in life.</p>
<ul>
<li>Ecclesiastes 3:11</li>
</ul>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p><strong><em>He has made everything beautiful in its time. He has also set eternity in the human heart; yet no one can fathom what God has done from beginning to end. NIV (New International Version)</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20221228 ma non troppo/20220904_071432_2.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>memory</category>
  <category>time</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20221228 ma non troppo/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20221228 ma non troppo/20211227_075031_2-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Holiday Snowstorms</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20221226 snowstorm/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Snowstorms before Christmas brings memories of years past, as a student — and a father.<br>
June and I had 2 children before graduating from school.</p>
<p>Around Halloween, we brought our 2nd child, a son, home to a 500 square foot apartment.</p>
<p>It was snowing.</p>
<p>Our daughter welcomed home her brother and played with a doll with black hair like her.</p>
<p>I should have been worried, no terrified, about finishing school. Also obtaining a job that would pay sufficiently.</p>
<p>June directed and took care of matters so that I can focus on school tasks and worry less about the future.<br>
Recently, have learned the steps she had to take to live on a student budget. We cut out even necessary things to get by.</p>
<p>One of the few entertainment options was a video/pizza place on Canyon Road.<br>
For a couple of bucks, one can order a plain pizza and rent a videocassette movie.</p>
<p>Glad that we didn’t have internet and social media those days.<br>
It forced me to stay in school and work with others to get the work done.<br>
Also, there were no distractions on what other people were making or doing.</p>
<p>Because of her effort, and some family support, I was able to complete school and find a job. I was happy to have job, not too concerned about the salary. It was another 7 years before my salary matched our needs.</p>
<p>Even now, I recall how she encouraged and comforted me and made sure that home was welcoming and had freshly prepared meal ready. Because of it I didn’t know how desperate the situation and bleak the future really was.</p>
<p>Now, those 2 children are raising a family of their own.<br>
They are supporting one another and establishing a home of their own.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20221226 snowstorm/20221127_170959-01.jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">December Sunset</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>



 ]]></description>
  <category>gratitude</category>
  <category>nostalgia</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20221226 snowstorm/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20221226 snowstorm/20221213_182457-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>My Seminary Teacher : Remembered</title>
  <dc:creator>Steve Rawlins</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/carol rawlins 2/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Three days from now we will celebrate the the most important birth in history some 2000 years ago to Mary and Joseph in Bethlehem.</p>
<p>But for me the the birth of the second most important person in my life occurred 91 years ago on this day to Clyde and Elva Carter in Orem, Utah.</p>
<p>Her name is Carol Jean.</p>
<p>Three months and twenty days ago she passed through the veil to return to her Heavenly Father.<br>
It was her time to go but not my time to let her go.</p>
<p>She has left huge hole in my heart.</p>
<p>I want to tell you some things about this beautiful feisty woman.<br>
She was quiet but tough.</p>
<p>She had a very clear sense how she should live her life and once she made up her mind to do something she did it regardless of circumstances.</p>
<p>Her son, David said of her</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“she had an unwavering belief in our potential to do whatever we set our mind to. I know her belief in me made a difference in my life.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And her belief in me made all the difference in my life and I’d like to tell you about it.</p>
<p>I had grown up on a small farm in Washington state and had not taken college preparation courses in a high school but instead had taken courses to prepare me to go back to the farm.</p>
<p>Following graduation I was working for a farmer harvesting sugar beets when the weather turned cold and froze the beets in the ground. Two of my friends returned from BYU for Christmas break and told me how nice it was at BYU.</p>
<p>I decided I’d had enough trying to dig frozen beets out of the ground and put my clothes into a cardboard box and took a Greyhound bus to Provo.</p>
<p>I didn’t plan to stay in school but thought that a few agriculture classes couldn’t hurt.</p>
<p>I just wanted to get out of the cold.</p>
<p>It turned out that my two friends were renting rooms in Carol’s home In Provo and they introduced me to her.</p>
<p>At BYU of course I signed up for agriculture classes and Dr.&nbsp;Thomas Martin was my advisor.</p>
<p>At the end of the quarter I was in his microbiology class and at the end of it he said</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“Mr.&nbsp;Rawlins I would like to see you in my office”.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Being very shy and insecure I entered with trepidation wondering what I had done.</p>
<p>He said to me</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“Mr Rawlins I’ve been observing your work and next quarter I don’t think you should take any more agriculture classes. You can learn all that by reading books. I think you should take Math, Physics and Chemistry classes and go on and get your PhD”.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I was completely shocked. This was the furthest thing from my mind.</p>
<p>By this time Carol and I were seeing each other occasionally and when I told her of this preposterous suggestion and that I thought Dr.&nbsp;Martin was out of his mind she did did not agree.</p>
<p>She had worked as a secretary for him and was aware of his success in helping students obtain advanced degrees.</p>
<p>She simply said</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“of course you should do it. You can accomplish anything so set your mind to do”.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And she never wavered from her belief in my potential.</p>
<p>When the PhD diploma was issued it had my name on it but she was responsible for a huge part of it.</p>
<p>As I have looked back I realize that without the confidence I had gained from Carol’s belief in me there would have been no PhD.</p>
<p>I would not have returned to school and would have simply returned home and got some kind of a job. With my limited resources there is no question that I would not have been a successful farmer but would have probably ended up as a farm worker as many in my family had been.</p>
<p>What a special woman she is.</p>
<p>I literally owe my life to her.</p>
<p>And it’s impossible to know how many lives like mine have been changed by her example of personal courage and an unwavering belief in their potential.</p>
<p>What a blessing she has been to all us that have had the privilege of having her in our lives.</p>
<p>Our last six months living in a senior living center have been wonderful.</p>
<p>With no external distractions and relatively good health we have spent all of our time doing things together and have grown very close.</p>
<p>When Carol returned from rehab for her hip surgery where I could not spend the night we were so pleased to be able to be together.</p>
<p>On the morning a day before she died she rolled over and laid her head on my shoulder and said to me</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“I love you Stephen. We are a team. We are tough cookies and together we can handle anything life brings our way”.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And with Carol’s example of strength and courage and the help and guidance of our Lord I know I will be able to handle whatever life brings to me including this temporary separation from her.</p>
<p><code>Steve Rawlins</code></p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/carol rawlins 2/carol_stephen.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Carol and Steve</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>



 ]]></description>
  <category>gratitude</category>
  <category>marriage</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/carol rawlins 2/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/carol rawlins 2/IMG_2371.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>shewed mercy and was a neighbor to strangers</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/strangers/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>My mother will be coming home in a few days.</p>
<p>She has been in the Utah Valley Hospital and Provo Rehabilitation &amp; Nursing since November 10th.</p>
<p>Grateful to dedicated workers, technology, and the grace of God.</p>
<p>For unknown reasons, her right arm began to swell and changed colors – to purple.</p>
<p>Workers performed blood tests, administered IV and blood transfusion and managed her pain.</p>
<p>Doctors at the hospital determined that acute symptoms have abated and discharged her to the rehabilitation facility across the street, to recover and to return home.</p>
<p>But her arm didn’t get better.</p>
<p>Although Rehab facility personnel tried their best with their given resources, my mom’s pain and the swelling increased.</p>
<p>As a last resort, her daughter-in-law pleaded with administrators to send her back to the hospital for evaluations – to find the cause.</p>
<p>A nurse from the radiology admission area came to take mom to the CT (computer tomography) Scan area.</p>
<p>When the nurse saw the condition of the arm, she changed the directive and wheeled my mom to the emergency area.</p>
<p>Because of the action of that nurse, mom was able to get both the CT Scan and the Ultrasound of her arm and increased attention on pain management.</p>
<p>The evaluations showed that there was a pseudo-aneurysm in her artery near the fistula.</p>
<p>The solution was to inject Thrombin into the area that was leaking blood.</p>
<p>The surgery was performed on the day before Thanksgiving.</p>
<p>It was successful and mom avoided more invasive surgery.</p>
<p>Now she can begin the 4-week recovery.</p>
<p>Thankful to be living in a time and place that has access to the latest medical advancements. To live among men and women with the knowledge and practice medicine with wisdom.</p>
<p>To those men and women that responded and answered the prayer and pleading of the daughter-in-law and shewed mercy and was a neighbor to strangers - thank you.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/strangers/mom.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>neighbor</category>
  <category>mercy</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/strangers/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/strangers/IMG_6893-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>景翳翳以將入</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/shadows/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>“Shadows darken as the sun prepares to set;</p>
<p>caressing a solitary pine I tarry long”</p>
<p>景翳翳以將入，撫孤松而盤桓。</p>
<p>~ 歸去來辭</p>
<p>Tao Yuanming 陶淵明 (365-427)</p>
<p>*****</p>
<p>ƒ/1.8 aperture</p>
<p>1/90 shutter speed</p>
<p>6.7mm focal length</p>
<p>ISO16</p>
<p>Colors enhanced using Snapseed App.</p>
<p>Taken in the Oak Hills area, looking towards Eureka and beyond..</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/shadows/sunset.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>sunset</category>
  <category>陶淵明</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/shadows/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/shadows/sunset.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Rabbi Manis Friedman</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/doubt resolution/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>YouTube algorithm suggested Rabbi Manis Friedman.</p>
<p>The Rabbi looks like someone from the Old Testament days, with a long white beard.</p>
<p>So far I heard him talk about money, relationship and meaning.</p>
<hr>
<p>Quoting Gemara (Talmud) he said in a video post,</p>
<p>“there’s no joy like the joy of the resolution of doubts”</p>
<p>Because,</p>
<p>Things that make us unhappy are doubts.</p>
<p>Best solution to regaining joy is to</p>
<p>(wake up in the morning and)</p>
<p>focus on the things you have no doubts about</p>
<p>(and repeat at the end of the day)</p>
<p>my parents’ life, that is something to remember.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/doubt resolution/marunouchi.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Marunouch</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>



 ]]></description>
  <category>talmud</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/doubt resolution/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/doubt resolution/marunouchi.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>That is why we go</title>
  <dc:creator>Mark A. Wilson</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/that is why/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>“Sir, I want to thank you and your fellow countrymen<br>
for coming to the aid of my country so many years ago.<br>
Because of your sacrifices, people like me could grow up in freedom!”.</p>
<p>My father knew the reason for the war.</p>
<p>Mark A. Wilson’s father had to wait 40 years to find the answer.</p>
<p>When my father passed away (Feb 1930 - May 2020) I wrote his life sketch.</p>
<p>It was posted on FB and Mark mentioned his father was born a week earlier and he too served in the Korean War.</p>
<p>I thanked him for the sacrifice and Mark shared the story of how his father learned the meaning of his service in Korea.</p>
<p>Thank you, all those that have served the country, and in particular, during Korean conflict.<br>
For preserving the freedom for the people of Korea.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Thank you for your gratitude! My dad died 20 years ago. He never talked about his experiences in South Korea. He refused to answer our questions, even when we asked him directly.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>About the only thing he would ever say was how much of a waste of men it was. He claimed he never understood why “kids” his age had to go so far away to kill people.</p>
<p>But, in 1992 my mother died. A year later my dad had remarried and came to DC to “see the sights” with my stepmother.</p>
<p>I volunteered to be their tour guide! One day we were doing the Mall area, visiting the monuments.</p>
<p>Back then, there was a small eatery near the base of the Washington monument. We went there for some lunch.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/that is why/monuments.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The three of us sat at a small table in the back. A few minutes later an Asian kid asked if he could join us!</p>
<p>My dad started asking him questions. He was 18 years old and from Busan, South Korea, and was touring the United States.</p>
<p>My dad said, “Oh, I’ve been to Busan, but it is probably in a lot better shape today!”.</p>
<p>Then the kid asked my dad some questions about my dad’s experience South Korea, which, surprisingly he answered (this is how I now know my dad was in Busan and Inchon)!</p>
<p>The kid eventually finished his lunch, asked my dad if he could be excused, and took his trash to the garbage can.</p>
<p>Then he came back!?</p>
<p>He stood in front of my dad at attention and saluted him!</p>
<p>He said something like, “Sir, I want to thank you and your fellow countrymen for coming to the aid of my country so many years ago. Because of your sacrifices, people like me could grow up in freedom!”.</p>
<p>And, poof! he was gone, lost in the crowds before any of us could say anything.</p>
<p>When I looked at my dad, there was a tear rolling down his face. After a few minutes, he mumbled something like, “So, that is why we go!!!”. And, after that he never complained about going “so far away”. He still wouldn’t answer any questions us kids had, but lunch that day at the base of the Washington monument changed his outlook on life…and his war.</p>
<p>So, it is in this light, I thank you David Kang, for expressing your gratitude! I’m sure, if my dad was alive today, your gratitude would bring another tear to his cheek!!!</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/that is why/20221015_183517-01.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>korean war</category>
  <category>gratitude</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/that is why/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/that is why/monuments.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>as you wish</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/princess bride/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>At times a popular movie alters and captures the mindset and imagination of a whole generation – and beyond.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>One such movie, for my generation, was the <strong>Princess Bride</strong>, released in 1987.</p>
<p>The movie fulfilled a need of that time period by re-visiting tried and true movie making approaches – with a modern twist.</p>
<p>Action-Romantic-Comedy, not necessarily in the order of importance, would be one classification of the movie.&nbsp; But like all great movies, it created its own genre and became a source of Vulgate for years to come.</p>
<p>Beyond its romance tinged plot, the witty dialogue won me over.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/best-quotes-from-the-princess-bride-list-2017-9" class="uri">https://www.businessinsider.com/best-quotes-from-the-princess-bride-list-2017-9</a></p>
<p><br>
</p>
<p><strong>Grandpa</strong>: Nothing gave <strong>Buttercup</strong> as much pleasure as ordering <strong>Westley</strong> around.</p>
<p><strong>Buttercup</strong>: Farm boy, polish my horse’s saddle. I want to see my face shining in it by morning.</p>
<p><strong>Westley</strong>: As you wish.</p>
<p><strong>Grandpa</strong>: “As you wish” was all he ever said to her.</p>
<p><strong>Buttercup</strong>: Farm boy, fill these with water - please.</p>
<p><strong>Westley</strong>: As you wish.</p>
<p><strong>Grandpa</strong>: That day, she was amazed to discover that when he was saying “<strong>As you wish</strong>,” what he</p>
<p>meant was, “<strong>I love you</strong>.” And even more amazing was the day she realized she truly loved him back.</p>
<p><strong>Buttercup</strong>: Farm boy ... fetch me that pitcher.</p>
<p><strong>Westley</strong>: As you wish.</p>
<p><br>
</p>
<p>When a relationship is solid, growing, and nurturing, voices are subdued.</p>
<p>At times no sound is needed.</p>
<p>For "As you wish" can be conveyed, just as well, without words</p>
<p>The Lord God speaks in a still, small voice.</p>
<p>When people are listening, following, obeying, no dramatic intervention is needed.</p>
<p>If not, 災難 (disasters), wars and rumors of war and captivity of nations and souls follow.</p>
<p><strong>Princess Bride</strong> showed that the dialogues are just as important, perhaps more important than actions in movies – as the popularity of Korean Dramas have recently demonstrated.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>love</category>
  <category>nostalgia</category>
  <category>indirect</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/princess bride/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/princess bride/20221019_084239 (1).jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Improve on Silence</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/silence/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>“In saying what I have in mind, will I really improve on the silence?”</p>
<p><em>Robert K Greenleaf, Servant Leadership, page 17</em></p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/silence/20211228_085952 (1).jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Apache Trail</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>



 ]]></description>
  <category>servant-leader</category>
  <category>silence</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/silence/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/silence/20211228_085952 (1).jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Superheroes</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/superheroes/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>They are to live forever. They are always full of energy and hope. They are superheroes that we can always count on.</p>
<p>They are our parents.</p>
<p>One of the challenges of this life is to see our heroes fade away.</p>
<p>Many in my parents’ generation experienced wars, colonial occupation, famine, torn families, political and economic upheavals, street demonstrations that led to democratic reforms and eventual economic miracle.</p>
<p>In particular, my parents had to re-start their lives in 2 different countries – as refugees and immigrants.</p>
<p>Once as refugees of a war, from their home in North Korea to South Korea in their teenage years.</p>
<p>Next as a searching for better economic outcome immigrant to United States in their 40s</p>
<p>I don’t recall all the individual lessons of my parents.</p>
<p>I do remember their calm approach to life.</p>
<p>Because of their experiences with people, events, and challenges that they had to overcome, growing up, I never saw them panic.</p>
<p>They would analyze the situation, draw upon their collective experiences, then formulate a plan to deal with it.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>If the burden seemed too heavy, they called on the help from above.</p>
<p>Their, not so secret, arsenal was their faith in God.</p>
<p>Both of them lived their lives in accordance with this&nbsp;Christian principles,</p>
<p><strong><em>Therefore all things whatsoever ye would that men should do to you, do ye even so to them: for this is the law and the prophets.</em></strong></p>
<p>As my wife and I are assuming the role of that generation.</p>
<p>We are not prepared for that role and are scared about the future.</p>
<p>However, these things give us hope</p>
<p>Strength and tender care and love our parents demonstrated.</p>
<p>A certain knowledge that God is with us.</p>
<p>Watching and associating with the people of this rising generation.</p>
<p>This generation that knows far more than we ever imagined at their age.</p>
<p>This generation that is not afraid to tackle tasks, considered too difficult in generations past.</p>
<p>Thank you Mom and Dad, we can count on this new generation of superheroes.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>parents</category>
  <category>heroes</category>
  <category>lessons</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/superheroes/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/superheroes/dad_uncle.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Welcome To My Blog</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/welcome/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>To remember the faith, experience and wisdom of my parents.</p>
<p>November 2022</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/welcome/mom_dad.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>intro</category>
  <category>parents</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/welcome/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/welcome/mom_dad.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
