<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Quarto Blog</title>
<link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.2.269</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 06:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Korean War : 1950 - 1953</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Remembrance of past events is beneficial – even without the benefit of personal witness and its recollection and interpretation.</p>
<p>Without my father’s personal recollection, the Korean War remembrance is unfocused and its significance reduced.</p>
<p><a href="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230530%20Reunite/">past Korean War remembrance</a></p>
<p>In that post, I pleaded with God for a single, united nation under God. South Korea and North Korea becoming one nation.</p>
<p>That is no longer my wish.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/main.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<hr>
<p>The 70th Anniversary of cessation of hostility in Korea has re-invigorated the idea of Peace Treaty that will replace the Armistice Treaty signed on 27 July 1953.</p>
<p>An internet search of key words <code>Korea Peace Treaty</code> yielded the following.</p>
<p>Pope Francis through Korean emissary, Cardinal Lazzaro You Heung-sik, wished for peace on the Korean Peninsula.<sup>1</sup></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>In this way, I trust that the marking of the armistice will point not only to the cessation of hostilities but to a bright future of reconciliation, fraternity and enduring harmony for the Korean Peninsula, and indeed the wider world,</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Reporter Iris Kim writes in <code>NBC News</code> <sup>2</sup></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>The U.S. has a moral responsibility to finally end the war</p>
</blockquote>
<p>World Council of Churches (WCC) stated,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>… a formal declaration of the end of the Korean War “could be a powerful circuit-breaker and catalyst for peace.”<sup>3</sup></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Congresswoman, Young Kim,<sup>4</sup> writes an article in <code>Foreign Policy</code>, <strong>A Korean Peace Treaty Would Be an Unforced Blunder</strong></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>The big problem here is that North Korea has consistently failed to abide by previous attempts to make peace on the Korean Peninsula<sup>5</sup></p>
</blockquote>
<p>While these are timely and necessary reminders, repetition will not result in a breakthrough.</p>
<hr>
<p>Rather than wishing for a peace or united country, I will ask for a new freedom for people in North Korea and continued protection of freedom for South Koreans.</p>
<p>People of Israel was in bondage for over 100 years. Rabbi Dovid Rosenfeld estimates,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>the (Egyptian) slavery lasted somewhere between 86 and 116 years.<sup>6</sup></p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>How much longer do Koreans in Northern Korea must endure their bondage?</li>
</ul>
<p>Furthermore, after wandering in the wilderness for 40 years nearly all died.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Every Israelite over twenty years of age when they left Egypt under Moses’ leadership was now dead, except for three people: Moses, Joshua, and Caleb (see Numbers 14:38).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My father was 20 years old when the Korean War began.</p>
<p>He and others, both from North and South Korea as well as United Nations Command and China, served their nations and its people.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/landscape.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Korean War Casualties<sup>7</sup></figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>They all served the cause or ideologies of their countries. For this we thank them.</p>
<div id="fig-medals" class="quarto-layout-panel">
<figure class="figure">
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell quarto-layout-cell-subref" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div id="fig-8876" class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center anchored">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/IMG_8876.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img" data-ref-parent="fig-medals"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">(a) 8876</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell quarto-layout-cell-subref" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div id="fig-3648" class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center anchored">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/IMG_3648.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img" data-ref-parent="fig-medals"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">(b) 3648</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell quarto-layout-cell-subref" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div id="fig-3651" class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center anchored">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/IMG_3651.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img" data-ref-parent="fig-medals"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">(c) 3651</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell quarto-layout-cell-subref" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div id="fig-0360" class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center anchored">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/IMG_0360.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img" data-ref-parent="fig-medals"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">(d) 0360</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Figure&nbsp;1: Dad’s Medals of Appreciation from the Korean Government</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Within 20 years, those that were old enough to remember the War (older than 10 years of age in 1950) will reach 100 years age.</p>
<p>My generation remembers stories and lessons of the war, but it is fading.</p>
<ul>
<li>What would be a benefit of a united nation if no one has common experience and no binding ideology?</li>
</ul>
<p>God has performed miracles on behalf of people of Korea.<br>
That will continue – in His timeline.</p>
<p>God has led our family out of bondage and harms way a number of times.<br>
We will continue to praise and serve Him.</p>
<p>The re-uniting of families in Korea will occur in manner and in time designated by God.</p>
<p>But if we could ask for a wish or two, like Alma.</p>
<ul>
<li>Would it be possible for missionaries to re-enter both North and South Korea and hearts will be re-united with their God and their people</li>
<li>Would it be unrealistic to ask for a religious gathering in PyongYang on the anniversary of the War or the Armistice Treaty Signing?</li>
</ul>
<p>The message of truth, the Good News, will enable freedom to return to the Korean Peninsula and remain.</p>
<p>Free people of God will then organize a form of government and establish an economy that will both strengthen and enrich both people and the country.</p>
<p>This is my revised wish.</p>
<p>July 2023</p>
<p>Son of a North Korean Christian Family</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://www.koreaherald.com/view.php?ud=20230727000764#:~:text=%22In%20this%20way%2C%20I%20trust,wider%20world%2C%22%20it%20added.↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>https://www.nbcnews.com/news/asian-america/70-years-later-koreans-are-still-working-formally-end-korean-war-rcna96209↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>https://www.oikoumene.org/news/wcc-stands-in-hope-with-korean-peninsula-during-conference-marking-70th-anniversary-of-armistice-agreement↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn4"><p>the representative for Calfornia’s 40th Congressional District and chairwoman of the Indo-Pacific Subcommittee of the U.S. House Foreign Affairs Committee↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn5"><p>https://foreignpolicy.com/2023/07/27/north-south-korea-peace-war-treaty-armistice-united-states/↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn6"><p>https://aish.com/duration-of-slavery-in-egypt/↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn7"><p>https://www.britannica.com/event/Korean-War↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>remembrance</category>
  <category>resolve</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Opportunitites Will Come</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230704 Seek Opportunity/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Don’t go looking for opportunities, they will come looking for you</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That was the parting, reassuring statement from my manager as I ended the 4 year assignment in Korea.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, things didn’t happen as he predicted. I had to look for and apply to opportunities since those words were spoken 20 years ago.</p>
<p>Experiences gained during those ensuing years have taught me these alternate interpretations.</p>
<ul>
<li>You have done something significant for you and the company, and we appreciate it.</li>
<li>You have skills that are well suited for this and similar roles.</li>
<li>Opportunities, is it defined by us, the company or by God?</li>
</ul>
<section id="opportunities-a-company-perspective" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="opportunities-a-company-perspective">Opportunities : A Company Perspective</h2>
<p>Early in my career, first 5 or 6 years, I was bound to my office.</p>
<p>Never attended a seminar, a conference or visited a manufacturing location outside of Utah.</p>
<p>Then in 1997, a colleague invited me to travel to Suzhou (苏州, 蘇州).</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230704 Seek Opportunity/suzhou1.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>We were to transfer a set of equipment that make catheters.</p>
<p>For the next 10 years, I would travel extensively.</p>
<p>Also the company asked me to live abroad and help with acquisition and transition of Korean Medical Device companies.</p>
<p>The arrangement was mutually beneficial.</p>
<p>I was providing a service that was in demand, a knowledge of local language and culture plus the knowledge of specific set of catheter manufacturing knowledge.</p>
<p>At some point, I made a mistake of thinking that companies exist to serve my needs.</p>
<p>It is the other way around.</p>
</section>
<section id="opportunities-a-life-long-persepective" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="opportunities-a-life-long-persepective">Opportunities : A life-long Persepective</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Was the manager incorrect in saying that opportunities will come?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Similar to company/individual relationship that can be defined as life’s opportunities, Rabbi Manis Friedman provides another perspective.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>We do not have needs, God does. and He has a plan.<br>
He will use us, rather, we will partner with God<br>
To achieve purposes of our creation</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230704 Seek Opportunity/temple.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Since the assertion by that manager, there has been a number of set-backs and disappointments, but were they actually opportunities?</p>
<ul>
<li>How should I view/accept my recent role, working with the Japanese team?</li>
<li>Was it to fulfill my needs or did I partner with God in any degree?</li>
<li>How many opportunities were lost, not even considered, because I was inward focused?</li>
</ul>
<p>The opportunity, as we define it in terms of our needs, may not come along.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230704 Seek Opportunity/kamakura.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>However, other forms or representations, that are in effect opportunities will be available.</p>
<p>These may start out as educational training, conference attendances, a reminder from a family member, a message from a friend, an invitation to join a team by a former colleague.</p>
<p>Therefore, by seeking the needs of God and understanding His plan, we can educate ourselves and make ourselves more suited for that role.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Can we just fast forward or skip to the next opportunities – Us</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Please give me a moment, let me check what we agreed to – God</p>
</blockquote>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>opportunities</category>
  <category>goodness of fit</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230704 Seek Opportunity/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230704 Seek Opportunity/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Canyons : Near and Far</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>I live close to a location with both a nondescript and a pedestrian name.</p>
<p>That aptly named place was accessible for nearly 40 years.</p>
<p>During those years, it was like a National Park hours away, for I visited it once a year or less.</p>
<p>I rediscovered it recently.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/flora2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>For most of those years, I was commuting to Salt Lake Valley - over a 30-mile commute.</p>
<p>A change in job to a Utah Valley location meant the commuting time spent in cars or trains/buses can be replaced by a number of activities.</p>
<p>I followed a suggestion on a website<sup>1</sup>.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>The canyon…draws thousands of people annually who seek recreation, renewal, and inspiration. It is one of the few remaining “URBAN FORESTS” in the United States</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A few times that I hiked the area, I was not impressed.</p>
<p>Aside from a few geological features, the trail was unremarkable.</p>
<p>I usually went after the sun had risen, during the summer months.</p>
<p>Afterwards, I concluded that an hour or two spent in the canyon or the forest was not worth it.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/flora1.jpeg" class="img-fluid"> Then I switched the hiking hours so that I could visit the area in the morning and still be at work</p>
<p>That meant an adjustment to the sleeping schedule.</p>
<p>The early morning hours highlighted peaks, fauna, and flora that I hadn’t noticed before.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/fauna.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>As I began to notice the small changes in the surroundings, I began to track and follow not only the sunrise and sunset information but also the moonrise and moonset data.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/moon.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>It was almost like being transported to a different location in a time capsule – and back invigorated.</p>
<p>Those trips offered visual and aural as well as tactile experiences</p>
<p>The time spent in that capsule filtered and cleared my thoughts.<br>
It allowed me to forget things I should not hold onto.<br>
Lightened my mind and my burden.</p>
<p>I have experienced some of the more established, crowd-inviting locations with more exotic offerings.</p>
<p>But it was very difficult to experience its unique offerings during the peak visiting hours with all the other guests.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/sun.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I have to agree with Mark, Mark Twain.</p>
<p>I didn’t realize I lived next door to a National Park named Rock Canyon.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>When I was a boy of fourteen, my father was so ignorant I could hardly stand to have the old man around. But when I got to be twenty-one, I was astonished at how much he had learned in seven years. – Mark Twain</p>
</blockquote>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://www.rockcanyonutah.com/↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>tales from RC</category>
  <category>renewal</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Father’s Day 2023</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230624 Fathers Day 2023/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>There are times, during the summer, when holidays seem to run together.<br>
Each year the meaning and purpose for the celebration seem less clear.</p>
<p>Father’s Day is one of those.</p>
<p>According to Wikipedia, Father’s Day<sup>1</sup> is</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>… a holiday honoring one’s father, or relevant father figure, as well as fatherhood, paternal bonds, and the influence of fathers in society.</p>
</blockquote>
<section id="a-physical-yearly-gift" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-physical-yearly-gift">A Physical, Yearly Gift</h2>
<p>At the entrance to the church meeting hall, there were beautifully wrapped 6” cookies for all the fathers.</p>
<p>There were several scores of cookies on display</p>
<p>The individual that made these used a lot ingredients and took a long time to bake these.</p>
<p>A store bought cookies would have sufficed but the effort was certainly appreciated.</p>
<p>Thank you Sister S., the RS President</p>
<p>Receiving gift always improves one’s outlook on life.</p>
<p>Then came the spiritual gift from Sister H.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230624 Fathers Day 2023/main.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="a-spiritual-gift" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-spiritual-gift">A Spiritual Gift</h2>
<p>She didn’t grow up with a father, since her parents divorced when she was 3.</p>
<p>Her mother remarried when Sister H was a teenager.</p>
<p>During those years, her father figure was her grandfather.</p>
<p>She described a time when her grandfather went to a function that would be attended by fathers and daughters.</p>
<p>She described her giving a talk about fathers as a blind person explaining an art work.</p>
<p>But she talked to a number of her friends, not just one or two, to gather a set of traits of fathers.</p>
<p>Those traits that are manifested in our earthly father but those also reflects our celestial heritage.</p>
<p>Fathers,</p>
<ul>
<li><p>are to provide, including safety.</p></li>
<li><p>are there, their presence is important</p></li>
<li><p>are examples of long-suffering and are patient</p></li>
<li><p>have a perfect love for the children</p></li>
<li><p>teaches about the divine nature</p></li>
<li><p>don’t judge</p></li>
<li><p>just love those around him</p></li>
<li><p>don’t talk about Jesus, but be like Jesus</p></li>
</ul>
<p>Listening to these traits, I recognized that I have failed to grasp many of these, especially the last one about <code>…be like Jesus</code></p>
<p>However, my father in his own way and throughout 6 decades, exemplified many if not all of these traits.</p>
<p>Thank you dad.</p>
</section>
<section id="a-generational-gift" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-generational-gift">A Generational Gift</h2>
<p>Back in the mid 1980s, Brother L. gave a talk as part of a ward Christmas devotional, at Carrollton, Maryland.</p>
<p>I was a newly returned missionary at the time, home from school.</p>
<p>My world view consisted of information filtered through TV news, radio broadcasts, and the Washington Post. And what we discussed and lived as an immigrant family.</p>
<p>My father was in his 50s.</p>
<p>I didn’t fully understand nor appreciate the impact of what Brother L. was saying.</p>
<p>Brother L. had far greater access to information and trends as a University Professor.</p>
<p>I don’t recall all of the supporting evidence he presented but he mentioned,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Fathers are an endangered group in the United States of America.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230624 Fathers Day 2023/dad.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="a-steady-foundation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-steady-foundation">A Steady Foundation</h2>
<p>Since then I have reflected on his observations.</p>
<p>I have a far greater appreciation for his message.<br>
And for my own father.</p>
<p>He espoused and demonstrated the role and the traits of the father .</p>
<p>For many years my father worked in a hazardous environment.<br>
But I don’t recall him complaining or wishing that he had a different role.<br>
I think he was happy to provide for the family.<br>
At the same time wishing that we realized a better living condition for ourselves and our children.</p>
<p>Thank you Sisters S and H for the cookies and the Father’s Day message.<br>
Thank you Brother L. for planting a thought that kept me thinking all these years.</p>
<p>Thank you Dad for providing all the earthly goods and means for our success.</p>
<p>For demonstrating Father’s traits and emulating the One.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230624 Fathers Day 2023/mom.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Events, gestures, and a remembrance made me realize that remembering our fathers, relevant father figures, paternal bonds, and fatherhood is still important and should be celebrated more often.</p>
<p>It is a society’s way of remembering and celebrating ones that nurtured and guided us, by setting aside a special day.</p>
<p>However, whenever we pause and remember them and renew our dedication for this life, we are celebrating and remembering our mothers and fathers.</p>
<p>Looking forward to the coming days and to next year’s celebration of both Mother’s Day, Father’s Day and all the other summer holidays.</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Father%27s_Day↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>appreciation</category>
  <category>remebrance</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230624 Fathers Day 2023/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230624 Fathers Day 2023/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Anti Social Beginning</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>We wanted a Japanese person for the role<br>
We would have accepted an American project leader<br>
But a Korean person that doesn’t drink!?!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Thus began my 6 year assignment to coordinate a production line transfer from Fukuroi(袋井市), Japan to Utah and Texas.</p>
<p>Wondered,</p>
<p>What happened to the description of Japanese people that I had studied prior to the visit.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Japanese people are polite, shy, kind and most of the time indirect in communications.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This was not the beginning I had imagined.</p>
<p>After an 12 hour flight to Narita(成田市), we were on our way to Tokyo via Narita Express (NEX).</p>
<p>With that declaration, he single-handedly shook my confidence, as well as stirred national differences that I had not considered.</p>
<p>[For this role, I had been interviewed by a Director of R&amp;D, the VP of R&amp;D, and the President of Technology. They agreed that I could do this. I wanted this role, and believed that this was an opportunity that my previous manager predicted.]</p>
<p>Thought of going back home, crossed my mind, if there was a convenient way and if my Director and the VP hadn’t accompanied me</p>
<p>However, relying on past human relationship lessons<sup>1</sup>, I patiently listened to <code>H san</code>’s lecture on Japanese business practices for foreigners…</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Japan as a nation is a tight group. One mistake and you are branded.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I was glad that the ride was less than an hour.</p>
<section id="start-of-the-project" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="start-of-the-project">Start of the Project</h2>
<p>Next morning, <code>H san</code> looked and acted differently than the night before. Calm, with far less words.</p>
<p>I was to meet with the team I was to work with. I wasn’t as concerned about the technical aspect of the transfer. Since I had worked in the industry over 15 years.</p>
<p>I had been chosen for the role, because I knew the Asian culture, not because of the language skills, unlike my role in Korea. However, the remaining concern of the project, communicating with my counterpart, vanished when I met <code>K san</code>.</p>
<p>We had exchanged emails prior to the visit, so I knew her written English skills rivaled natives. It turns out, she had graduated from University of Warwick and had studied British Humor.</p>
<p>I was home free – almost.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/fuji2.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="a-social-lubricant" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-social-lubricant">A Social Lubricant</h2>
<p>I had left Korea before I became a teenager.</p>
<p>I returned 25 years later.<br>
Many things had changed. But not the pervasive use of alcohol.</p>
<p>One manager described alcohol as a social lubricant.<br>
Personal experience told me otherwise, it was neither social nor a lubricant.</p>
<p>It may seem to relax people that drink. However, I also saw individuals acting in a way that they would regret later.</p>
<p>If people asked why I didn’t drink, I gave religion as the initial answer. However, if they pressed on with the inquiry – there were additional responses.</p>
<p>There was one more reason – a family one.</p>
<p>I saw how alcohol wrecked lives of my relatives.</p>
<p>They seemed to be mild, coherent person, prior to alcohol consumption. Afterwards, it seemed a darker part of humanity took over.</p>
<p>It seemed they become more bold as restraints were removed. The alcohol laced relatives were not the people I wanted to be social with.</p>
<p>I was able to spend 4 years in Korea and another 6 years of business dealings with a Japanese firm where alcohol was offered and consumed.</p>
<p>I am glad I didn’t participate.</p>
<p>[2 years into the role, a colleague from Texas joined the project. He indicated he drank. Japanese hosts unloaded on him. He could not make it to his hotel without an incident.]</p>
<p>Grateful for the religion and the support around me that encouraged and enforced a life long decision of not drinking alcohol. Also life’s experiences that allowed a choice to pause and react appropriately to <code>H San</code>’s disappointment and the ensuing lecture.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/me.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="memories-of-visits-to-japan" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="memories-of-visits-to-japan">Memories of Visits to Japan</h2>
<p>By suppressing my initial response and overcoming jitters of the first evening in Japan, now I can recall those 6 years of working with the Japanese team.</p>
<p>We would visit Japan several times a year. <code>H San</code> continued to come to Narita to meet us and guide us through Tokyo Station. After 3rd or 4th visit, he would let us find our way to the Marunouchi (丸の内) Hotel ourselves.</p>
<p>Recall fondly his favorite restaurants in Roppongi(六本木) in Tokyo, run by his classmate, and Shabu Shabu place in Hamamatsu (浜松市).</p>
<p>These visits taught me, among others</p>
<ul>
<li>the importance of making the guest/customer welcomed and feel at ease.</li>
<li>know the target for the product and process, work at it and achieve it.<sup>2</sup></li>
<li>invest in and take part in the local food and culture</li>
</ul>
<p>Wondered whether I would have had these opportunities, and completed them, if I hadn’t had religion or had adopted alcohol drinking as a social norm.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/card1.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/card2.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>These days, <code>H san</code> and I exchange emails regularly. He also sends me, lovely, end of the year greeting cards</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>by this time, I had worked in the industry in various roles in US and abroad. Had witnessed several incidences where those that kept their composure was the de facto winner, no matter the outcome↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>the Japanese and the American had a very different view on the length and scope of the training↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>opportunities</category>
  <category>friendships</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Recordings that Reflects : Analog</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230606 Analog Recordings/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>One of the benefits of aging is the reserve of memory or remembrance.</p>
<p>Of times, places, and people.</p>
<p>Equally challenging is the effort required to keep up with and be current with the latest technology offerings that aides in that remembering.</p>
<div class="quarto-layout-panel">
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230606 Analog Recordings/bb1.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230606 Analog Recordings/bb2.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230606 Analog Recordings/bb3.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230606 Analog Recordings/bb4.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Spent better part of last weekend transferring analog video images from over 30 years ago.</p>
<p>Viewed, edited and converted Video 8, Hi 8 and Digital 8 images using a Sony Video Camera<sup>1</sup>, a FireWire<sup>2</sup> cable, a Mac Mini that included iMovie from a dozen years ago.</p>
<p>(See Section&nbsp;7 for additional technical discussions.)</p>
<p>This was a technology equivalent of astronomical or stars aligning.</p>
<section id="first-attempt" class="level2" data-number="1">
<h2 data-number="1" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="first-attempt"><span class="header-section-number">1</span> First Attempt</h2>
<p>Initially, made the mistake of trying to enhance the footage by inserting a period music in the sound portion of the video.</p>
<p>It overshadowed the embedded, original audio. That audio was the element that listeners and viewers were interested in.</p>
<p>The benefit of the video, compared to still image, is the sound and the presence associated with the person.</p>
<p>Afterwards, the video was faithfully transferred without any modification or enhancements.</p>
</section>
<section id="initial-impressions" class="level2" data-number="2">
<h2 data-number="2" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="initial-impressions"><span class="header-section-number">2</span> Initial Impressions</h2>
<p>The finished product sounded and looked dated.</p>
<p>There is only so much that can be done with 200 lines of resolution and mono sound recording.</p>
<p>The intended audience was my father-in-laws’ descendants. He had 5 children and 15 grand children. (He passed away in 2008)</p>
<p>I didn’t expect much response or feedback, since it was meant for the immediate family of Hong Han Pyo and Whang Young Ja.</p>
<p>I was surprised to hear that many people were interested in viewing this footage.</p>
<p>Turns out my father-in-law had 10 siblings and his father’s brother had 7 children.</p>
<p>The response was overwhelmingly favorable.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230606 Analog Recordings/sp.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="the-reason-for-the-popularity3" class="level2" data-number="3">
<h2 data-number="3" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-reason-for-the-popularity3"><span class="header-section-number">3</span> The reason for the popularity<sup>3</sup></h2>
<p>Video contains ordinary, everyday events like family gathering, eating together, visits during holidays</p>
<p>However, hearing their familiar voices, tinged with local accent, is irreplaceable.</p>
<p>For it also contains images of members of the family that are no longer with us.</p>
<p>Ultimately, it is not necessarily the resolution presented on the screen or the sound quality produced by the speaker that matters.</p>
<p>It is memories that are triggered and the relationship we remember, when we see the electronic representation of them.</p>
<p>A remembrance of times and places that were slower and quieter.</p>
</section>
<section id="consumer-vs.-producer" class="level2" data-number="4">
<h2 data-number="4" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="consumer-vs.-producer"><span class="header-section-number">4</span> Consumer vs.&nbsp;Producer</h2>
<p>My father declared in his 50s</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I am satisfied with what I have learned and remembered.<br>
No longer need the latest offerings or trends.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>His memory was nearly full – with analog recordings.<sup>4</sup></p>
<p>There were times, during my 20s and 30s, when I paid attention to the advertisements for the latest offerings and compared my equipment against it.</p>
<p>Wondered how much better things would sound or more pleasing to the eye.</p>
<p>Recently, I have changed my thinking.</p>
<p>No longer looking for the latest and greatest.</p>
<p>Instead, I am more interested in identifying the lowest requirements that meet my needs.<br>
Rather than owning items that are brighter, clearer, or louder than my neighbors.</p>
</section>
<section id="reflection-of-life" class="level2" data-number="5">
<h2 data-number="5" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="reflection-of-life"><span class="header-section-number">5</span> Reflection of Life</h2>
<p>Grateful that I can still hear (without hearing aides) the sound coming from mechanical vibration that is a transformation of electrical signal.</p>
<p>Also that I can still see (with corrective lens) and recognize images of loved ones from the past, when they were at their prime.</p>
<p>Grateful that those images and sound triggers longing for a home that no longer exist but one that can be built with loved ones.</p>
<p>The societies and companies will continue to move toward higher resolution and noiseless offerings that I can no longer distinguish and hear.</p>
<p>I will continue to invest in and enjoy the original recording without enhancements. For those recordings represent life – the one that I am familiar with.</p>
<p>[At times mistakes are made but we have the capacity and means to either accept the flaws or modify them as needed.]</p>
<p>I am looking forward to a time when digital things will be converted back to analog format, even with its shortcomings.<sup>5</sup></p>
<p>Meanwhile,I will continue to work on the project of analog conversion, 12 tapes down and 70 more to go.</p>
</section>
<section id="further-reflections" class="level2" data-number="6">
<h2 data-number="6" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="further-reflections"><span class="header-section-number">6</span> Further Reflections</h2>
<ul>
<li><p>It’s a wonder how people understand what I say. It is difficult to fully hear the sound. The communication is more than sound or just voice.</p></li>
<li><p>Viewing those videos and knowing what happened afterwards has been instructive. We live this life serially, with faith and reflect with a much better sense of meaning. Recall a quote, <code>if we knew beforehand what would happen, we would die due to too much happiness (or sadness)</code></p></li>
<li><p>Many of the people in the videos were same age as my current age. I thought they were too old. They continue to live a productive life, 30 years later. And the young ones in the video are now starting their own family. The cycle continues.</p></li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="sec-technical" class="level2" data-number="7">
<h2 data-number="7" class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sec-technical"><span class="header-section-number">7</span> Technical Discussion</h2>
<p>This project took nearly a decade to complete</p>
<p>It is not because I didn’t have the desire or the knowledge.</p>
<p>Even though I had the desire, the hardware and software complexity along with its availability due to its age, made it challenging. For example , I was not looking forward to using 2 dongles to go from the Firewire to Thunderbolt 2 (MDP, Mini Display Port) to Thunderbolt 3 (USB-C).</p>
<p>A breakthrough was finding a Mac Mini (circa 2010) that had the right connection. See the table below</p>
<p>So the connection from the Sony Camera was just one cable. Plus the built in software was adequate for the transfer as well processing and conversion</p>
<p>My earlier efforts to digitize was minimally successful. It was a haphazard effort and I got frustrated and gave up when I ran into issues. But this time, I had the tools plus the combined knowledge base of YouTube with me.</p>
<p>Therefore I was able to overcome technical hurdles such as choosing the right firewire cable, sourcing the right software and hardware to process the DV files into MP4 files.</p>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">

<div id="fahezistvl" style="padding-left:0px;padding-right:0px;padding-top:10px;padding-bottom:10px;overflow-x:auto;overflow-y:auto;width:auto;height:auto;">
<style>html {
  font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Helvetica Neue', 'Fira Sans', 'Droid Sans', Arial, sans-serif;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_table {
  display: table;
  border-collapse: collapse;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  color: #333333;
  font-size: 16px;
  font-weight: normal;
  font-style: normal;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  width: auto;
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-width: 2px;
  border-top-color: #A8A8A8;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 2px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #A8A8A8;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 2px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_heading {
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  text-align: center;
  border-bottom-color: #FFFFFF;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 1px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 1px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_caption {
  padding-top: 4px;
  padding-bottom: 4px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_title {
  color: #333333;
  font-size: 125%;
  font-weight: initial;
  padding-top: 4px;
  padding-bottom: 4px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  border-bottom-color: #FFFFFF;
  border-bottom-width: 0;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_subtitle {
  color: #333333;
  font-size: 85%;
  font-weight: initial;
  padding-top: 0;
  padding-bottom: 6px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  border-top-color: #FFFFFF;
  border-top-width: 0;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_bottom_border {
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_col_headings {
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-width: 2px;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 1px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 1px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_col_heading {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  font-size: 100%;
  font-weight: normal;
  text-transform: inherit;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 1px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 1px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
  vertical-align: bottom;
  padding-top: 5px;
  padding-bottom: 6px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  overflow-x: hidden;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_column_spanner_outer {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  font-size: 100%;
  font-weight: normal;
  text-transform: inherit;
  padding-top: 0;
  padding-bottom: 0;
  padding-left: 4px;
  padding-right: 4px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_column_spanner_outer:first-child {
  padding-left: 0;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_column_spanner_outer:last-child {
  padding-right: 0;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_column_spanner {
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
  vertical-align: bottom;
  padding-top: 5px;
  padding-bottom: 5px;
  overflow-x: hidden;
  display: inline-block;
  width: 100%;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_group_heading {
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  font-size: 100%;
  font-weight: initial;
  text-transform: inherit;
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-width: 2px;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 1px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 1px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
  vertical-align: middle;
  text-align: left;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_empty_group_heading {
  padding: 0.5px;
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  font-size: 100%;
  font-weight: initial;
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-width: 2px;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
  vertical-align: middle;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_from_md > :first-child {
  margin-top: 0;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_from_md > :last-child {
  margin-bottom: 0;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_row {
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  margin: 10px;
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-width: 1px;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 1px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 1px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
  vertical-align: middle;
  overflow-x: hidden;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_stub {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  font-size: 100%;
  font-weight: initial;
  text-transform: inherit;
  border-right-style: solid;
  border-right-width: 2px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_stub_row_group {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  font-size: 100%;
  font-weight: initial;
  text-transform: inherit;
  border-right-style: solid;
  border-right-width: 2px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  vertical-align: top;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_row_group_first td {
  border-top-width: 2px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_summary_row {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  text-transform: inherit;
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_first_summary_row {
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_first_summary_row.thick {
  border-top-width: 2px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_last_summary_row {
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_grand_summary_row {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  text-transform: inherit;
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_first_grand_summary_row {
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  border-top-style: double;
  border-top-width: 6px;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_striped {
  background-color: rgba(128, 128, 128, 0.05);
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_table_body {
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-width: 2px;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_footnotes {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  border-bottom-style: none;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 2px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 2px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_footnote {
  margin: 0px;
  font-size: 90%;
  padding-left: 4px;
  padding-right: 4px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_sourcenotes {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  border-bottom-style: none;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 2px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 2px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_sourcenote {
  font-size: 90%;
  padding-top: 4px;
  padding-bottom: 4px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_left {
  text-align: left;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_center {
  text-align: center;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_right {
  text-align: right;
  font-variant-numeric: tabular-nums;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_font_normal {
  font-weight: normal;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_font_bold {
  font-weight: bold;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_font_italic {
  font-style: italic;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_super {
  font-size: 65%;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_footnote_marks {
  font-style: italic;
  font-weight: normal;
  font-size: 75%;
  vertical-align: 0.4em;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_asterisk {
  font-size: 100%;
  vertical-align: 0;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_indent_1 {
  text-indent: 5px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_indent_2 {
  text-indent: 10px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_indent_3 {
  text-indent: 15px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_indent_4 {
  text-indent: 20px;
}

:where(#fahezistvl) .gt_indent_5 {
  text-indent: 25px;
}
</style>
<table class="gt_table">
  
  <thead class="gt_col_headings">
    <tr>
      <th class="gt_col_heading gt_columns_bottom_border gt_left" rowspan="1" colspan="1" scope="col" id="Hardware - Software">Hardware - Software</th>
      <th class="gt_col_heading gt_columns_bottom_border gt_left" rowspan="1" colspan="1" scope="col" id="Model No.">Model No.</th>
      <th class="gt_col_heading gt_columns_bottom_border gt_left" rowspan="1" colspan="1" scope="col" id="Function">Function</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody class="gt_table_body">
    <tr><td headers="Hardware - Software" class="gt_row gt_left">Sony</td>
<td headers="Model No." class="gt_row gt_left">DCR-TRV 520</td>
<td headers="Function" class="gt_row gt_left">Render data stored in magnetic tape.  
Provide output at the iLink Port</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Hardware - Software" class="gt_row gt_left">FireWire</td>
<td headers="Model No." class="gt_row gt_left">4-Pin to 6-Pin Cable</td>
<td headers="Function" class="gt_row gt_left">carry digital data from the camera at 300 Mb/s per IEEE 1394a Standard</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Hardware - Software" class="gt_row gt_left">Mac Mini &amp; iMovie</td>
<td headers="Model No." class="gt_row gt_left">2011 with Snow Leopard, iMovie '09</td>
<td headers="Function" class="gt_row gt_left">Create a digital copy (*.dv)
Create a Project in iMovie using (*.dv) files
Convert the project data to MP4 (M4V) format</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Hardware - Software" class="gt_row gt_left">Cloud hosting and sharing service</td>
<td headers="Model No." class="gt_row gt_left">Google Photo</td>
<td headers="Function" class="gt_row gt_left">Store video files and provide links</td></tr>
  </tbody>
  
  
</table>
</div>
</div>
</div>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Handycam?oldformat=true↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>https://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=IEEE_1394&amp;oldformat=true↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>Consumer video recording was not widely adopted in early 1990s, especially in Korea.↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn4"><p>he left reels of recording and a reel-to-reel recorder that he purchased in Hong Kong back in 60s↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn5"><p>2 main reasons are low resolution and real time conversion, 2 hour tape takes 2 hours to copy to the digital domain↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>technology</category>
  <category>rememberance</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230606 Analog Recordings/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230606 Analog Recordings/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A United Nation under God</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230530 Reunite/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>My mother was an avid consumer of all things from and about Korea - that included Korean Popular Entertainment. I believe that eased her longing for both Koreas, North and South.</p>
<p>She would watch the daily KBS News, and also keep up to date on popular celebrities, (연예인, 탤런트) or singers.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230530 Reunite/main.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I remember, growing up, she would rent a dozen or so VHS tapes to view her favorite series, 연속극(連續劇)</p>
<p>Although I watched few episodes of Jewel in the Palace (대장금/大長今) and Moon Embracing the Sun (해를 품은 달) I resisted her invitation to watch those programs with her since it took a considerable time and commitment.</p>
<p>And I also knew they were well written and acted and their period customs were both accurate and well made.</p>
<p>So I avoided watching them, knowing how addictive they were.</p>
<p>My standard reply was,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I am already involved in a real life Korean-drama in this family.</p>
<p>Why do I want to watch another on TV?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>She knew more about the Korean entertainment scene than most people one-half or one-forth her age.</p>
<p>And her enthusiasm for the Korean Wave preceded the general public by a decade or two</p>
<p>However, when she moved to Utah in her late 70s, she lost her network of friends who kept her updated and who used to share those DVDs and VHSs and her access to her familiar or go-to Korean TV channels and programs, available via the Dish TV.</p>
<p>She never got adjusted to internet-based programming.</p>
<p>My son got her the Google TV and that helped her with YouTube and other offerings.</p>
<p>Then she and I began hearing about a drama from friends in far away places and subsequently read up on a world-wide phenomenon, known as CLoY, Crash Landing on You (사랑의 불시착).</p>
<p>Before I knew about the story line, my wife informed me that the leading character was someone she liked based on <code>Secret Garden</code> series</p>
<p>I knew Ms.&nbsp;Son from the movie, <code>Classics</code>.</p>
<p>The story line, set in today’s Korea dealt with defectors crossing DMZ back and forth - a dream for those from the North.</p>
<p>This sounded like a must-see Korean Drama.</p>
<hr>
<p>So my mom and I started watching the series together.</p>
<p>Fell immediately for the characters, especially those depicting villagers in North Korea and Korean People’s Army (조선인민군), in addition to leading characters.</p>
<p>For those supporting cast members spoke just like my mom and dad, my uncles and aunts, with the Northern Accent.</p>
<p>My extended family, when they gather, they subconsciously let go of decades-long practice of using the Southern Accent.</p>
<p>Endearing me further was the scene and practices of a life in North Korea, that was closer to the Korea I grew up in the 60s and 70s.</p>
<p>The black market scene brought back memories of those days when everything seemed to be in short supply and beyond the affordability of most people.</p>
<p>Whenever I go back to Korea, I am taken back by the growth and affluence.</p>
<p>Most of the time, I feel like I am from a developing country.</p>
<p>Everyone seems to be a well dressed model and have jumped out of magazines or they can readily jump into a Korean Drama or a number of “Korea’s Got Talent” like shows.</p>
<p>It was a rare treat to see North Koreans depicted with care and accuracy that made me feel that there were distant cousins and other family members that I may meet in the future.</p>
<p>And that there may be a few areas in common that we can begin the conversation.</p>
<p>My mom and I finished the series in a matter of days, often viewing 2 to 3 episodes at a time.</p>
<p>For a brief time, the series took us to another place and time and brought us a hope for possible unification and a chance to unite as a family.</p>
<hr>
<p>That was two years ago.</p>
<p>Now that my parents have departed this life, there is little to no prospect of uniting with my parents’ family in North Korea.</p>
<p>Even if the boundaries were opened tomorrow and we could travel to the hometown or ancestral homes of my parents, would the Kang/Hwang family still be there?</p>
<p>By miracle that we were able to locate the family, how would we begin the conversation?</p>
<ul>
<li>How do you make up for 73 years of no communications?</li>
<li>Are there any areas of common understanding?</li>
<li>How would writers of Korean Dramas write the script for this kind of reunion?</li>
</ul>
<p>I have an uncle, my dad’s youngest brother, in his 80s.</p>
<p>He is the last link, on the Kang side, with North Korea.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230530 Reunite/refugees.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">My uncle is in the foreground, in his early teenage years, middle school perhaps</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>On my mother’s side, there are 3 surviving younger sisters in South Korea.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230530 Reunite/sisters.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Hwang Sisters, late 1960s</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>My mother has one more sister in North Korea, she is 1.5 years younger than my mother.</p>
<p>She may still be alive, but there has been no confirmation of her whereabouts for nearly 75 years.</p>
<hr>
<p><code>Crash Landing on You</code> romanticized the 2 sides of a nation still at war.</p>
<p>Providing a momentary glimpse and a hope that the separated family may once again be united.</p>
<p>With each passing year, the generation that experienced the Korean War is dwindling.</p>
<p>Those that experienced the lasting effect of war, poverty, death and separation of family are aging quickly.</p>
<p>I do not know if unification will ever take place in the peninsula of Korea.</p>
<p>Even if it did, I don’t how the families will be reunited and reacquainted.</p>
<p>Even for the writers of CLoY, it would be a challenge to write scripts for these improbable re-unions</p>
<p>Although it is highly unlikely, I will pray for divine intervention to take place in my lifetime.</p>
<p>For, If any nation or people can pull this off, it is the people of Korea, both North and South.</p>
<p>They have demonstrated their hard work, post Korean War.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230530 Reunite/church1958.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">A Protestant church my mom attended, 1958</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>They created and experienced the economic miracles that started during the 70s and 80s.</p>
<p>Now we need a spiritual miracle, a return to god.</p>
<p>The God of Abraham, Isaac and Jacob, who was renamed Israel<sup>1</sup>. <a href="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/manual/gospel-principles/chapter-42-the-gathering-of-the-house-of-israel?lang=eng">link</a></p>
<p><em>God Almighty, through thy servants, thou hast revealed the truth to the people of Korea, a little by little.</em></p>
<p><em>Thou hast also rescued and preserved this country, called Korea, numerous times.</em></p>
<p><em>Will thou hasten the restoration of that nation once more, as one, under God.</em></p>
<p><em>That we may once again call one another brothers and sisters, which we are.</em></p>
<p><em>Wilt thou move the hearts and minds of leaders of 2 Koreas and those nations that have controlling interest in Korea.</em></p>
<p><em>Pray that the unification can take place in my lifetime.</em></p>
<p><em>If it is not thy will currently, will thou reveal steps, send dedicated people, and name sacrifices necessary for the unification to occur in my lifetime or in my children’s lifetime.</em></p>
<p>Pleading on behalf of my parents’ generation and also for the rising generation.</p>
<p>Gratefully,</p>
<p>A son of North Korean Parents May 2023</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Because Jacob was faithful, the Lord gave him the special name of Israel, which means “<strong>one who prevails with God” or ”let God prevail”</strong> (Bible Dictionary,”Israel,” 708). Jacob had twelve sons. These sons and their families became known as the twelve tribes of Israel, or Israelites (see Genesis 49:28)↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>longing</category>
  <category>unification</category>
  <category>dreams</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230530 Reunite/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230530 Reunite/intro.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Live Like a Refugee</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230529 A Refugee/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>During my high school years Tom Petty and the Heartbreakers had a hit song called <code>Refugee</code>.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Somewhere, somehow, somebody must have kicked you around some…<br>
Honey, it don’t really matter to me, baby<br>
Everybody’s had to fight to be free…<br>
You don’t have to live like a refugee.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Some of my high school friends used to tease me.<br>
Saying,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Why do you have to live like a refugee.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I thought it didn’t bother me,</p>
<p>But I obviously remembered it, so it must have had its intended impact and affected my psyche – after all these years.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230529 A Refugee/main.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The simple answer is that I lived like a refugee, because for all intents and purposes, our family was an economic or opportunity seeking refugees from South Korea that moved to America.</p>
<p>Officially, our family came to the United States on an Employment-Based Immigrant Visa<sup>1</sup></p>
<p>In some sense, we can be further categorized as economic, political or war time refugees from North Korea.</p>
<p>Since my parents move out of North Korea.</p>
<p>My father’s family moved to South Korea for better opportunities.</p>
<p>My mother’s family escaped North Korea after enduring communist take over of once promising agricultural and commercial ownership</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230529 A Refugee/marriage.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Incheon, 1958</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>However the response may include contemplation of the following,</p>
<ul>
<li>From what were we running away.</li>
<li>To what were we running to.</li>
<li>What was our refuge?</li>
<li>Where was that refuge?</li>
<li>Are we still running?</li>
</ul>
<p>Based on those review questions, as my High School friends correctly observed, I have lived like a refugee, currently live a refugee-like life.</p>
<p>I will probably live in the future as one.</p>
<p>Until I find contentment, or that place or time that I have been seeking</p>
<p>[Or continue to run away from and to live separately].</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Is it possible to achieve refugee-free life - in this life.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Immigrants, refugees, and asylum seekers are all seeking the same – peace based on acquisition of place, wealth, and relationships.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230529 A Refugee/remembrance.jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Note, my mom’s actual birth year is 1932, records were altered after the War</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>When life presents its many challenges and questions, my parents’ life provide a hint, a glimpse, a path.</p>
<p>They saved, worked, and believed like they were constantly building a new and better life.</p>
<p>We always had life’s essentials, even when we lived in a small apartment. Rice, water, soy sauce and emergency provisions</p>
<p>Their life was centered around work. They didn’t stop until last few years of their lives.</p>
<p>They were fiercely independent in thoughts or ideals.</p>
<p>A discussion on relative merits of different forms of government was a non-starter.</p>
<p>For them there was only one, the one that guarantees the opportunity or freedom of and for its people.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230529 A Refugee/june.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I never fully understood their way of living nor was I, at times, proud to be part of the family.</p>
<p>There is no doubt in my mind, they did their best to give us a safe, god-fearing, kind to others life.</p>
<p>They give me strength and hope that I will ultimately arrive at the refuge that I have been seeking.</p>
<p>Mom and Dad, thank you.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Are we still running?</p>
</blockquote>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230529 A Refugee/future.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Gimpo Airport, 1966?</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://travel.state.gov/content/travel/en/us-visas/immigrate/employment-based-immigrant-visas.html↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>seeking</category>
  <category>dreams</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230529 A Refugee/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230529 A Refugee/orem_temple.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gathered to his Fathers</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230528 Memorial Day/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Like many immigrants before him, he was not gathered to his fathers physically, when he passed away 3 years ago.</p>
<p>It is longing of nearly all people, to buried like Biblical Patriarchs.<sup>1</sup></p>
<p>But he was gathered to the place and to the people he associated with and cherished for most of his adult life.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230528 Memorial Day/main.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>My father lived first 44 years of his life in Korea. Then he spent the next 46 years in America</p>
<p>For the vast majority of his adult life he had contact with the American people and their institutions, its values and economic system and the ideal of freedom.</p>
<p>His maternal uncle sought him and and the family, often walking along the 120 mile journey from Seoul to their home in Hamkyung do.</p>
<p>He made it to Southern Korea before the War.</p>
<p>He most likely would have perished in the Korean War had he fought on the North Korean side.</p>
<p>His fate altered, he was a trained army personnel fighting alongside United Nations forces, and its chief sponsor, the United States of America</p>
<p>Like many young, poor people of his generation, some of the tenets of Communism appealed to him.</p>
<p>An abolition of class through revolution and the promise</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>to abolish private ownership of the means of production, advocating for collective ownership and control</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230528 Memorial Day/dad.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>However when he witnessed the outcome of socialism or communism his mind was changed</p>
<p>He fought North Koreans in battles and saw their dead and how utterly ill-prepared they were for the fight.</p>
<p>He was furious that the young people were dying to prove some theories that they neither understood nor would have supported if given a choice.</p>
<p>He became, in essence, a born-again anti-communist, a supporter of freedom from tyranny of communism</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230528 Memorial Day/crane.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>After the war, he secured a job with the remaining American forces, a 미군부대, 美軍部隊.</p>
<p>Learning a skill that would serve him well.</p>
<p>He would go on to work in and in Vietnam, where he was able to understand better the traits of American people.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230528 Memorial Day/chevy.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>He returned home in 1970 but he didn’t stay very long. He moved to Maryland, on April, 1974</p>
<p>During those 4 years in Korea, he met missionaries, invited them home and my family was baptized in May of 1971</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230528 Memorial Day/letter.JPG" class="img-fluid"> He died the morning of Tuesday, a week before Memorial Day.</p>
<p>The cemetery said, the weekend burial would be nearly impossible due to the expected Memorial Day crowd.</p>
<p>Then they suggested a remote possibility of a Friday graveside service.</p>
<p>He was interned on Friday, May 22nd.</p>
<p>Next day, the whole cemetery was filled with flags and flowers.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230528 Memorial Day/cemetery.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>For a patriotic soldier, it was a loving welcome from the adopted country.</p>
<p>And a fitting goodbye for an immigrant family, originally from a small village in Northern Korea.</p>
<p>Someday, when the man-made and man-upheld boundaries are no longer, I hope to seek out records of fathers and mothers of past generations and their descendants and have another memorial service on behalf of my parents in North Korea.</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://bible.knowing-jesus.com/Genesis/49/29↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>ancestors</category>
  <category>dreams</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230528 Memorial Day/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230528 Memorial Day/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Decades of Travels</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230522 passport travel/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Received a new passport, issued by the United States Department of State.</p>
<p>It took twice as long to renew, about 10 weeks, roughly a monthly apartment rent, when I was a newly-wed back in the 1990s.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230522 passport travel/flower.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="first-passport-jul-1990---jul-2000" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="first-passport-jul-1990---jul-2000">First Passport : Jul 1990 - Jul 2000</h2>
<p>Hardly used the first.</p>
<p>From 1974 till 1990, I never traveled outside of the United States.</p>
<p>Then after marrying June, we went to Korea to report our marriage to June’s family. Her family traces her lineage back for nearly thousand years and they are majority owner in a village next to 현충사(顯忠祠)<sup>1</sup></p>
<p>However, my side of the family, because most family members still live in North Korea, we can count on 2 hands, those that are directly related to us.</p>
<p>We had a wonderful month long visit to June’s hometown and her ancestral home.</p>
<p>I remember sleeping the main bedroom when we visited their old home. They graciously let us sleep in the most comfortable room and they slept in the guest room. I can still recall hearing the cicadas buzzing sound as we slept.</p>
<p>In addition, my family came to Korea to celebrate my dad’s 60th Birthday and my grandmother’s 80th Birthday.</p>
<p>Seeing all my families together, some I hadn’t seen in nearly 20 years, made me feel more homesick and I resolved that I would find a way to visit more often.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230522 passport travel/1990_family.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>But my desires for international travel didn’t materialize for a long time.</p>
<p>Then it happened.</p>
<p>In 1997, a trip to Suzhou, China was arranged.</p>
<p>It was a trip to plan an equipment transfer from Sandy, Utah to Suzhou, China plant. This was the beginning and it opened many more opportunities.</p>
<p>The company was expanding into Asia and I met people who travel to overseas, assess potential business acquisition and formulate strategies to integrate those company.</p>
<p>I wanted to be part of it.</p>
<p>Then a year later, a VP of World Wide Manufacturing calls me into his office.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Would you interested in moving to Korea with your family and work on integrating Korean manufacturers into the world wide group?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I could have given my answer right then.</p>
<p>He suggested June and I traveled to Korea and see if this is something I wanted to do.</p>
<p>Then to bolster my confidence, he said as I left his office.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>You are probably the only person on this earth capable of handling this role.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Starting in the fall of 1998, I was using the passport on a monthly basis. Sometimes weekly, since the Asian Pacific HQ was in Singapore.</p>
<p>By May of 2000, 2 months prior to expiration date, I ran out of pages on the passport.</p>
</section>
<section id="nd-passport---may-2000---may-2010" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="nd-passport---may-2000---may-2010">2nd Passport - May 2000 - May 2010</h2>
<p>Went to the United States Embassy in Seoul to renew the passport.</p>
<p>I was treated like a VIP and the passport was issued to me within hours.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230522 passport travel/passport2.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>This time the booklet was much thicker, anticipating more work related travels to China, HK, Singapore, Japan, and even Europe.</p>
</section>
<section id="rd-passport---jun-2012---june-2022" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="rd-passport---jun-2012---june-2022">3rd Passport - Jun 2012 - June 2022</h2>
<p>For nearly 5 years, from 2007 to 2012, there were no overseas travel.</p>
<p>However, to be ready, just in case, the passport was renewed.</p>
<p>Then a new role with a new company, I would travel to Japan several times a year.</p>
<p>This was not expected outcome but welcomed.</p>
<p>Appreciated and cherished the opportunity to travel to Asia again.</p>
</section>
<section id="renewed-appreciation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="renewed-appreciation">Renewed Appreciation</h2>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230522 passport travel/passport1.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Upon receiving the new passport, looked up the cost of traveling to some favorite locations.</p>
<p>Prices were roughly twice as much from recent traveling years.</p>
<p>Accrued airline mileages could only take me to Continental US locations.</p>
<p>Far cry from times when not only renewal costs but vast majority of travels to Asian and European destinations were paid for by the employer.</p>
<p>I may not travel and use my new passport.</p>
<p>However, I opted for the thicker booklet (52 pages) rather than the standard 28 pages. Just in case…</p>
<p>My son once said that it is hard to claim knowledge or understanding of a country that you are visiting as a tourist or on business.</p>
<p>Nevertheless traveling even if for a few weeks or days it is still far better than not traveling at all.</p>
<p>I regret that I did not prepare myself before traveling those locations.<br>
I may have gained far more understanding of the culture and history, had I tried.</p>
<p>So I will pay the necessary fees, prepare and wait on future opportunities to travel.</p>
<p>If not, then I will look back and reminisce about lessons learned and people I met, during past travels.</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://www.wikiwand.com/ko/%ED%98%84%EC%B6%A9%EC%82%AC↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>travel</category>
  <category>dreams</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230522 passport travel/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230522 passport travel/flower_canyon.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Marriott Commencement</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230521 marriott commencement/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Attending an 2-hour commencement ceremony, one can get through much reflections about the past and the future.</p>
<p>The 148th Commencement<sup>1</sup> was well executed, like a smooth running factory where everyone knew where they needed to be.</p>
<p>The speaker<sup>2</sup> said all the right things. The College Dean<sup>3</sup> was upbeat and beaming at times.</p>
<p>This was a pinnacle of capitalistic education</p>
<p>Each graduate had 10 to 15 seconds of fame. When their name was called and their accomplishment recognized.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230521 marriott commencement/20230428_194210-01.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Thought of the Marriott Family of Washington DC.</p>
<p>They have a school name after them. They also built a structure 50 years ago that houses, athletic events, devotionals, and graduations such as this.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>What did J. Willard and Alice discuss when they launched their Hot Shoppes business shortly after they married?<br>
What led them to Washington DC?<br>
Did they ever doubt their decisions, how did they overcome their doubt?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>They transitioned to a hospitality business 30 years later.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Did they envision a future as a billion dollar enterprise?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Now nearly 100 years after they were married, Marriotts are blessing lives of thousands of individuals each year.</p>
<p>As my wife like to say,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Hard to fathom the strength and accomplishment of 2 devoted, determined individuals that become one in purpose.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My parents also attended the graduation in August of 1988.</p>
<p>Whereas I walked to this commencement from home in 2023, they drove over 2,000 miles to be there in 1988.</p>
<p>I can’t remember who the speaker was or whether I received diploma from the college dean that day</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230521 marriott commencement/mom_graduation.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>But I do remember the journey the driving to Utah from Maryland in Oldsmobile Delta 88 diesel.</p>
<p>Will treasure days travelling to and from Utah and visiting with them.</p>
<p>I used to question why did they come all that way?</p>
<p>Recently I remembered that their education was cut short due to external circumstances, the Korean War, death of their father.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230521 marriott commencement/sean_dad.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>They came to celebrate not only their son’s graduation but seeing a fulfillment of their longstanding wishes and dreams.</p>
<p>Realized that unfulfilled dreams of past generations are worked on and completed by the current and future generations.</p>
<p>I mingled outside with other parents and grandparents watching little ones.</p>
<p>As I returned to watch the balance of my son’s graduation, I wondered,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>what kind of world his daughter and her generation would inherit and create.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>More immediately,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>What legacy are we leaving for my son’s generation.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>what dreams will be fulfilled by future generations</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>What enterprises and dreams will be started and fulfilled by the children of this graduating class?</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>How many Marriotts will there be in 25, 50 or even 100 years from now?</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230521 marriott commencement/sean_mom.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>In the distant future when my grandchildren graduates,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Will there be actual, in-person ceremonies? Will there be Universities, like the ones we know? Will I see them graduate?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Go Class of 2045 to 2050 !</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://marriott.byu.edu/graduation/wp-content/uploads/sites/59/BYU_Marriott_Convocation_2023.pdf↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Nathan Savage↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>Brigitte Madrian↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>future</category>
  <category>dreams</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230521 marriott commencement/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230521 marriott commencement/mountain.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>School Friend</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230426 30 year friendship/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>A friend lives in a town, 20 miles away. Situated nearly the height of Willis (Sears) Tower, above the valley.</p>
<p>He has lived there for nearly 30 years and we have known one another for nearly entire time.</p>
<p>Still remember when he announced he had sold his home near BYU (Brigham Young University).</p>
<p>Can’t remember much of subjects that were taught. But we became friends, as well as our wives and children got acquainted.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230426 30 year friendship/nebo.jpeg" class="img-fluid"> Over the years, we had a chance to visit their home in the mountains.<br>
Marveled how they improved both the land and their home.</p>
<p>Witnessed how they raised their children and at the same time taking care of their aging parents.<br>
Saw they were cared for with love. The arrangement afforded both living independently and be among their grandchildren. This was a life’s lesson to be cherished.</p>
<p>Recall times when they would ‘camp’ out to get a great spot for the annual July 4th Parade.<br>
We would show up the morning of the Parade and they took us in.<br>
Consequently, extended family members were able to see the Parade in comfort and up close</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230426 30 year friendship/cedar.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Also we took long road trips together.<br>
(nearly all road trips are long in the West)</p>
<p>Through Las Vegas as well as Cedar Breaks, at times.<br>
And making them even longer by going through seldom visited towns such as Alamo and Caliente, Nevada.</p>
<p>In Alamo, we visited Mr.&nbsp;and Mrs.&nbsp;Martin Cox who used to live near us.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230426 30 year friendship/cox.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Once, they invited our whole family, including my parents and my mother-in-law to <a href="https://fortbridgerrendezvous.net/">Fort Bridger Rendezvous</a></p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230426 30 year friendship/bridger.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>We were treated to meals, scenes, and experiences that we could not have on our own.</p>
<p>Thank you Pat and Mike and the rest of the Reid Clan for sharing part of your life with our family.<br>
We appreciate it very much.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>friendship</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230426 30 year friendship/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230426 30 year friendship/view.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Father’s Voice</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/2023040 Korean Fireside/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Met the parents of my mission companion.</p>
<p>The meeting was the post General Conference Korean Fireside hosted by the Korean Ward located in the <a href="https://goo.gl/maps/K9K92MyYesqxqGzH7">Orem Sunset Stake. 1260 S 400 W, Orem, UT 84058</a></p>
<p>As long as I can recall, Koreans have always met separately after the conclusion of the General Conference.</p>
<p>I remember as a missionary, seeing a contingent from Korea addressing Korean Saints in the LA area. <a href="https://goo.gl/maps/hQdrMkvAeuq8dHPNA">LA Olympic Korean Ward. 1209 S Manhattan Pl, Los Angeles, CA 90019</a></p>
<p>Also during the early 1980s, visitors would meet in the old <a href="https://goo.gl/maps/DiaG6HkGJqysDiMu8">7th East Building. 2450 S 600 E, Salt Lake City, UT 84106</a></p>
<p>As the Korean Branch/Ward expanded during the last couple of decades, meetings have been held in various buildings in the Edgemont Area of Provo, as well as in Midvale. <a href="https://goo.gl/maps/DX7zWVgvmpjM4CGr5">8350 Jackson St, Midvale, UT 84047</a></p>
<p>I don’t recall much of what was said by speakers in those gatherings. I do remember meeting old friends and meeting new acquaintances A warm feeling of being with fellow believers and hearing comforting words in language of my father and mother.</p>
<p>Any other group would say 5 sessions and nearly 10 hours of gospel-centered messages would be sufficient.</p>
<p>Not Koreans.</p>
<p>They want to hear directly from their leaders A statement of those principles in their native language. As well as soak up any and all Korea related news.</p>
<p>As a bonus, this year, an Area 70 from Japan attended. Elder Imai said, he found out that his ancestors were from Korea</p>
<p>Format and people attending has changed over the years. But there are few families and individuals that did not change over time</p>
<p>My mission companion, Elder Pak, was from North Ogden. He is the youngest of 6 children and the only son in the family.</p>
<p>Also met the husband of his oldest sister. 김상현. He mentioned that E. Pak is doing quite well as an orthopedic surgeon. Owns 2 hospitals and 2 homes in Buena Park and Huntington Beach. His daughter chimed in, “He is in Peru now, arranging a bike ride back to US”</p>
<p>Thought to myself, my companion has done real well.</p>
<p>Then the daughter mentioned their mother has dementia and has moved in to help out.</p>
<p>If she hadn’t mentioned it, I would not have realized, since she recalled and we talked normally about past events.</p>
<p>As I talked to the father more, I realized he sounded a lot like my own father.</p>
<p>So I ventured and asked where he is from. He said, he has lived in Incheon but he is originally from 함경도 Hamkyung Do. Just few miles from my father’s hometown. (he lived about the same distance as Ogden to Provo).</p>
<p>For a few minutes, thought I was listening to my own father speaking. That unmistakable pattern or 사투리 (억양 抑揚 or intonation) that only North Koreans from 함경남도 (咸鏡南道) area can express..</p>
<p>Thank you Paks. Thank you Father.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/2023040 Korean Fireside/EPSON009_3.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Dad and 고모 [姑母] aunt</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>



 ]]></description>
  <category>gatherings</category>
  <category>memories</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/2023040 Korean Fireside/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/2023040 Korean Fireside/20230327_194753-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Gift from Above</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230223 gift from above/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Received another round of gift from above – moisture – in the form of mixed precipitation or sleet.</p>
<section id="magical-winter-scenes" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="magical-winter-scenes">Magical Winter Scenes</h2>
<p>Earlier in the month, wife asked,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Are you getting tired of removing snow from the sidewalk?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I could have agreed with her, Instead I said,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I enjoy shoveling snow.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Since each snowflakes are unique Each storm brings, slightly different type of snow. Each snow removing session is also unique and a strategy driven event.</p>
<p>Use the <code>shovel-and-throw-over-shoulder</code> approach or the <code>plow-until-you-can't-push</code></p>
<p>It is magical how snow reaches the ground and covers everything.</p>
<ul>
<li>How are layers of snow deposited on surfaces?
<ul>
<li>It it temperature driven?</li>
<li>Is there a industrial equivalence?</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Which factors determine rain, freezing rain and snow?</li>
</ul>
<p>[Not only the scene but the sound changes after snow, things are more serene and quieter.]</p>
</section>
<section id="decisions-short-vs-long-term" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="decisions-short-vs-long-term">Decisions : Short vs Long Term</h2>
<p>There are short term decisions. Where to dine, which country to visit, who to date.</p>
<p>Then there are longer term decisions. Which food to avoid and how much to intake, which neighborhood to set up home, who to commit to and live this life together.</p>
<p>The decision to live in Utah, with its long and snowy winter, was made decades ago.</p>
<p>Decided to take spring wild flowers, summer heat, fall foliage, as well as the winter storms.</p>
<p>(Thus gladly accepting inches of gift of moisture in a high desert),</p>
<p>Rather than judging a place by short visits, there are many who made decisions to make Utah their home.</p>
<p>As well as those that have decided that desert southwest will be their home - year round.</p>
<p>As my sister in Arizona says,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Arizona has summer months, and Utah has its winter months, as burdens to bear.</p>
</blockquote>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230223 gift from above/images/20230320_073227-01 (1).jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Arizona in the Winter, 2023</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>[But if one avoids the place, job, relationship because of limited exposure to extremes or based on rumors or writings on internet, then one misses out on the opportunity to see and experience the abundance of nature, a chance for an advancement and expanding and enriching friendship]</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230223 gift from above/images/IMG_7738.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Snow Patrol, Provo December 2008. PC Davis Archibald Daily Herald</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</section>
<section id="reflecting-on-removing-snow" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="reflecting-on-removing-snow">Reflecting on removing snow</h2>
<p>There was time when I wished for snow to plow – lots of it.</p>
<p>Having a snow plow equipped, 4-wheeler meant, snow removal was something to look forward to.</p>
<p>Now days, if someone offered to clean my sidewalk, wonder how I would respond.</p>
<ul>
<li>how would I spend the time saved</li>
<li>lose out on the opportunity to exercise</li>
</ul>
<p>It is a great feeling to see the clean sidewalk, that would take less than 30 minutes to clear.</p>
<p>The warm weather is most effective means of snow removal.</p>
<p>One develops sense of when to pick up the shovel, or wait on benevolence of neighbors or nature.</p>
<p>As I grow older, hope that I have the strength and fortitude of this gentleman in Park City.</p>
<p>[Vic, in his 90s, is a former miner that lives near the ski area]</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230223 gift from above/images/IMG_1052.CR2.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Vic of Park City, March 2019</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>gratitude</category>
  <category>decisions</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230223 gift from above/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230223 gift from above/IMAG0997.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mom’s Early Days : In her own words</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230219 mom history/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="excerpts-from-moms-early-days-written-by-mom." class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="excerpts-from-moms-early-days-written-by-mom.">Excerpts from <code>Mom's Early Days</code>, written by mom.</h2>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230219 mom history/images/Epson_02192023180029(1).jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Mom’s Early Days</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>우리 엄마 사정을 본 이모는 한 명을 데려가서 공부를 시키겠다고 했다.</p>
<p>처음에는 내가 갈 예정이었는데 엄마가 싫어해서 동생 현숙 이를 보냈다.</p>
<p>그리고는 1947년인지 48년인지 기억이 잘 안 난다.</p>
<p>그럼 몇 번 소식을 들었다.</p>
<p>그렇게 헤어지고 이때까지 보지도 듣지도 못 했다.</p>
<p>지금은 얼굴조차 잘 생각이 안 난다.</p>
<p>너무너무 보고 싶은 내 동생 현숙이,</p>
<p>내가 어찌 잊을 수 있겠는지</p>
<p>쌍둥이 같이 자랐고</p>
<p>눈물이 많아 같이 울고</p>
<p>고생도 같이한 내 동생 현숙이가 아닌가</p>
<p>너무 너무 보고싶고 그립다</p>
<p>내가 죽기 전에 꼭 한 번이라도 만나 봤으면 얼마나 좋겠는지</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>하나님 아버지 꼭 한 번이라도 만날 수 있도록 해 주세요</p>
<p>정말 정말 부탁합니다</p>
<p>진심으로 기도합니다</p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="a-recording-of-my-mom-recounting-her-familys-address" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-recording-of-my-mom-recounting-her-familys-address">A recording of my mom, recounting her family’s address</h2>
<figure class="figure">
<figcaption class="figure-caption">
Mom was 89 at the time
</figcaption>
<audio controls="" src="Mom recals address.mp3">
Your browser does not support the <code>audio</code> element.
</audio>
</figure>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230219 mom history/IMG_2293.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>recollection</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230219 mom history/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230219 mom history/20230217_180419-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Birthday Remembrance</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Want to thank my parents for taking away the fear and stigma associated with getting old and facing death.</p>
</blockquote>
<section id="birth-week" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="birth-week">Birth Week</h2>
<p>Mom and dad were born this week.</p>
<p>Even though we know their birthdays were Lunar Calendar based, we remembered their lunar birthdate on the Solar Calendar Date.</p>
<p>For example, my dad’s birtday is listed as February 12th, which would be March 11th. Still we had the celebration on February 12th.</p>
<p>Likewise, my mom’s would be celebrated on February 20th, instead of March 26th.</p>
<p>[My mom’s birthday would be 26 March 1932, and my dad’s would be 11 March 1930]</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/IMG_0510.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">March 2019</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Want to thank my parents for taking away the fear and stigma associated with getting old and facing death.</p>
<p>Our family was small growing up, on my mother and father’s side. Most family members stayed in North Korea, because everyone thought the War and the separation will be short lived.</p>
<p>Growing up, I saw funeral procession on the street or on TV for one of the relatives of the last monarch.</p>
<p>Most everyone I knew were young and vibrant.</p>
<p>Then our family moved to United States, where I was further removed from pain and suffering associated with death. After turning 20 did I learn that some of the relatives have passed away.</p>
</section>
<section id="maternal-grandmother-5-february-1914---25-november-1999" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="maternal-grandmother-5-february-1914---25-november-1999">Maternal Grandmother (5 February 1914 - 25 November 1999)</h2>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/kim_granma.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>First death of a family member, that I attended, was in the year I turned 37.</p>
<p>At the time I was working in Daegu and my grandmother lived in Incheon.</p>
<p>My maternal grandmother passed away at aged 87, who lived without her husband for nearly 60 years, after suffering from dementia. My aunt lovingly took care of her at home and she looked happy and well taken care of until her passing.</p>
<p>Felt the sorrow of 4 surviving sisters. My mother is the oldest and one that knows, intimately challenges of growing up fatherless. Adding to the sorrow was that her only son passed away when he was in his 40s.</p>
<p>Took on some of the male role that would be handled by male heirs. Felt the sorrow of family members as she was laid to rest.</p>
<p>The ceremony was done according to Christian traditions.</p>
</section>
<section id="paternal-grandmother-20-july-1911---2-may-2003" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="paternal-grandmother-20-july-1911---2-may-2003">Paternal Grandmother (20 July 1911 - 2 May 2003)</h2>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/kang_granma.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>My father’s mom, passed away a year after we returned to US.</p>
<p>My father’s youngest brother and his wife, took care of her for nearly 30 years. (it helped that uncle’s in-laws were trained nurses, they took care of grandmother before she became ill)</p>
<p>Similar to Kim Grandma, my grandmother also lost her husband, and lived alone for nearly 55 years.</p>
<p>My grandmother loved to farm and hike nearby mountains. She passed away at age 92. It was thought that, had she lived in the country, she would have lived another 10 years.</p>
<p>Through family connections, they were able to secure a proper burial place in the mountain. This is important in old Korean culture.</p>
<p>Was able to visit the grave site, two years later.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/IMG_0707.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="my-parents" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="my-parents">My Parents</h2>
<p>Both of my parents lived to be 90 years of age.</p>
<p>I am grateful that my parents, not only lived a full, long life but that they were able to communicate to us, until last days of their sojourn.</p>
<p>They were independent until the end.</p>
<p>They expressed their love and appreciation.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/IMG_0742.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">March 2016</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>There were no fear of passing through to the next life. Only sorrow at the separation from loved ones.</p>
<p>Learned through their lives that living and passing on is both necessary yet beautiful part of the Plan. The Plan that enables us to be born again.</p>
<p>No longer fearful about the as-of-yet not revealed part of life and death.</p>
<p>For my parents and my grandmothers have shown how to live courageously and face death peacefully.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/IMG_7159.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>recollections</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230212 happy birthday/20221206_085703.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Thou Shalt Rise! My Dust, Thou Shalt Arise</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230127 resurrection/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>26 그리고 나 야곱은 내가 반드시 곧 나의 무덤으로 내려갈 것임을 알아, 나의 아들 이노스에게 이르기를, 이 판을 맡으라 하고, 또 나의 형 니파이가 나에게 명한 것을 그에게 말하였더니, 그가 명에 복종할 것을 약속하였느니라. 이제 나는 이 판에 나의 기록함을 마치노니, 그 기록한 것이 작았을지라도 많은 나의 형제들이 내 말을 읽기를 바라며, 읽는 자에게 작별을 고하노라. 형제들아 잘 있으라.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>26 And it came to pass that I, Jacob, began to be old; and the record of this people being kept on the other plates of Nephi, wherefore, I conclude this record, declaring that I have written according to the best of my knowledge, by saying that the time passed away with us, and also our lives passed away like as it were unto us a dream, we being a lonesome and a solemn people, wanderers, cast out from Jerusalem, born in tribulation, in a wilderness, and hated of our brethren, which caused wars and contentions; wherefore, we did mourn out our days</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Jacob 7:26, Book of Mormon</p>
<p>My parents’ and my wife’s parents’ lives were as if a dream. They lived their lives mostly in solitary, lonesome world for them.</p>
<p>Through much tribulation, they tried their utmost against life’s challenges and left us a far better life.</p>
<section id="mourning-practice-in-old-korea" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="mourning-practice-in-old-korea">Mourning Practice in Old Korea</h2>
<p>When I was little, it was common to see those lost their parents to wear a marker on their clothes or on their hair. It was made from a particular clothes and shaped like a small bow tie.</p>
<p>In the olden days, a son was to build a shack by the tomb and spend 3 years of his life by the deceased. The logic was to pay back to parents what they did when we were little. 3 years of raising us, therefore spend 3 years of caretaker by the grave.</p>
<p>This type of reasoning did not survive the modern Korean thinking.</p>
<p>The introduction of Christianity and perhaps the increased practice of cremation may have brought about the certain demise of this practice.</p>
</section>
<section id="a-story-about-regrets" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-story-about-regrets">A story about regrets</h2>
<p>A well know story about not listening to one’s parents is told through a story about a wayward green frog.</p>
<p>There was a green frog that did exactly the opposite of what he was told. The mother frog tried to change the son, time and again she failed. She turned old and was about to die.</p>
<p>She made her final request.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“When I die, please bury me on the bank of a river”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When she died, the son followed her words this time.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“I always did the opposite of what she told me when she was alive,” he said to himself, “but now I will do exactly as she told me.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The green frog sat in the pouring rain by the river bank, crying and crying for his mother. And that is why, to this day, the green frogs cry when it rains.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sejongsociety.org/korean_theme/korean_folk_tales/green_frog.html#:~:text=Long%20ago%2C%20the%20green%20frog,go%20up%2C%20he%20went%20down.">Korean Folk Tales</a></p>
</section>
<section id="personal-regrets" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="personal-regrets">Personal Regrets</h2>
<p>2 things on my mind,</p>
<ul>
<li>Why didn’t I spend more time with them?</li>
<li>Why wasn’t I more kind to them when I was with them?</li>
</ul>
<p>The belief in Christianity and faith on Christ brings some solace.</p>
</section>
<section id="thou-shalt-rise-my-dust-thou-shalt-arise---1764" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="thou-shalt-rise-my-dust-thou-shalt-arise---1764">Thou Shalt Rise! My Dust, Thou Shalt Arise - 1764</h2>
<ul>
<li>Frederick Gottlieb Klopstock</li>
<li>1724-1803</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://hymnary.org/text/thou_shalt_rise_my_dust_thou_shalt_arise#pagescans">Thou shalt rise!</a></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Thou shalt rise! my dust, thou shalt arise!</p>
<p>Not always closed thine eyes:&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thy life's first Giver&nbsp;</p>
<p>Will give thee life forever,&nbsp;</p>
<p>Hallelujah!</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Sown in darkness but to blossom again,</p>
<p>When after winter's reign,</p>
<p>Jesus is reaping&nbsp;</p>
<p>The seed now quietly sleeping,&nbsp;</p>
<p>Hallelujah!</p>
<p><br>
</p>
<p>Day of praise! for thee, thou wondrous day,</p>
<p>In my own grave I stay;</p>
<p>And when I number&nbsp;</p>
<p>My days and nights of slumber,&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thou wakest me!</p>
<p><br>
</p>
<p>Then , as they who dream, we shall arise</p>
<p>With Jesus to the skies,</p>
<p>And find that morrow;</p>
<p>The weary pilgrim's sorrow</p>
<p>All past and gone!</p>
<p><br>
</p>
<p>Then shall I the path to Holiest tread,</p>
<p>By my Redeemer led,</p>
<p>Through heaven soaring,</p>
<p>His holy name adoring</p>
<p>Eternally!</p>
<p><br>
</p>
<p><a href="https://www.evangeliums.net/lieder/lied_auferstehn_ja_auferstehn_wirst_du.html">Auferstehn, ja auferstehn wirst du</a></p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="urlict-1892" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="urlict-1892">Urlict (1892)</h2>
<p>Primordial light</p>
<p>English Translation © Richard Stokes</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>O red rose, Man lies in direst need, Man lies in direst pain, I would rather be in heaven. I then came upon a broad path, An angel came and sought to turn me back, Ah no! I refused to be turned away. I am from God and to God I will return, Dear God will give me a light, Will light my way to eternal blessed life.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Translation © Richard Stokes, author of The Book of Lieder (Faber, 2005)</p>
<p>Urlicht</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>O Röschen rot, Der Mensch liegt in grösster Not, Der Mensch liegt in grösster Pein, Je lieber möcht ich im Himmel sein. Da kam ich auf einen breiten Weg, Da kam ein Engellein und wollt mich abweisen, Ach nein ich liess mich nicht abweisen. Ich bin von Gott und will wieder zu Gott, Der liebe Gott wird mir ein Lichtchen geben, Wird leuchten mir bis an das ewig selig Leben.</p>
</blockquote>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>faith</category>
  <category>resurrection</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230127 resurrection/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230127 resurrection/Thursday_Sunset.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>records of thy fathers</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230126 kang family records/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“That search may be made in the book of the records of thy fathers:…”</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Ezra 4:15, King James Version</li>
</ul>
<p>I have never met my grandfather.<br>
We don’t have a photograph of my grandfather.<br>
We don’t have any records of my family, beyond my grandfather.</p>
<p>We know his name, Kang Hyun Yong</p>
<p>He was an only child and when his mom re-married, he almost assumed a new family name, Shin. However, even though he was not even a teenager, he wanted to and kept his original surname of Kang.</p>
<p>My mom told me that when she was expecting me she had a dream. In that dream, she met a bearded man in a mountain setting.</p>
<p>The man handed my mom a book. The book seemed to be a record. A record of the Kang Family.</p>
<section id="kang-family-records" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="kang-family-records">Kang Family Records</h2>
<p>My sons do not have 2 character names. Left them blank in case we determine 항렬(行列)</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>항렬(行列)은 같은 씨족 안에서 상하의 차례를 분명히 하기 위하여 만든 서열이다</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>is a sequence made to clarify the order within the same clan</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My uncle’s search for his lineage met its dead end.</p>
<p>There are siblings that share the 항렬(行列).<br>
However since my grandfather was all alone, we could figure out his generations</p>
<p>Families that originated from North Korea were allowed to register their family records in 1957. Since many of the families had either left records behind, or some families may not have had family records.</p>
<p>My father assumed the role of the family head.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230126 kang family records/Original_KangFamily_Record_Page_1.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Excerpt from the family record, created in 1957</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>To my uncle’s estimate we belong to Eun Youl Clan 은열공파 (殷烈公派 :파조 민첨), 27th generation<sup>1</sup>.</p>
</section>
<section id="yu-president" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="yu-president">YU President</h2>
<p>One day, was driving to meet June for lunch.<br>
Heard a voice on the classical FM station.<br>
The voice had characteristics not often heard in these parts yet the message was familiar and soothing.</p>
<p>The speaker spoke of the death of his father.</p>
<p>They were memorializing the eternal resting place, at the same time, recognizing that his father was not in that place but in the heart of that son.</p>
<p>Likewise fathers carrying grandfathers in his heart before him.</p>
<p>I needed to hear this personalized message.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230126 kang family records/511841291_520995.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="a-family-of-abraham" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-family-of-abraham">A family of Abraham</h2>
<p>That YU speaker recounted how the entire Jewish Family has a common heritage.</p>
<ul>
<li>Fathers: Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob.</li>
<li>Mothers: Sarah, Rebekah, Leah, and Rachel.</li>
</ul>
<p>I only know my father and know the name of my grandfather. We have been told that the all of the Kang family can trace their lineage back to General Kang of the 6th Century AD<sup>2</sup>.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>진주 강씨(晋州 姜氏) 시조 강이식(姜以式)은 고구려 병마도원수이다<sup>3</sup></p>
</blockquote>
<p>I am not able to confirm if we started out as a Kang family. Perhaps we started our journey as many other families did — no surnames.<br>
Maybe we were indentured servants, bound to the land or authorities.</p>
<p>(My wife can trace their family back to China. An emissary from China stayed in Korea and became a predecessor)</p>
<p>I hope there will come a time when we have a full access to the family records. If that doesn’t happen in this lifetime, we will ponder on these words,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>And think not to say within yourselves, We have Abraham to our father: for I say unto you, that God is able of these stones to raise up children unto Abraham.</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Matthew 3:9, King James Version</li>
</ul>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://m.blog.naver.com/o1o38oo86oo/221797060004↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>https://www.wikiwand.com/ko/%EA%B0%95_(%EC%84%B1%EC%94%A8)↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>http://www.findroot.co.kr/%EC%84%B1%EC%94%A8%EC%B0%BE%EA%B8%B0/%E3%84%B1/%EA%B0%95-2/%EC%A7%84%EC%A3%BC-%EA%B0%95/↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>records</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230126 kang family records/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230126 kang family records/20221221_171422-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>7 Steps Up - 14 Steps Down</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230125 7 steps up/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>For the last 12 years of her life, my mother lived in a white brickhouse.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230125 7 steps up/IMG_6003 (1).JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The house was built on a slight slope, so that the east side of the house sat higher than the west.</p>
<p>It also meant, front of the house had 7 stair steps, where as it took 14 stairs to get to the basement. The basement opens up to the ground level on the west side.</p>
<p>From her kitchen, she could see the Y-Mountain. Mount Timpanogos can be seen from the living room.</p>
<p>Mother and Father would convert a yard with grass into a gardening area that produced vegetables year around, except for the winter.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230125 7 steps up/IMG_8081.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>It contradicted what I envisioned as a retired person. In fact, my mother farmed until the very last, worked during the season of growing.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230125 7 steps up/LND_56A554AC-0CA4-4A0C-8F24-B8782149DB42.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>She was very independent. She would not use a wheel chair, no walker and definitely no canes for her.</p>
<p>However, during the last few months of her life, she could not negotiate those steps. In addition, the snowfall made it dangerous for her to walk to the curbside.</p>
<p>One option was for her to move downstairs. Basement had a direct access to outisde and the driveway, thus no stairs involved.</p>
<p>However, she would miss the sunlight that main level provided, especially on those cold winter days.</p>
<p>We discussed further.</p>
<p>The thought of sending mother to an assisted living was never brought up, since the thought never crossed our minds. We were united in keeping our mother at her home.</p>
<p>Then, my wife suggested the following.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“…I will carry her on my back…”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My mother is a small person, but still carrying a person down a flight of stairs is no simple task. Not to mention going back up those same 14 steps while carrying a person on the back.</p>
<p>In a small measure, we were able to give back all that our parents provided over the years.</p>
<p>Perhaps in a very small means, we were able to do unto others, things they are not able to do on their own.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>recollections</category>
  <category>independence</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230125 7 steps up/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230125 7 steps up/IMG_7719 (1).JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>father’s messages</title>
  <dc:creator>DK</dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>My father didn’t express his feelings much. Like most men from his generation, less words the better.</p>
<p>Was surprised to discover journals kept by him, in his 80s.</p>
<p>My father spent 36 years in Maryland area. Then in summer of 2010, he sold his home and moved to Provo to be close to the grandchildren.</p>
<p>His life in Utah centered around the family and his God.</p>
<p>Daily activites were with the family and for the family. When good things happened, big or small, he thanked the source of all blessings - our God</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/Epson_01252023194746_3.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Journal Entry from April 2011</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/EPSON044-02.jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">In Đà Nẵng</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>It has been said “a picture is worth thousand words”<br>
However the original quote refers to deed or action</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“A thousand words leave not the same deep impression as does a single deed.” Source: theidioms.com</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Henrik Ibsen</li>
</ul>
<p>Then it is possible that a single act or deed can inspire a multitude of imagery or words.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/IMG_0286.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Dad in his 80s</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>There are multiple ways of living a record or legacy.</p>
<p>A visual medium such as video has multiple codec.<br>
A audio format has even more ways to encode data.</p>
<p>However, how many of these will survive and be interpreted by future generations.</p>
<p>The engraved or written record may be the most simple yet most enduring - precisely because of its simplicity.</p>
<p>While the world may search for the most accurate depiction of its surroundings and everyday occurrence, perhaps the most potent and effective means of preserving and passing on the values from one generation to another is used by the young and old alike – writing down the feelings of each moment.</p>
<p>Because, it is not the amount nor the accuracy that ultimately matters, but the feelings that the message conveys, and the impressions or imagery the message conjures up.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/IMG_9527 (3).JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Dad in his late 80s</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Thanks dad for keeping the journal for us to remember your good life.</p>
<p>It reminds me to be industrious, do good, and give thanks, until the very end.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>family</category>
  <category>records</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230124 dad messages/20230201_172340-01.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
