<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Quarto Blog</title>
<link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 07:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>A Neighborhood Conference</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20240121 Meaning of All Things/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Attend a conference.</p>
<p>At this weekly conference, life’s personal guidelines were presented – both from very old to pre teens.</p>
<p>Not the same person or a group of people each week but a person chosen among the neighborhood congregation.</p>
<p>An insight into their lives and the blessings of the gospel.</p>
<p>This conference can also be called the <code>Meeting of a Neighborhood</code> or the Sacrament Meeting on the Sabbath.</p>
<hr>
<p>A young man passed the sacrament to the congregation for the first time.</p>
<p>He seemed like he was closer to the baptism age than the priesthood age.</p>
<p>He was passing the sacrament along with his father.</p>
<p>There were others that were at least foot taller than he.</p>
<hr>
<p>A young Sister E, spoke of growing up in the household of gospel learners.</p>
<p>Her parents taught early seminary and they played gospel related games growing up.</p>
<p>She related how attending the early Seminary impacted her life.</p>
<p>Visiting the Sacred Grove and re-affirming her testimony</p>
<hr>
<p>Then Sister A spoke like we were part of a General Conference.</p>
<p>She acknowledged and thanked members of the congregation.</p>
<p>She reflected a life well lived.</p>
<p>From the heart.</p>
<p>Soothing.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20240121 Meaning of All Things/main.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<hr>
<p>Attended the Breakout Sessions of the conference</p>
<p>It was called the Sunday School Lesson.</p>
<p>The teachers added not only their life’s experience but also their vocation and training</p>
<p>We were taught by current and past BYU professors and researchers.</p>
<p>They brought their own style of teaching.</p>
<p>An Economics Professor K, paused as he was about to make a statement.</p>
<p>He then formulated a question from the statement.</p>
<hr>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>We are living in a privileged time.</p>
<p>When there are so much resources.</p>
<p>By those who have devoted much of their lives for studying.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Thus began the Sunday School teacher, Brother H.</p>
<p>His first name matches a well known Ivy League School.</p>
<p>He also worked on editing and abridging the Journals of David O McKay</p>
<hr>
<p>He compared the journey of the Lehi’s family in the wilderness as a microcosm of our earthly life</p>
<p>We have a choice to be a willing participants, like Nephi was.</p>
<p>Or murmur like the first 2 sons, Laman and Lemuel.</p>
<section id="difficulty-of-an-abridgereditor" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="difficulty-of-an-abridgereditor">Difficulty of an abridger/editor</h2>
<p>There were 3 major editors of the Book of Mormon.</p>
<p>Nephi, Mormon and Moroni.</p>
<p>Roughly 2 pages per year<sup>1</sup>.</p>
</section>
<section id="weakness-in-their-language" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="weakness-in-their-language">Weakness in their language</h2>
<p>D&amp;C 1:24</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>24 Behold, I am God and have spoken it; these commandments are of me, and were given unto my servants in their weakness, after the manner of their language, that they might come to understanding.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He described the process of translation.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>The person sees images, conveys and writes its meaning in written language</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He then made this analogy, quoting Neal A. Maxwell</p>
</section>
<section id="an-hurried-tourist" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="an-hurried-tourist">An Hurried Tourist</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>May we come to feel as a whole people beckoned beyond the entry hall. May we go inside far enough to hear clearly the whispered truths from those who have “slumbered,” which whisperings will awaken in us individually the life of discipleship as never before<sup>2</sup>.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20240121 Meaning of All Things/m.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>He then quoted <code>1 Nephi 11</code></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>16 And he said unto me: Knowest thou the condescension of God?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Teacher’s son wanted to serve a mission. He was ready and worthy.</p>
<p>He was called to serve a mission in Ukraine. His diagnosis of leukemia delayed it.</p>
<p>With years of chemotherapy, the cancer was in remission. Shortly before his graduation from BYU, leukemia returned.</p>
<p>Bone marrow transplant followed.</p>
<p>He lived to be 29 years of age<sup>3</sup>.</p>
<p>The teacher concluded with the words,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>17 And I said unto him: I know that he loveth his children; nevertheless, I do not know the meaning of all things.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Until that time when the meaning of all things will be made known…</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Over 500 pages covers 1000 years of history↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>https://rsc.byu.edu/voice-my-servants/book-mormon-great-answer-great-question↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>https://www.legacy.com/us/obituaries/legacyremembers/daniel-heath-obituary?id=28901508↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>unanswered</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20240121 Meaning of All Things/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20240121 Meaning of All Things/main.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Outward Impressions</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20240107 Remembering Deceased/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Growing up in Korea, I remember seeing a bow, about the size of an iPhone charger. It was made from the sackcloth. Men would pin it on their shirt and the women on their hair.</p>
<p>This was to signify that they are in mourning. Often for 3 years.</p>
<p>In the old days, people would spend 3 years next to a grave. Matching the same period as the parents taking care of little ones.</p>
<p>Times have altered traditions. Periods of mourning have been shortened as well as the method of mourning.</p>
<p>I don’t recall seeing anyone wearing those sackcloth bows these days</p>
<hr>
<p>How are we to know if someone is in mourning?<br>
How do we know if someone is struggling?<br>
How do we know how others feel at the moment?<br>
</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20240107 Remembering Deceased/intro.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="a-breeze-flight-from-provo-to-phoenix" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-breeze-flight-from-provo-to-phoenix">A Breeze Flight from Provo to Phoenix</h2>
<p>The plane was roughly half full, was hoping there would be empty seats.</p>
<p>It was not to be.</p>
<p>I was seated on the aisle seat, 22D to be exact. 2 ladies came to the row 22.<br>
The younger lady with a headphone took the window seat. The older lady began asking questions.</p>
<p>I wished I had brought a noise cancellation headphone<br>
I was flying without a carry on. Since I had left most things in AZ It felt good to just have a tote bag</p>
<p>It meant I had to leave some essentials behind. Including a noise cancellation device for listening to music and isolation from others</p>
<p>She asked where I was headed. I gave some generic, non-revealing answer.</p>
<p>She began the dialogue with a story. She was on a women-only retreat to Tucson, after her sister’s funeral in Salt Lake.</p>
<p>I gave in and revealed a little.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20240107 Remembering Deceased/m2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I was heading to a family member funeral in Phoenix.</p>
<p>She said her sister was 40 years old with few kids. The cancer overtook her.</p>
<p>At this point I was trying to calculate the odds. There are nearly 200 people in this plane, Airbus 220.</p>
<p>She and I shared something in common and we were having a conversation about losing someone very close.</p>
<p>Was this a coincidence, a random occurrence? She and I talked for the duration of the flight.</p>
<p>She mentioned that her parents were very strict and it drove some children away from the faith.</p>
<p>I was grateful that she took time to explain her circumstances even though I was not a willing participant.</p>
<p>Grateful that fate intervened and I was comforted by sharing our common experiences</p>
<hr>
<p>Ancients and progenitors devised a way for people to mourn in private. Also publicly – if one chooses.</p>
<p>Currently, we celebrate happy moments together. In diverse ways, including social media, balloons and T-shirts.</p>
<p>However, we seldom, especially men, share the grief with others.</p>
<p>I want to thank the person in seat 22E, on the flight MXY 620.</p>
<p>It helped me ease my burden by both listening and expressing our common experiences.</p>
<p>Neither one of us wore a distinguishing marks. But one of us was sensitive enough to open up and share her sister’s life and death.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20240107 Remembering Deceased/m1.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>remembrance</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20240107 Remembering Deceased/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20240107 Remembering Deceased/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fear No More - 對話 8</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231228 Fear Future/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>손자/孫子</p>
<p>I heard you said something back in Winter of 2021/22, during the Covid-19<sup>1</sup> Pandemic, something to the effect that you no longer had fears about the future.</p>
<p>Older Me</p>
<p>That sounds plausible, that was when I was serving with Young Adults in Provo.</p>
<p>I did say a few things that I didn’t document, or that I should not have said in the first place.</p>
<p>But those words seem like something I could have said.</p>
<p>Who told you I said those words?</p>
<p>손자/孫子</p>
<p>Professors Emily and Spencer at UCLA Medical School.</p>
<p>Dr.&nbsp;Emily is head of the Neuroscience and AI Development and</p>
<p>Dr.&nbsp;Spencer is an endowed professor of Research Institute for the Robotic Surgery.</p>
<p>They both remembered and attributed those quotes as coming from you.</p>
<p>So do you remember them and why you made that statement?</p>
<p>Older Me</p>
<p>I remember Emily and Spencer well…</p>
<p>I think we were heading into the 2nd or 3rd variant of the Covid-19 virus, and another spike in positive cases.</p>
<p>Was concerned about the emotional and spiritual well-being of young people.</p>
<p>In addition, I was worried about my future after retirement and the health of those around me, especially your great-grandma Hwang.</p>
<p>손자/孫子</p>
<p>I am glad you remembered them.</p>
<p>So what was the genesis of change in thinking from negative to positive outlook?</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231228 Fear Future/main.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Older Me</p>
<p>I began to think about the one-sided, usually negative, depressing scenario propagated through mediums we had at the time.</p>
<p>Something was didn’t seem right and at times felt anxious about the future.</p>
<p>I thought there must be some positives that can be reported.</p>
<p>I need a change in perspective.</p>
<hr>
<p>What would my mom and dad have done in a similar situation?</p>
<p>They endured immediate threat to life and impending hardships as refugees, due to being displaced from their homes and being drafted into combat duty.</p>
<p>They both knew the enemy, communist ideology and post-war poverty and they were able to endure, battle and overcome both.</p>
<p>손자/孫子</p>
<p>You mean the Covid-19 situation and predicted outcome was based on probable or model based.</p>
<p>Older Me</p>
<p>Exactly.</p>
<p>The prospective doom scenario was scary but at times they were off on their estimation.</p>
<p>Sometimes, they were wrong.</p>
<p>In the case of Covid-19, we knew the enemy but it was shifting and self-replicating and therefore prognostications and diagnosis were ever changing, and sometimes incorrect.</p>
<p>I recall people were locked into battles of opinions, precedents, rights and fears, during this time of uncertainty – relying on the strength of men and women and societal systems.</p>
<p>I, along with your grandma, clung to God of Old Testament and of New Testament for strength and comfort.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231228 Fear Future/main3.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>손자/孫子</p>
<p>So it was a combination of examples and life of your parents and remembering the God of Old and New Testament days.</p>
<p>What was the result of having that thought and resolution? What did you do differently?</p>
<p>Older Me</p>
<p>Realized I had to be stronger spiritually, emotionally and physically to overcome the Pandemic or any other calamities .</p>
<p>Others can offer advice and even offer medical, man-made solutions, but I realized I need to be prepared for not only this Pandemic but all the other ones that were foretold.</p>
<p>Equally, I needed to rely, more fully, on the God of Miracles, the same God that led children of Israel from Egypt to the Land of Canaan.</p>
<p>Please remember that same spirit of resilience and reliance on the Lord that your forefathers had is also in you and your generation.</p>
<p>You can do this and other great, wondrous things that Lord God will ask you to perform</p>
<p>손자/孫子</p>
<p>You became both independent and dependent.</p>
<p>The call to leave spiritual and physical Babylon is always with us.</p>
<p>But at times, we need to endure likes of Pandemic.</p>
<p>Thanks Grandpa, that was very helpful.</p>
<p>Any words for Professors Emily and Spencer, next time I am in their classes?</p>
<p>Older Me</p>
<p>Philippians 4:13</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Corona Virus Disease 2019↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>future</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231228 Fear Future/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231228 Fear Future/main.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Maryland Christmas Memories</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231219 Memories of MD Christmas/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Spent 9 years living in a suburban Washington DC area, Maryland.</p>
<p>That was the beginning of our lives in the United States.</p>
<p>Those years can be recalled in terms of where we lived and what school we attended.</p>
<p>Rather, those years were years of association with a unit known as the Carrollton Ward.</p>
<p>That was a great blessing for our Family.</p>
<hr>
<p>Immigrants seek a better life elsewhere</p>
<p>Mainly for education and economic improvement for future generations, religious liberty, asylum from persecution and family strife.</p>
<p>My family came for 3 out of 4 reasons.</p>
<p>In the end religion became the defining reason.</p>
<hr>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231219 Memories of MD Christmas/main1.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>As an immigrant I learned how to read, write and speak in English through the Prince George’s county school system.</p>
<p>However, I learned how to live this life, as a follower of Christ, in a congregation of saints</p>
<hr>
<p>Figuring out the church schedule was a challenge, since we couldn’t understand the announcement.</p>
<p>We sometimes missed meetings because Stake and General Conferences meant a different location and time.</p>
<p>Others because not understanding the Daylight Savings Time.</p>
<p>Our language improved over the years and Brother Bacon from Terre Haute, IN became our Home Teacher. For the next 5 years, he faithfully visited our home.</p>
<hr>
<p>We became more involved in the Ward</p>
<p>Not always, but attended the weeknight meetings as well.</p>
<p>That led to participating in Road Shows, summer camps and a church wide celebration.</p>
<p>Summer camps and Father and Sons campout were those rare occasions to see places other than a cityscape</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231219 Memories of MD Christmas/main2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The Sesquicentennial celebration in Roanoke and the surrounding area in 1980 was a defining event for a young person.</p>
<p>The magnitude of participation, from the mid-atlantic areas, as well as the depth of commitment demonstrated by participants made a deep impression.</p>
<p>The Ferrum College and the surrounding areas of Roanoke Conference Center opened up a new chapter for a young immigrant person.</p>
<hr>
<p>Many Koreans, including our family, attended church in Korea after the War.</p>
<p>For adults, it was a religion.</p>
<p>For a young person, it was a chore to walk to and from church often at night</p>
<p>Hearing wild animals added to the sense of sacrifice and an adventure.</p>
<p>For many of us, Christmas was a foreign tradition.</p>
<p>Snacks or treats offered during Easters and Christmas were definitely highlights.</p>
<p>Then our family, mainly through my mother’s conversion, joined another congregation. It was not a popular choice then. But my mother was convinced that it was the right choice for her and the family.</p>
<p>Within 3 years, we were boarding a plane headed for Anchorage. On our way to a new home in the Washington DC area.</p>
<p>[How Washington DC was chosen, see, <a href="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230705%20New%20Carrollton/">link</a>]</p>
<hr>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231219 Memories of MD Christmas/main3.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I remember gatherings in Maryland at Christmas time.</p>
<p>Was asked to learn Christmas Carol to be sung at the Church. Not exposed to music up until then, I struggled to learn, but I still recall the refrains of <code>Angels We Have Heard...</code></p>
<div class="quarto-video"><iframe data-external="1" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/anV7_4NNiFQ" width="400" height="300" title="" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>
<p>Participated in Christmas Devotional at the Church. Where many difficult concepts were explained in plain, parent-like mannners.</p>
<p>My father became one of the Wisemen at a church play. That participation meant a lot to him and for us.</p>
<p>Recall a Christmas Eve gathering at a home, where people are invited to visit, stay or go according to their schedule. Plenty of goodies were served. Remember thinking, when I have a chance, I want to have a gathering like this.</p>
<p>This and many other gatherings helped me realize what a family centered, the community assisted living was like.</p>
<p>According to Ephesians,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>19 Now therefore ye are no more strangers and foreigners, but fellowcitizens with the saints, and of the household of God;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Thank you Carrollton Ward Members.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>Christmas</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231219 Memories of MD Christmas/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231219 Memories of MD Christmas/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Sayings of My Parents</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231212 Sayings of My Parents/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>My parents’ favorite Old Korean Proverb was,</p>
<p>소문난 잔치에 먹을거 없다</p>
<p>Well publicized event has no food.<sup>1</sup></p>
<p>The word 소문 can mean a <code>rumor</code> So an alternate interpretation may be</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>A rumored feast turned out to be a disappointment.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Korea faced food shortage well into the 20th century, so this is no passing phrase.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231212 Sayings of My Parents/main.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>This one saying can summarize the entirety of my parents generation</p>
<p>When shortage of food was central or essential life’s concern the common greeting in Korea used to be,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Have you eaten.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The harvest determined whether there was food during the winter months that will last into the spring</p>
<section id="the-proverbs-are-original-and-enduring-twitter-or-x" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-proverbs-are-original-and-enduring-twitter-or-x">The proverbs are original and enduring Twitter (or X)</h2>
<p>Decisive advantage old proverbs have over modern sayings is that they are well tested and proven.</p>
<p>Perhaps they are the original LLM<sup>2</sup>. Tested on large sample of people and situation. Thus earning the same label, GPT <code>Generational Personalized Training</code>.</p>
<p>The saying</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Well publicized event has no food</p>
</blockquote>
<p>is helpful to assess or filter modern day situations as well.</p>
<p>Some ways to keep from being disappointed.</p>
<ul>
<li>Be aware of, verify, sources of rumor.</li>
<li>Avoid big feast, or gatherings, ones with long lines. <a href="https://www.biblegateway.com/verse/en/Matthew%207%3A13">Matthew 7:13</a></li>
<li>If one must attend the feast, eat some before arriving. In case food runs out or it is not what you expected.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="story-of-張良-at-yishui-bridge" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="story-of-張良-at-yishui-bridge">Story of 張良 at Yishui Bridge<sup>3</sup></h2>
<p>Old people tend to arrive at an appointment early.</p>
<p>張良(Zhang_Liang_(Western_Han)) learned his lesson from Huang Shigong (黃石公)</p>
<p>Huang Shigong told Zhang Liang to meet him at a bridge for a follow up lesson.</p>
<p>But when 張良 went to the bridge, at the appointed hour, the old master was already there.</p>
<p>Another encounter 5 days later. Same thing happened</p>
<p>On the third try, 張良 went to the bridge at midnight and waited for the master.</p>
<p>張良 was given a set of treatise on Warfare and how to manage the affairs of kingdom.<sup>4</sup></p>
<p>張良 is considered one of the 3 pillars that established the Han Dynasty.</p>
<p>My mom’s family also learned a lesson about arriving early for an appointment.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231212 Sayings of My Parents/main2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="a-story-of-an-escape-from-north-korea" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-story-of-an-escape-from-north-korea">A Story of an Escape from North Korea</h2>
<p>The boat had space for 40 individuals but only 13 made it.</p>
<p>The boat, that was to take my mother’s family to South Korea, came earlier than scheduled.</p>
<p>The escape boat faced less resistance or the shooting was lighter than expected.</p>
<p>In her own words, this is how she escaped during the winter of 1950/51.</p>
</section>
<section id="an-audio-recording-from-november-2017" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="an-audio-recording-from-november-2017">An Audio Recording from November 2017</h2>
<p>She recounts her escape from North Korea on January 1951. Recording made when mother was 85.</p>
<figure class="figure">
<figcaption class="figure-caption">
Click to Listen
</figcaption>
<audio controls="" src="mom_escape.mp3">
Your browser does not support the <code>audio</code> element.
</audio>
</figure>
<p>The boat had capacity of 40 but only 13 boarded. Because the boat arrived earlier than scheduled.</p>
<p>While escaping, a machine gun was firing from the shore and planes were dropping bombs on them.</p>
<p>[Perhaps because mom and dad suffered when they were young, they were able to overcome trials that came later]</p>
<p>When the boat arrived at the appointed island, the whole island had been bombed. All 20 homes were destroyed</p>
<p>And the snow covered the ground</p>
<p>Two young men that came on the boat started digging a hole for the family to sleep.</p>
<p>As they dug, there were more ashes on the ground.</p>
<p>They placed the blanket they had brought and slept on that makeshift survival arrangement.</p>
<hr>
<p>For Zhang Liang persistence and being early for an appointment meant gaining the wisdom literature.</p>
<p>[If the records and legends are correct].</p>
<p>For my mother’s family.</p>
<p>Being early meant escaping the North at a time when the UN Forces were also withdrawing.</p>
<p>If they missed that hired boat, the family may have not have escaped North.</p>
<p>My mother’s family was able to start a new life in Incheon (인천) a few years later.</p>
<p>The lessson from that boat encounter will stay with our family.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231212 Sayings of My Parents/main3.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Chat GPT interpretation, The literal translation of “소문난 잔치에 먹을거 없다” from Korean to English is “There is nothing to eat at the famous feast.” However, this expression is often used idiomatically to convey a sense of disappointment or unmet expectations. In English, a similar expression might be “There’s nothing to eat at the big event” or “There’s no food at the renowned feast.”↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Large Language Model↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>as recorded in Wikipedia↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn4"><p>Six Secret Teachings by Jiang Ziya↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>sayings</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231212 Sayings of My Parents/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231212 Sayings of My Parents/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Personal Family Conferences</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231210 Family Conference/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This weekend our neighborhood celebrated the lives of two individuals that spent their last and perhaps their best years of their lives with their family and friends.</p>
<p>They shared their wisdom, time and love.</p>
<p>The families held their Family Conferences and we were invited to join.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231210 Family Conference/main.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<hr>
<p>Last Sunday, our bishop was uncharacteristically extemporaneous.</p>
<p>Normally a calm, in-control person, seemed a bit distracted – almost unprepared.</p>
<p>At the start of the meeting, he announced that Brother Steve had passed away.</p>
<p>We could hardly believe it, for we all saw him healthy, doing his normal routine of hiking/biking the Rock Canyon – just a week ago.</p>
<p>Then before bearing his testimony, he announced that Sister Jackie had also passed away.</p>
<p>Later we learned that he was told about these at 11:58 and 12:13.</p>
<p>Our church services begin at Noon.</p>
<p>The balance of the meeting was turned into a impromptu memorial service for Jackie and Steve</p>
<p>Recounting their kindness and service.</p>
<section id="scheduling-of-the-neighborhood-conference" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="scheduling-of-the-neighborhood-conference">Scheduling of the Neighborhood Conference</h2>
<p>The Ward had already scheduled the annual Christmas Party at 10AM on Saturday.</p>
<p>Jackie’s family chose to meet on Friday at 6PM.</p>
<p>Steve’s family planned to meet after the Ward Christmas Party.</p>
<p>This was the beginning of what turned out to be a rich, memorable gathering.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-public-side" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-public-side">The Public Side</h2>
<p>We knew both Jackie and Steve loved to travel, to gain a better understanding of humanity.</p>
<p>They preferred the non-traditional approach to travel.</p>
<p>Spend time with locals, in their environment.</p>
<p>The longer the stay, the better.</p>
<p>Difficult to document all of the places and people they traveled to, met and influenced.</p>
<p>But it must have impacted Jackie and Steve as well</p>
<p>They both could not only read and understand individuals that came into their sphere, but also knew how to succor them and make them whole.</p>
<p>They loved all humankind, the creation of our common God.</p>
<p>Humankind responded in a like manner.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231210 Family Conference/main3.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="words-and-music-as-a-complementary-force" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="words-and-music-as-a-complementary-force">Words and Music as a complementary force</h2>
<p>They graduated from this phase of progression, the life we are familiar and confined to.</p>
<p>They have shown how to learn, then teach and serve others.</p>
<p>The family and friends paid tribute in words and music.</p>
<p>And this in turn invoked memories of their lives and influence on us</p>
<p>Chosen music and words were elevating and eloquent.</p>
<p>Speakers wove the family lessons and experiences as if they were one – because they are.</p>
<p>Jackie’s family shared her writings. Often captured in poems.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231210 Family Conference/poem.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Grandsons of Steve performed <code>Be Still My Soul</code></p>
<p>They pulled out hats prior to singing, a tribute to their hat loving grandfather.</p>
<p>That hymn was also sung on the Friday evening portion of the gathering.</p>
<p>The music based on Sibelius’ Finlandia and words by Katharina A. von Schlegel was a fitting choice for their Nordic or Scandinavian heritage</p>
<p>Grateful for that heritage.</p>
<p>One that displays, The Cross, on their national symbol</p>
<p>The one that we, <code>bear patiently</code>, <code>the cross of, grief or pain</code>.</p>
<p>The Friday evening session ended with an abundant serving of dessert, a mingling of family and friends, as Jackie would have wanted.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231210 Family Conference/main2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Saturday Afternoon Session continued the lessons from uplifting and transformational life of Steve.</p>
<p>He loved people and he made sure they knew it.</p>
<p>By providing the needful item, whether it was a warm bread or words of encouragement.</p>
<p>His father passed away when Steve was 13.</p>
<p>Because Steve grew up without a father’s presence, he knew how to succor those that needed his assuring wisdom</p>
<p>The Saturday afternoon session ended with a graveside service at the Provo Cemetery.</p>
<p>The December afternoon gave way to a clearing, ray of sunshine.</p>
<p>A military honor was provided.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231210 Family Conference/flag.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="general-instructions-personal-transformations" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="general-instructions-personal-transformations">General Instructions &amp; Personal Transformations</h2>
<p>In the Church, general instructions are given, 2 times a year, on how we should live our lives.</p>
<p>In the family, we receive life long lessons from, mostly from parents, when we are young and growing up.</p>
<p>Then as adults, we influence and transform one another.</p>
<p>We change and grow by implementing those principles that we learn at the general church level, reinforced each Sabbath.</p>
<p>However, it is at the family or neighborhood level that lessons are implemented and transformed into life’s – on a daily basis</p>
<p>At times we get a personal glimpse of how a family influences and builds lives</p>
<p>This weekend we were blessed to see and mingle with two such families.</p>
<p>Thank you to the families of Jackie and Steve.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231210 Family Conference/ray.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>hometown</category>
  <category>remembrance</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231210 Family Conference/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231210 Family Conference/intro.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A future dialogue with a grandson, Episode 3</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231208 Musk We Trust/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>손자/孫子:<br>
Grandpa, why are old people so predictable?</p>
<p>Older Me:<br>
You mean why are we so boring?</p>
<p>손자/孫子:<br>
I didn’t say that…but maybe I meant it.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231208 Musk We Trust/main1.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Older Me:<br>
We may be boring but we are not bored, but that discussion is for another time. You remember the Central Limit Theorem, please explain it to me.</p>
<p>손자/孫子:<br>
Something like, the distribution of a sample variable approximates a normal distribution as the sample becomes larger.</p>
<p>ChatGPT 101.WRX Turbo says,<br>
</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>So, the central limit theorem tells us that even if the individual measurements are not normally distributed, their averages tend to follow a normal distribution when you have a lot of them. This makes it easier for us to make predictions and understand the behavior of averages in a variety of situations.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>In simpler terms, it’s like saying if you keep taking the average of a bunch of measurements, no matter what those measurements are, the results will look like a nice, predictable bell curve. It’s a helpful tool in statistics that lets us make sense of randomness and understand patterns in data</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Older Me:<br>
Each old person is a sample variable and their experiences, trials, disappointments, failures, and reversals in fortune constitute a sample.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231208 Musk We Trust/main2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>손자/孫子:<br>
OK. So as one ages, our individual attributes fade and universal truths prevail and lessons deepen. But what about the good things that happen to individuals?</p>
<p>Older Me:<br>
You asked what makes us so predictable. Each person is given moments of happiness or their 15 minutes (perhaps 15 nano seconds now days) of fame and may feel joy for a period of time.</p>
<p>Individual differences and “moments in the spotlight” makes this life interesting or enjoyable.</p>
<p>But it is those times that we face setbacks and challenges that define and unite us as a “predictable” part of the human race.</p>
<p>손자/孫子:<br>
Can I get to the truth or that level of understanding without going through life’s trials?</p>
<p>Older Me:<br>
What does the Central Limit Theorem predict?<br>
What do great literature and sacred writings teach? What do you think?</p>
<p>손자/孫子:<br>
Our objective in life is to go through and gain experiences that define us.<br>
There is no short-cut.<br>
No matter how much some parents try to shield us from those experiences.</p>
<p>Older Me:<br>
I think you learned it well. It’s getting late. You better go pick up your date. What vehicle do you drive/fly nowadays?</p>
<p>손자/孫子:<br>
Tesla XYZ, the one with vertical take-off and landing and available full auto-pilot mode.</p>
<p>Older Me:<br>
In that case, you will need some extra funds for the upkeep. Here are 100 Bitcoins (BTC) for you. What does the new inscription say on the coin?</p>
<p>손자/孫子:<br>
“In Musk we trust?”</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231208 Musk We Trust/main3.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>future</category>
  <category>dialogue</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231208 Musk We Trust/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231208 Musk We Trust/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Official Time Keepers</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231206 Official Calendar Turner/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>One of the advantages of working for a Japanese company affiliate is tasting the sweets that people bring following a business trip.</p>
<p>Regional delicacies from Niigata (新潟県), famous treats from Tokyo like Tokyo Banana.</p>
<p>And even chocolates from Belgium.</p>
<hr>
<p>Another distinction are beautifully crafted calendars from vendors in Japan.</p>
<p>A new scenery is displayed every 2 months.</p>
<p>As I was turning Sep/Oct into Nov/Dec.&nbsp;I noticed that the place depicted seemed familiar.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231206 Official Calendar Turner/yamadera.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">立石寺, 山形県, from Ohara 2023 Calendar</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Yet the name listed on the calendar, Risshaku-ji (立石寺) I didn’t recognize. But the prefecture seemed familiar – Yamagata 山形県</p>
<p>An internet search and a confirmation with a colleague from Niigata showed its alternate designation, Mountain Temple or 山寺</p>
<p>It was the same temple that I had visited before, during one of the business trips.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231206 Official Calendar Turner/IMG_1703.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">山寺, 山形県</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Immediately became more connected with the image on the calendar.</p>
<p>I would keep and frame those captured images of beautiful locations</p>
<hr>
<p>Names, designations for places, cities and prefectures may change but places like Yamadera will retains its rightful designation – <code>A Temple in the Mountains</code>.</p>
<hr>
<section id="temple-in-canyons-and-mountains" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="temple-in-canyons-and-mountains">Temple in Canyons and Mountains</h2>
<p>That temple in the mountain gave a new appreciation for workmanship of dedicated people. It will stand the throughout ages.</p>
<p>There is a building nearby in Utah that also gave much memories</p>
<p>This temple has been place of inspiration and solace.</p>
<p>Also a place of gathering for missionaries in general and for a random (not planned?) encounters with family members that were in the MTC.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231206 Official Calendar Turner/temple1.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Calendar pictures or photos of place and buildings bring back many memories</p>
</section>
<section id="yield-to-a-new-era" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="yield-to-a-new-era">Yield to a new era</h2>
<p>Calendars occupy a certain space and time and must yield to new period of time</p>
<p>Similarly, buildings that have served its purpose are replaced by more modern and convenient design.</p>
<p>However, there are cultures that value things of old and seem outdated.</p>
<p>Some culture favors new buildings with modern designs</p>
<p>Elsewhere a standard for longevity are in centuries and millenia.</p>
<p>Some seem to measure in terms of years and decades.</p>
<p>A preference for progress and a new-start over preservation and continuity.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231206 Official Calendar Turner/main.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="building-lasting-memories" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="building-lasting-memories">Building Lasting Memories</h2>
<p>Memories associated with these buildings will outlive the physical building and this life.</p>
<p>It will take some time to adjust to the new building that will grace that spot in the canyon.</p>
<p>Thank you, the temple in the canyon, the canyon itself, and the people in the area.</p>
<p>You have given me and many many others a lifetime of memories.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231206 Official Calendar Turner/temple3.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>nature</category>
  <category>temples</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231206 Official Calendar Turner/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231206 Official Calendar Turner/intro.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Recollections and Memories : Why Blog?</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231204 Why Blog/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Shared a video clip with a former colleague.</p>
<p>The setting was a farewell luncheon held at Morelia’s (now called Casa Linda) near the Fashion Place Mall.</p>
<p>But I had difficulty remembering names of people in the video.</p>
<p>I recognize their faces and their roles but I could only remember the names of roughly half the people present.</p>
<p>That luncheon was held in December 1998.</p>
<hr>
<p>Taking notes used to be an option but now it is becoming essential – if I want to remember places, time and names.</p>
<p>These and other factors made me write down my recollections, rather than solely relying on memories.</p>
<hr>
<p>This is the greatest era for capturing and archiving memories.</p>
<p>There are innumerable ways to record or capture ideas or memories using audio, video, written with a physical pen/ink or with an electronic pen/ink.</p>
<p>There are apps and programs that will convert one medium to another. There are equally numerous ways to disseminate and share the content.</p>
<p>During a recent conversation, one commented</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>People in the past did many things with very little. Today, we have many, great things, What will we leave behind?</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231204 Why Blog/main3.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="which-medium-and-manner-of-record-keeping" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="which-medium-and-manner-of-record-keeping">Which medium and manner of record keeping</h2>
<p>It is said that a picture is worth a thousand words. It is also true that a typical photo takes nearly 5 Million bytes of storage space.</p>
<p>The <code>Twitter</code> (now <code>X</code>) began with 120 character limit.</p>
<p>Nearly 40,000 times difference between a digitized photo and a character based message.</p>
<p>This passage from the Book of Mormon seems to address a similar situation.</p>
<section id="mormon-chapter-9" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="mormon-chapter-9">Mormon Chapter 9</h3>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>32 And now, behold, we have written this record according to our knowledge, in the characters which are called among us the reformed Egyptian, being handed down and altered by us, according to our manner of speech.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>33 And if our plates had been sufficiently large we should have written in Hebrew; but the Hebrew hath been altered by us also; and if we could have written in Hebrew, behold, ye would have had no imperfection in our record.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Which codec (tools that will code and decode electronically or digitally), tools will survive.</p>
<p>The best way is to implant messages or thoughts in our minds and hearts. Without using any external means.</p>
<p>However, in the absence of the implanting method and with limited and deteriorating memories, I need to choose which medium and method.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="years-in-korea" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="years-in-korea">4 years in Korea</h2>
<p>Of our 4 children that learned Korean, only 1 didn’t remember it after returning to America.</p>
<p>The youngest never learned the written language.</p>
<p>Therefore, even though his speaking ability was developed, he soon forgot when he joined the American school system.</p>
<p>While it is true that images and videos carry the message far more efficiently, there is an advantage of learning and conveying message via written language or characters.</p>
<p>It is compact and can outlast any other formats for storing and retrieving information.</p>
<p>If the right medium is chosen.</p>
</section>
<section id="an-alternate-reason" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="an-alternate-reason">An alternate reason</h2>
<p>Nephi states,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>2 Yea, I make a record in the language of my father, which consists of the learning of the Jews and the language of the Egyptians.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>3 And I know that the record which I make is true; and I make it with mine own hand; and I make it according to my knowledge.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>1 I, Nephi, having been born of goodly parents, therefore I was taught somewhat in all the learning of my father; and having seen many afflictions in the course of my days, nevertheless, having been highly favored of the Lord in all my days; yea, having had a great knowledge of the goodness and the mysteries of God, therefore I make a record of my proceedings in my days.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It unlikely that records will survive more than a generation.</p>
<p>But perhaps by remembering and recording events of my life. I will come to realize the goodness of the Lord and absolute faith of my parents.</p>
<p>That I was favored, protected and guided through this life.</p>
<p>In doing so, I hope to stay rooted in the faith of my parents.</p>
<p>Remembering that I am a temporal guest – a sojourner.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231204 Why Blog/main2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="technical-notes" class="level1">
<h1>Technical Notes</h1>
<p>A phone app that captures both audio recording and words are transcribed simultaneously.</p>
<p>MS Word has a dictation function and Google Docs has a voice typing feature.</p>
<section id="one-possible-workflow" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="one-possible-workflow">One Possible Workflow</h2>
<p>Write down the recollections on paper or iPad. OR Make an audio memo, send emails to myself. OR Use whatever tools are nearby to collect thoughts.</p>
<p>Gather above material as a text into a Google Docs. Google Docs provides an easy way to compile and convenience of multiple language</p>
</section>
<section id="multimedia-handling" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="multimedia-handling">Multimedia Handling</h2>
<p>Any digitized resource can be added and modified or enhanced by modern tools. Though raw or original state is preferred, there are times, one has to edit for clarity or to fix physical damages</p>
</section>
<section id="r-r-studio-and-quarto" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="r-r-studio-and-quarto">R, R Studio and Quarto</h2>
<p>Used for compiling, formatting and integrating based on the markdown tools.</p>
<p>Final product is uploaded to Github pages.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>technology</category>
  <category>memories</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231204 Why Blog/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231204 Why Blog/main1.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Family Gathering</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231202 Family Gathering/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Celebrated the first holiday, a wedding and a 돌잔치 (First Birthday Celebration) -- without my parents generation.</p>
<p>Within the last 3 years, first my father (2020), followed by my mother-in-law (2021), then my mother (2023), they left us.</p>
<p>Could no longer count on them to be there and guide us on what to do.</p>
<p>Felt alone as the holidays and events approached.</p>
<p>Where will we gather, who will be there?</p>
<p>How will we plan for these events?</p>
<p>Apprehension set in as the wedding date approached.</p>
<p>Did I contact enough people, will they be able to come the reception</p>
<p>What about 폐백 (幣帛), who will lead it?</p>
<p>I have only participated and watched the proceedings.</p>
<p>There had always been others with better, more complete knowledge.</p>
<p>What about the First Birthday Celebration?</p>
<p>Will I remember the sequence and arrangements for the 돌잔치, particularly 돌잡이.</p>
<p>Then I remembered a family gathering some 33 years ago.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231202 Family Gathering/main.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="that-gathering-at-木洞" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="that-gathering-at-木洞">That Gathering at 木洞</h2>
<p>Sister K and I were in Korea, with our first born, to meet her family for the first time.</p>
<p>Neither my father-in-law nor my mother-in-law came to the US for the wedding.</p>
<p>I was welcomed into their family and had a chance to meet the extended family.</p>
<p>In contrast to our small family that escaped from 북한 (北韓), Sister Ks family had lived in the same area for hundreds of years.</p>
<p>My parents and my sisters also came to Korea.</p>
<p>To celebrate the 80th Birthday of my grandmother Kim.</p>
<p>Also the 60th Birthday of my father.</p>
<p>As a bonus, our daughter celebrated her 100th day while in Korea.<sup>1</sup></p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231202 Family Gathering/grandma.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>This was before the Internet, before cell phones.</p>
<p>Don’t know how, but all guests were contacted, invited and came to the gathering</p>
<p>Chosen date was Sunday, August 26th.</p>
<p>The place was an apartment in 목동 (木洞) in Seoul.</p>
<p>This was my first time seeing my extended family in 16 years.</p>
<p>I was worried that there might be some distance after all those years.</p>
<p>My paternal grandmother had 4 sons and a daughter.</p>
<p>My maternal grandmother had a son and 4 daughters.</p>
<p>My father was the oldest and my mother was the oldest in her family.</p>
<p>Didn’t have to worry about people not recognizing me.</p>
<p>After living alone in US for nearly 2 decades it felt wonderful to be among those that knew who I was.</p>
<p>People came throughout the day.</p>
<p>No set time meant people came when it was convenient.</p>
<p>However, for the people in charge of the meal, it meant a new setting with a new arrival of family members.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231202 Family Gathering/food.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>My uncle became the de facto MC as he greeted and became the bridge between generations and among my father’s and my mother’s family and his wife’s family.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-family-entertainer" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-family-entertainer">The Family Entertainer</h2>
<p>This is the same uncle that moon lighted as a wanna be medicine salesman on the trains and buses, in his college days.</p>
<p>Everyone was encouraging him to perform.</p>
<p>Although he refused at first, by the afternoon, and after a few beers, he gave in.</p>
<p>He gave a 2-part performance.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231202 Family Gathering/mom.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<div class="callout callout-style-default callout-note callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
These files contains audio, may need to adjust volume accordingly.
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">

</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="audio-recording" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="audio-recording">Audio Recording</h2>
<figure class="figure">
<figcaption class="figure-caption">
Click to Listen
</figcaption>
<audio controls="" src="MedicineMan.mp3">
<p>Your browser does not support the <code>audio</code> element.</p>
</audio>
</figure>
<p>First act was pretending he was a factory direct sales man of 우황청심원 (牛黃淸心元) Medicine <sup>2</sup></p>
<p>He re-enacted a frantic scene of a baby crying, waking up from a dream.</p>
<p>A dream where he fell from a cliff.</p>
<p>Everyone is looking for medicine but none can be found.</p>
<p>There are watches and jewelry aplenty but no medicine can be found.</p>
<p>Then he would say, you would pay a lot more if this product was packaged and sold through the normal channel.</p>
<p>But today only, you can buy it for a special price of a few bucks.</p>
<p>The second routine was for him to relate how he became an orphan.</p>
<p>His father died while working as a 나무군<sup>3</sup>. From falling off a tree.</p>
<p>And his mom ran off with the neighborhood barber</p>
<p>So he would sing a sad song and do a simple trick and ask for a small donation to help him.</p>
<p>My mother, who witnessed this, confirmed that people actually applauded his performance and gave him money.</p>
<p>Not sure how much planning was involved and don’t know the budget for that event.</p>
<p>But it is an event that we all remembered.</p>
<p>Seeing our relatives again prompted my sister and I to find a way to go back to Korea.</p>
<p>My sister, who worked for Motorola, spent a year working in Korea.</p>
<p>I followed her and lived in Korea for a few years, starting in 1999.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231202 Family Gathering/parting.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<hr>
<p>I worried unnecessarily.</p>
<p>Though our parents didn’t leave a detailed instructions, they left us with enough personal demonstration for us to carry on the tradition</p>
<p>Including an approach that has worked for them</p>
<p>Prepare well and let higher power guide and help</p>
<p>As well as let the talents of others shine at events.</p>
<p>Because the wedding and 돌잔치 were within 10 days.</p>
<p>Most people took an extended vacation and stayed for the whole duration.</p>
<p>Some came from the East Coast, the West Coast, and some even Korea</p>
<p>Much like the combined events of 1990 — but even better organized and implemented.</p>
<p>Though small in number, didn’t feel alone</p>
<p>Young people did a much better job of implementation. The color and design were all updated and looked modern yet captured the essence of the occassion.</p>
<p>The cousin that MCed the 폐백 knew facts that older people had forgotten.</p>
<p>People came at the appointed hour, visited and made the event memorable.</p>
<p>Thanks to the the former generation for demonstrating how to organize a family gathering.</p>
<p>Thank you, the young generation, for researching, interpreting and making the tradition even better and making them your own.</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://encykorea.aks.ac.kr/Article/E0022291↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>https://namu.wiki/w/%EC%9A%B0%ED%99%A9%EC%B2%AD%EC%8B%AC%EC%9B%90↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>https://namu.wiki/w/%EB%82%98%EB%AC%B4%EA%BE%BC↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>gathering</category>
  <category>celebration</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231202 Family Gathering/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231202 Family Gathering/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Where Clouds Gather</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231118 Where Clouds Gather/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="korean-lyric-songs" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="korean-lyric-songs">Korean Lyric Songs</h2>
<p>At the beginning of marriage years, my cousin in Korea bought me a packet of 5 cassettes containing Korean Lyric Songs.</p>
<p>Lyric Songs are created by combining a poem with western style music. Most songs were developed during the early and mid 20th century</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231118 Where Clouds Gather/s-l1600.jpg" class="img-fluid" style="width:50.0%"> <img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231118 Where Clouds Gather/s-l1601.jpg" class="img-fluid" style="width:50.0%"></p>
<p>Each cassette contained about an hour of music. (a great planning to fit close to 30 minutes per side, but not to go over it)</p>
<p>During my 30s, this was my main playlist, listened mainly for the beautiful melodies.</p>
<p>Since accompanying lyrics were not readily available.</p>
<p>(I made a duplicate copy of Tape #4, fearing that I may wear out the tape).</p>
<hr>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231118 Where Clouds Gather/timp_clouds.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="clouds-in-nature-captured-in-photography" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="clouds-in-nature-captured-in-photography">Clouds in Nature: Captured in Photography</h2>
<p>Along with tracking sunrise and sunset times. A knowledge of moon rise and moon set times and their directions is helpful.</p>
<p>Less predictable but more impactful and more rewarding are the direction and amount of cloud coverage.</p>
<p>One starts looking for any signs of cloud coverage and formations. And if it happens about the time of sunrise and sunset, it is a bonus. Consistently without clouds, one would be tempted to learn Photoshop.</p>
</section>
<section id="clouds-challenges-and-trials-in-life" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="clouds-challenges-and-trials-in-life">Clouds (Challenges and Trials) in Life</h2>
<p>Asked Sister K lately,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Why is this life so difficult and full of challenges?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>She replied.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>It always has been and always will be, you just have become more aware due to recent events around you.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Mentally and theoretically, it is easy to understand and justify that challenges and trials are part of this life.</p>
<p>Emotionally and spiritually, however, the amount and timing seems overwhelming and more than one can bear.</p>
</section>
<section id="a-discussion-among-men" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-discussion-among-men">A discussion among men</h2>
<p>Last Sunday, a group men, about 50 in total met as a group. The age of the group spanned 70 decades</p>
<p>The topic of discussion was a passage from Doctrine and Covenants 59, verse 7</p>
<p><code>Thou shalt thank the Lord thy God in all things</code></p>
<p>A brother in his mid 80s suggested that he was not particularly grateful for the onset of dementia</p>
<p>The discussion leader then suggest the distinction between</p>
<p><code>Gratitude for</code> vs <code>Gratitude in</code></p>
<p>We are grateful for things that we have, that is the first step. However even when things are taken away, we are still grateful.</p>
<p>We are not grateful for dementia, but are grateful in dementia.</p>
<p>Although he was not mentioned during the 40-minute long discussion, thought of Job, Chapter 19.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>v25 For I know that my redeemer liveth, and that he shall stand at the latter day upon the earth:</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>v26 And though after my skin worms destroy this body, yet in my flesh shall I see God:</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Everything, even friends and family were taken from Job. Yet he thanked or praised God and placed his trust in him.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231118 Where Clouds Gather/main2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="korean-lyric-song-저-구름-흘러가는-곳" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="korean-lyric-song-저-구름-흘러가는-곳">Korean Lyric Song: 저 구름 흘러가는 곳</h2>
<p>Been listening to this song, sung by a number of artists. It can be translated as, <code>That place where Clouds Gather</code></p>
<p>Each artist gave their unique interpretation.</p>
<p>However, I didn’t expect a version from Barbara Bonney. Back in 1998, she released an album entitle <code>Portrait</code><sup>1</sup> The first 5 songs were Korean Lyric Songs.</p>
<p>The 5th entry reads,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>저 구름 흘러가는 곳 Cho Gureum Huloganen Goht (김동진 / 김용호)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Grateful that we can hear this music sung and interpreted by artists in Korea and US.</p>
<p>Confirming that there are universal struggles that are contained in music and poems of each culture. Also an universal yearning to attain a place of peace and rest.</p>
<section id="barbara-sings-he-shall-feed-his-flock-from-handels-messiah" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="barbara-sings-he-shall-feed-his-flock-from-handels-messiah">Barbara sings “He shall feed his flock” from Handel’s ‘Messiah’</h3>
<div class="quarto-video"><iframe data-external="1" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l-bAXm-A3Ls" width="400" height="300" title="" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>
</section>
<section id="barbara-bonney-sings-저-구름-흘러가는-곳where-the-wind-blows" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="barbara-bonney-sings-저-구름-흘러가는-곳where-the-wind-blows">Barbara Bonney sings “저 구름 흘러가는 곳(Where the wind blows)”</h3>
<div class="quarto-video"><iframe data-external="1" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/C5RFATD0LXw" width="400" height="300" title="" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>
</section>
</section>
<section id="저-구름-흘러가는-곳" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="저-구름-흘러가는-곳">저 구름 흘러가는 곳</h2>
<p>저 구름 흘러가는 곳 아득한 먼 그곳 그리움도 흘러가라 파아란 싹이 트고 꽃들은 곱게 피어 날 오라 부르네 행복이 깃든 그 곳에 그리움도 흘러가라 저 구름 흘러가는 곳 이 가슴 깊이 불타는 영원한 나의 사랑 전할 곳 길은 멀어도 즐거움이 넘치는 나라 산을 넘고 바다를 건너 저 구름 흘러가는 곳 내 마음도 따라가라 그대를 만날 때까지 내 사랑도 흘러가라</p>
<p>저 구름 흘러가는 곳 가없는 하늘 위에 별빛도 흘러가라 황홀한 날이 와서 찬란한 보금자리 날 오라 부르네 쌓인 정 이룰 그곳에 별빛도 흘러가라 저 구름 흘러가는 곳 이 가슴 깊이 불타는 영원한 나의 사랑 전할 곳 길은 멀어도 즐거움이 넘치는 나라 산을 넘고 바다를 건너 저 구름 흘러가는 곳 내 마음도 따라가라 그대를 만날 때까지 내 사랑도 흘러가라</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231118 Where Clouds Gather/main1.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="that-place-where-the-clouds-are-flowing" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="that-place-where-the-clouds-are-flowing">That place where the clouds are flowing</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Translation Courtesy of Google</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That place where the clouds are flowing, far away The longing will pass and blue buds will sprout. The flowers bloom beautifully and call me to come Wherever happiness resides, let longing also flow. Where the clouds flow, this heart burns deep A place to convey my eternal love A country full of joy even though the road is long Cross the mountains and the sea Where the clouds flow, follow my heart too. Let my love flow until I meet you</p>
<p>Where the clouds flow, above the endless sky The starlight also flows by and an ecstatic day comes The brilliant nest calls me to come Let the starlight flow to the place where the accumulated affection will be fulfilled. Where the clouds flow, this heart burns deep A place to convey my eternal love A country full of joy even though the road is long Cross the mountains and the sea Where the clouds flow, follow my heart too. Let my love flow until I meet you</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231118 Where Clouds Gather/main4.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="the-place-where-those-clouds-flow" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-place-where-those-clouds-flow">The place where those clouds flow</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Translation by ChatGPT 3.5</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The place where those clouds flow, a distant and faraway place Let even the longing flow, and the blue sprouts grow The flowers bloom beautifully, calling for the day to come In that place where happiness resides, let even the longing flow The place where those clouds flow, deeply burning in my heart The eternal place to convey my love Though the road is long, it’s a land overflowing with joy Crossing mountains and seas To the place where those clouds flow, let my heart follow Until I meet you, let my love flow</p>
<p>The place where those clouds flow, above the boundless sky Let even the starlight flow, for the ecstatic day to come A brilliant sanctuary, calling for the day to come In that place where accumulated affections will come true, let even the starlight flow The place where those clouds flow, deeply burning in my heart The eternal place to convey my love Though the road is long, it’s a land overflowing with joy Crossing mountains and seas To the place where those clouds flow, let my heart follow Until I meet you, let my love flow</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231118 Where Clouds Gather/main3.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="that-place-where-clouds-gather" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="that-place-where-clouds-gather">That Place : Where Clouds Gather</h2>
<p>That place where clouds drifts and flows<br>
The longing will gather to it also</p>
<p>The place of a new birth and flowers blooming.<br>
It is calling me home.</p>
<p>That place of happiness, the destiny, of longing.</p>
<p>That place where clouds drifts and flows</p>
<p>The yearning of hearts burns with desire.</p>
<p>That place, of happiness, for eternal love is far<br>
Over mountains and oceans.</p>
<p>That place where clouds drifts and flows<br>
My heart and longings will follow</p>
<p>Till we meet, my love will flow and drift<br>
To that place where clouds drift and flow.</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>http://daihanmusic.co.kr/Item/ItemInfo?ITEM_CD=9620079081239↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>memories</category>
  <category>technology</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231118 Where Clouds Gather/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20231118 Where Clouds Gather/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Assisted Living</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230920 Assisted Living/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Thought Nurse Beth had just reported to work.<br>
Turns out she was finishing up her 12-hour shift and was headed home.</p>
<p>She still had enough energy to fuel or recharge at least 2 persons.<br>
And with that energy, she radiated love for not only the patient but for all in the room.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Can that level of warmth be obtained through training?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>She lifted others by listening to and complementing afterwards those in the room.</p>
<p>Although I was a visitor that day, I had been lifted.</p>
<p>Specifically, given a booster to, overcome and heal from doubts about life that I may have had or will have in the future.</p>
<hr>
<section id="section" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="section"><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230920 Assisted Living/main3.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></h2>
<p>There are certain modern phrases that are initially shunned, then accepted and eventually fully embraced.</p>
<p>One such phrase is <code>assisted living</code>.</p>
<p>Initially, the word and the concept behind it, is alien and is only applicable to others.</p>
<p>Because it seems like contradictory terms. You are either living or are assisted, but not at the same time.</p>
<p>3 experiences helped me accept and embrace it.</p>
</section>
<section id="tuesdays-with-morrie" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="tuesdays-with-morrie">Tuesdays with Morrie</h2>
<p>During my traveling days, one of the hotel chains had a free book campaign. Take a book, read it, return it, if you are in the neighborhood.</p>
<p>Some memorable lines from the book,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>The culture we have doesn’t make people feel good about themselves. We are teaching the wrong things. You have to be strong enough to say, if the culture doesn’t work, don’t use it. Create your own culture.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Which side wins?</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Love wins, love always wins</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The story made me re-evaluate my career-centric ways.</p>
<p>Coincidentally, I headed back home, from the expat assignment, within 2 years of reading that book.</p>
</section>
<section id="a-co-worker-with-als" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-co-worker-with-als">A Co-worker with ALS</h2>
<p>K was head of the Payroll Group, C was her assistant.<br>
I had my cubicle outside of their office.</p>
<p>K was diagnosed with ALS<sup>1</sup>. She was assisted by C.</p>
<p>I never suspected K was ill, because she was always cheerful.</p>
<p>Recall that Halloween when K chose to wear a home-made NY Yankees jersey. It was Lou Gehrig’s uniform.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230920 Assisted Living/IMG_8144_crop.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>We became closer as we shared notes and talked about our sons on missions. Her’s to Riverside, California learning Mandarin, mine to Fukuoka, Japan.</p>
<p>Recall the ice bucket challenge hosted by the R&amp;D Group.<br>
Its group leader also battle ALS.</p>
<p>Later on C had to help K. More than office duties.</p>
<p>Even though K could have stayed home, she still came to work a few times a week.</p>
<p>5 years ago this month, K passed away at age 53. Grateful for examples from K and C.</p>
<p>(Years later, K’s daughter and C’s son married each other)</p>
</section>
<section id="watching-parents-experience-assisted-living-with-dignity" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="watching-parents-experience-assisted-living-with-dignity">Watching parents experience assisted living with dignity</h2>
<p>My parents and Sister K’s parents have all passed away</p>
<p>Each endured and was assisted during their latter days. Cycle of a visit to doctors and hospitals, followed by a stay at the rehabilitation place.</p>
<p>Their individual experiences varied, but they did share one common attribute.</p>
<p>They all bore their sufferings with dignity.</p>
<p>They lived a full life and showed us how to deal with physical ailments and aging bodies.</p>
<p>And I believe there were loved ones, sustaining and comforting, on both sides of life and death.</p>
<p>They chose living, even if it meant assisted living.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“But there was no need to be ashamed of tears, for tears bore witness that a man had the greatest of courage, the courage to suffer.”<br>
― Viktor E. Frankl, Man’s Search for Meaning</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230920 Assisted Living/main2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"> It is easier to think that assisted living applies 2 extremes of our lives.</p>
<p>When we are born until we are independent.<br>
And when we stop being independent to when we die</p>
<p>Then one realizes that it is, and always will be an assisted living in this life.</p>
<p>We are never fully alone, assisted by both seen and unseen.</p>
<p>Always feeling the presence of help nearby.</p>
<hr>
<p>It is our task to be more like Morrie the Professor, K, and our parents.</p>
<p>As Professor Morrie stated,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>To give to the world what we possess.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And be present and lift others as Nurse Beth did that night at the <code>Honor Health Scottsdale</code>.</p>
<p>That is the essence of life.</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>service</category>
  <category>healing</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230920 Assisted Living/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230920 Assisted Living/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>15 Years of Memory</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230916 15 Year Memory/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Went through 65 video tapes<sup>1</sup>, containing family or home recordings.</p>
<p>These recordings contain the first 15 years of a married life, arrival of children and visits with family members and visits to places in the US and abroad.</p>
<p>The Analog to Digital transfer took over 200 hours.<sup>2</sup></p>
<p>After viewing, editing, digitizing, and uploading these memories, this is a summary of lessons learned.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Not Where or What, but Who<br>
Not When or How, but Now</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230916 15 Year Memory/main.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="but-who" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="but-who">But Who</h2>
<p>Before starting, I imagined I would save, some of the well known places, in the video.</p>
<p>However, very few images of places or things were saved into the digital format, they were not that interesting anymore.</p>
<p>The Great Wall, The Vatican, The Eiffel Tower, to name a few.</p>
<p>Yes they are marvels of human achievement, but if I decided to visit them next month, they will still be there.</p>
<p>But the scenes with the people – I kept.</p>
<p>Those that I lived, worked or traveled with are no longer here or are living far away or have grown up.</p>
<p>Those scenes with a familiar people were captured and shared.</p>
<p>There were several instances, where forgotten moments and unexpected guests appeared on the screen.</p>
<p>One such event was a 1-year birthday celebration at the Wymount Terrace.</p>
<p>People were squeezed to a 143 square feet space, it was difficult to recognize, due to low resolution, but there were faces that recognized and I haven’t seen in decades.</p>
<p>People accepting and taking a moment from their schedule to participate.</p>
<p>Making memory for the parent and the child, even though the child is seen crying because of the heavy, uncomfortable costume.</p>
</section>
<section id="but-now" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="but-now">But Now</h2>
<p>It was wonderful to see our parents age through their 60s, 70s and 80s with vibrancy – finally slowing down in their late 80s.</p>
<p>Setting a model for us to follow.</p>
<hr>
<p>11 month old child is about to fall again, but he takes another step. Siblings are cheering, mom and dad are extending their hands. The child smiles as he takes one step after another.</p>
<p>When children are little and they are trying something new, everyone encourages him or her. As they grow older, not as much attention, attempting something more noble.</p>
<hr>
<p>Greatness and beauty are made and captured little by little, some captured on digital medium but most are captured in hearts and minds of individuals that have been touched and served with love.</p>
<p>Life is a wonderful gift.</p>
<p>Can be experienced near or far, preferably near.<br>
Either now or in the future, rather to be enjoyed while young.<br>
To be shared with those that are near - now.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230916 15 Year Memory/STA_0518-PANO.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>a magnetic tape-based 8mm videocassette↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Analog to Digital transfer is a real time process, and conversion from DV format to MP4 format takes roughly 2X times. 2 minutes of DV video takes about 4 to 5 minutes to convert to MP4 format↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>memories</category>
  <category>technology</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230916 15 Year Memory/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230916 15 Year Memory/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Forgotten Season and Dream</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230831 Forgotten Dreams/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>There is a song, all adults in Korea over 50, can sing from memory.</p>
<p>Its refrain says</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>언제나 돌아오는 계절은 나에게 꿈을 주지만<br>
이룰 수 없는 꿈은 슬퍼요 나를 울려요</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Each season brings a renewed cycle of hopes and dreams</em><br>
<em>However, unrealizable dreams are inconsolable and bring tears.</em></p>
<p>The song is about past romance, separation, and regular remembrance during each fall.</p>
<p>At one level of interpretation.</p>
<p>When young, almost all events and songs can be related to and viewed in terms of relationships - both good and meaningful – ones that endure and those that end abruptly.</p>
<p>However, the expectation is that seasons and times will return and repeat, indefinitely.</p>
<p>For those that have lived a half-century or more, this inevitability sets in with force – the realization that there are finite cycles of seasons left.</p>
<p>Not necessarily because of the ordinal age but because life places and sets in motion a number of markers and reminders.</p>
<p>More dependent on the younger generation, mentally, emotionally and physically.</p>
<p>Loss of hope for the future, that things will get better is no longer believed or pursued.</p>
<p>The reduction in self-reliance and independence due to these surges can have a significant impact on one’s long term outlook and the day to day well being.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230831 Forgotten Dreams/main.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>About 5 years after that melancholy song was released, another group proclaimed the following</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>우리 타는 가슴 가슴마다 햇살은 다시 떠오르네.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Within our burning bosom, rises another source of light.</em></p>
<p>Later verses state,</p>
<p><em>I have another act to perform in my life,</em> <em>Even though I stand on the edge of wind-blown field, I am not lonely</em> <em>Yet, when a pine needle falls, my tears follow.</em> <em>With our changeless love for another, I will lift those in need by lending a helping hand</em></p>
<p>Mercifully, as years go on, goals and relationships are either adjusted downward or allowed to fade from our memories.</p>
<p>In coming days and years, I may vacillate among melancholic remembrance of past relationships, missed opportunities and abandoned dreams.</p>
<p>However, each day, I will believe, reach for and rely on the strength of individual and collective human will to continue and overcome.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230831 Forgotten Dreams/main2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="forgotten-season-잊혀진-계절" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="forgotten-season-잊혀진-계절">Forgotten Season (잊혀진 계절)</h2>
<p>지금도 기억하고 있어요 시월의 마지막 밤을<br>
뜻모를 이야기만 남긴채 우리는 헤어졌어요<br>
그날의 쓸쓸했던 표정이 그대의 진실인가요<br>
한마디 변명도 못하고 잊혀져야 하는 건가요<br>
언제나 돌아오는 계절은 나에게 꿈을 주지만<br>
이룰 수 없는 꿈은 슬퍼요 나를 울려요</p>
<p>I still remember the last night of October<br>
We broke up leaving only meaningless stories behind<br>
Is the lonely expression of that day your truth?<br>
Can’t even make a single excuse, should I be forgotten?<br>
The seasons that always return give me dreams<br>
Dreams that can’t come true are sad, they make me cry</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/fMmgz5RS0RE?si=whG6B6Usp4uvLj6l">A Link to the Song</a></p>
</section>
<section id="with-love-사랑으로" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="with-love-사랑으로">With Love (사랑으로)</h2>
<p>내가 살아가는 동안에 할일이 또 하나 있지<br>
바람부는 벌판에 서 있어도 나는 외롭지 않아.</p>
<p>그러나 솔잎 하나 떨어지면 눈물따라 흐르고<br>
우리 타는 가슴 가슴마다 햇살은 다시 떠오르네.</p>
<p>아 영원히 변치 않을 우리들의 사랑으로<br>
어두운 곳에 손을 내밀어 밝혀 주리라.</p>
<p>while i live I have one more thing to do<br>
Even if I’m standing in a windy field I’m not alone.</p>
<p>But if one pine needle falls flowing with tears<br>
Each of our burning hearts the sun rises again</p>
<p>Oh, with our love that will never change<br>
I will reach out my hand in a dark place and shed light on it<sup>1</sup>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uuJ-SCwk7Z0">A Link to the Song</a></p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>translation by Google Translate↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>remembrace</category>
  <category>hope</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230831 Forgotten Dreams/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230831 Forgotten Dreams/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Korean War : 1950 - 1953</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Remembrance of past events is beneficial – even without a personal witness and its clarification and interpretation.</p>
<p>Without my father’s personal recollection, however, the Korean War remembrance is unfocused and its significance reduced.</p>
<p><a href="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230530%20Reunite/">past Korean War remembrance</a></p>
<p>In a previous post, I pleaded with God for a single, united nation under God. South Korea and North Korea becoming one nation.</p>
<p>That is no longer my wish.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/main.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<hr>
<p>The 70th Anniversary of cessation of hostility in Korea has re-invigorated the idea of Peace Treaty that will replace the Armistice Treaty signed on 27 July 1953.</p>
<p>An internet search of key words <code>Korea Peace Treaty</code> yielded the following.</p>
<p>Pope Francis through Korean emissary, Cardinal Lazzaro You Heung-sik, wished for peace on the Korean Peninsula.<sup>1</sup></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>In this way, I trust that the marking of the armistice will point not only to the cessation of hostilities but to a bright future of reconciliation, fraternity and enduring harmony for the Korean Peninsula, and indeed the wider world,</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Reporter Iris Kim writes in <code>NBC News</code> <sup>2</sup></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>The U.S. has a moral responsibility to finally end the war</p>
</blockquote>
<p>World Council of Churches (WCC) stated,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>… a formal declaration of the end of the Korean War “could be a powerful circuit-breaker and catalyst for peace.”<sup>3</sup></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Congresswoman, Young Kim,<sup>4</sup> writes an article in <code>Foreign Policy</code>, <strong>A Korean Peace Treaty Would Be an Unforced Blunder</strong></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>The big problem here is that North Korea has consistently failed to abide by previous attempts to make peace on the Korean Peninsula<sup>5</sup></p>
</blockquote>
<p>While these are timely and necessary reminders, repetition will not result in a breakthrough.</p>
<hr>
<p>Rather than wishing for a peace or unified country, I will ask for a new freedom for people in North Korea and continued protection of freedom for South Koreans.</p>
<p>That will result in a people that are re-united with their God.</p>
<p>People of Israel was in bondage for over 100 years. Rabbi Dovid Rosenfeld estimates,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>the (Egyptian) slavery lasted somewhere between 86 and 116 years.<sup>6</sup></p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>How much longer do Koreans in Northern Korea must endure their bondage?</li>
</ul>
<p>Furthermore, after wandering in the wilderness for 40 years nearly all died.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Every Israelite over twenty years of age when they left Egypt under Moses’ leadership was now dead, except for three people: Moses, Joshua, and Caleb (see Numbers 14:38).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>My father was 20 years old when the Korean War began.</p>
<p>He and others, both from North and South Korea as well as United Nations Command and China, served their nations and its people.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/landscape.png" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">Korean War Casualties<sup>7</sup></figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>They all served the cause or ideologies of their countries. For this we thank them.</p>
<div id="fig-medals" class="quarto-layout-panel">
<figure class="figure">
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell quarto-layout-cell-subref" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div id="fig-8876" class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center anchored">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/IMG_8876.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img" data-ref-parent="fig-medals"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">(a) 8876</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell quarto-layout-cell-subref" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div id="fig-3648" class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center anchored">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/IMG_3648.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img" data-ref-parent="fig-medals"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">(b) 3648</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell quarto-layout-cell-subref" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div id="fig-3651" class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center anchored">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/IMG_3651.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img" data-ref-parent="fig-medals"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">(c) 3651</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell quarto-layout-cell-subref" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div id="fig-0360" class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center anchored">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/IMG_0360.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img" data-ref-parent="fig-medals"></p>
<figcaption class="figure-caption">(d) 0360</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Figure&nbsp;1: Dad’s Medals of Appreciation from the Korean Government</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Within 20 years, those that were old enough to remember the War (older than 10 years of age in 1950) will reach 100 years age.</p>
<p>My generation remembers stories and lessons of the war, but it is fading.</p>
<ul>
<li>What would be a benefit of a united nation if no one has common experience and no binding ideology?</li>
</ul>
<p>God has performed miracles on behalf of people of Korea.<br>
That will continue – in His timeline.</p>
<p>God has led our family out of bondage and harms way a number of times.<br>
We will continue to praise and serve Him.</p>
<p>The re-uniting of families in Korea will occur in manner and in time designated by God.</p>
<p>But if we could ask for a wish or two, like Alma.<sup>8</sup></p>
<ul>
<li>Would it be possible for missionaries to re-enter both North and South Korea and hearts will be re-united with their God and their people</li>
<li>Would it be unrealistic to ask for a religious gathering starting in PyongYang on the anniversary of the War or the Armistice Treaty Signing?</li>
</ul>
<p>The message of truth, the Good News, will enable freedom to return to the Korean Peninsula and remain.</p>
<p>Free people of God will then organize a form of government and establish an economy that will both strengthen and enrich both people and the country.</p>
<p>This is my revised wish.</p>
<p>July 2023</p>
<p>Son of a North Korean Christian Family</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://www.koreaherald.com/view.php?ud=20230727000764#:~:text=%22In%20this%20way%2C%20I%20trust,wider%20world%2C%22%20it%20added.↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>https://www.nbcnews.com/news/asian-america/70-years-later-koreans-are-still-working-formally-end-korean-war-rcna96209↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>https://www.oikoumene.org/news/wcc-stands-in-hope-with-korean-peninsula-during-conference-marking-70th-anniversary-of-armistice-agreement↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn4"><p>the representative for Calfornia’s 40th Congressional District and chairwoman of the Indo-Pacific Subcommittee of the U.S. House Foreign Affairs Committee↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn5"><p>https://foreignpolicy.com/2023/07/27/north-south-korea-peace-war-treaty-armistice-united-states/↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn6"><p>https://aish.com/duration-of-slavery-in-egypt/↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn7"><p>https://www.britannica.com/event/Korean-War↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn8"><p>Alma Chapter 29↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>remembrance</category>
  <category>resolve</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230727 Korean War Remembrance/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Maryland Carrollton Ward</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230705 New Carrollton/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>The year was 1969, my dad and his friends were wrapping up their employment with RMK-BRJ consortium in Vietnam.</p>
<p>Having experienced overseas living they wanted to work elsewhere and explored opportunities outside of Korea.</p>
<p>They consider such countries as, Brazil, Australia, Canada, and Japan – Kyushu area in particular.</p>
<p>But they all decided they’d rather go to United States</p>
<p>The remaining question was where in the United States.</p>
<p>They looked at a map and one person suggested that they should live near the capitol city – Washington DC</p>
<p>The reasoning was that there will be more cultural opportunities near Washington DC.</p>
<p>Some of these friends have grown up together since early childhood back in Won San<sup>1</sup></p>
<p>They fought in the war together, they worked together after the war and they came to Vietnam to work together.</p>
<p>Now they planned to immigrate to United States with their families.</p>
<p>My father would start the next phase of his life in Greenbelt, Maryland – He was 44.</p>
<section id="searching-for-an-american-religion" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="searching-for-an-american-religion">Searching for an American Religion</h2>
<p>When my father returned home in April of 1970 he noticed there were missionaries.</p>
<p>They were street contacting near one of the rotaries (roundabouts) in Incheon.</p>
<p>Since he had interest in overseas living, he invited them home.</p>
<p>But he had no interest in religion.</p>
<p>However my mom did, she would study with the missionaries for two years.</p>
<p>She studied and prayed.</p>
<p>After receiving a personal revelation and listening to visiting Elder Harold B Lee speak she was convinced of the truth.</p>
<p>She and three of her children were baptized in May of 1971 (Eastern Branch)</p>
<p>My father delayed his study and conversion.</p>
<p>His primary focus was moving the family to the US.</p>
<p>After a few setbacks, he finally attained work visa to United States in February/March of 1974.</p>
<p>He soon left for the United States and our family joined him on the 29th of April 1974.</p>
<p>Even though my parents didn’t express it at the time, life as an immigrant in their 40s was not easy.</p>
<p>Not only work but the language was a burden that the first generation immigrants had to bear.</p>
<p>They endured their lot as immigrants knowing that their children will have far better opportunities.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230705 New Carrollton/main.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<hr>
<p>So what seemed like a random decision, choosing to work and live in Maryland turned out to be a tremendous blessing for our family.</p>
<p>We had more cultural and as an added bonus, more religious opportunities.</p>
<p>Washington DC Temple was open to public and dedicated the year we arrived.</p>
<hr>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>What is a successful immigrant family? Had we gone elsewhere, what would have the outcome? What was unique about Maryland Silver Spring Stake?</p>
</blockquote>
</section>
<section id="immigrant-success" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="immigrant-success">Immigrant Success</h2>
<p>Open AI defines a successful immigrant families as those that &gt; …have achieved personal and socio-economic prosperity in their adopted homeland</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Integration and Adaptation</li>
<li>Education and Professional Development</li>
<li>Economic Stability and Entrepreneurship</li>
<li>Cultural Preservation and Integration</li>
<li>Social and Civic Engagement</li>
<li>Strong Family Bonds</li>
</ol>
<p>Not sure how our lives would have been if we didn’t go to Washington DC area as a family.</p>
<p>Our parents would have made sure we survived the initial stages as a new arrivals.</p>
<p>Based on those traits listed, we did OK, because we were among Saints.</p>
<p>In addition knowing that I needed extra help. We were sent to the Carrollton Ward.</p>
<hr>
<p>I remember going to school and because I knew no English how was the sign several teachers so that I could catch up.</p>
<p>One of them was Sister J, the wife of the Bishop. Furthermore, that Bishop’s son served in Korea. He came home and taught my father and baptized him.</p>
<p>I struggled through school years, like most young people. Having friends in and support from the church kept me going and kept me out of trouble.</p>
<hr>
<p>Going on a mission was something that was discussed nor encouraged at home.</p>
<p>Grateful for those that encouraged and supported me.</p>
<p>I left my mission on January 1983</p>
<p>Grateful all of the families that I got to meet in Maryland</p>
<p>Invited me to scout camps, summer camps to Goshen, VA, young men young women activities, .</p>
<p>Especially memorable and transformational event was in 1980, a gathering of young people from all over eastern seaboard.</p>
<p>Men were kept in Ferrum College, women in Radford.</p>
<p>For someone that hadn’t traveled much out of Washington DC, southwestern VA did seem like ‘almost heaven.’</p>
<p>People were equally nice.</p>
<p>Newly elected Orrin Hatch and Young Women President Cannon were keynote speakers.</p>
<p>What an event, it made me realize I was part of something big</p>
<hr>
<p>Now those families have moved back to their home in the West.</p>
<p>Mostly to Utah, Idaho and Arizona.</p>
<p>Grateful for those families that have helped me during those memorable years, 1974 to 1983.</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Won San is some 150 miles northeast of Seoul, in area that is called North Korea↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>kindess</category>
  <category>church</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230705 New Carrollton/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230705 New Carrollton/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Opportunitites Will Come</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230704 Seek Opportunity/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Don’t go looking for opportunities, they will come looking for you</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That was the parting, reassuring statement from my manager as I ended the 4 year assignment in Korea.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, things didn’t happen as he predicted. I had to look for and apply to opportunities since those words were spoken 20 years ago.</p>
<p>Experiences gained during those ensuing years have taught me these alternate interpretations.</p>
<ul>
<li>You have done something significant for you and the company, and we appreciate it.</li>
<li>You have skills that are well suited for this and similar roles.</li>
<li>Opportunities, is it defined by us, the company or by God?</li>
</ul>
<section id="opportunities-a-company-perspective" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="opportunities-a-company-perspective">Opportunities : A Company Perspective</h2>
<p>Early in my career, first 5 or 6 years, I was bound to my office.</p>
<p>Never attended a seminar, a conference or visited a manufacturing location outside of Utah.</p>
<p>Then in 1997, a colleague invited me to travel to Suzhou (苏州, 蘇州).</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230704 Seek Opportunity/suzhou1.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>We were to transfer a set of equipment that make catheters.</p>
<p>For the next 10 years, I would travel extensively.</p>
<p>Also the company asked me to live abroad and help with acquisition and transition of Korean Medical Device companies.</p>
<p>The arrangement was mutually beneficial.</p>
<p>I was providing a service that was in demand, a knowledge of local language and culture plus the knowledge of specific set of catheter manufacturing knowledge.</p>
<p>At some point, I made a mistake of thinking that companies exist to serve my needs.</p>
<p>It is the other way around.</p>
</section>
<section id="opportunities-a-life-long-persepective" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="opportunities-a-life-long-persepective">Opportunities : A life-long Persepective</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Was the manager incorrect in saying that opportunities will come?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Similar to company/individual relationship that can be defined as life’s opportunities, Rabbi Manis Friedman provides another perspective.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>We do not have needs, God does. and He has a plan.<br>
He will use us, rather, we will partner with God<br>
To achieve purposes of our creation</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230704 Seek Opportunity/temple.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Since the assertion by that manager, there has been a number of set-backs and disappointments, but were they actually opportunities?</p>
<ul>
<li>How should I view/accept my recent role, working with the Japanese team?</li>
<li>Was it to fulfill my needs or did I partner with God in any degree?</li>
<li>How many opportunities were lost, not even considered, because I was inward focused?</li>
</ul>
<p>The opportunity, as we define it in terms of our needs, may not come along.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230704 Seek Opportunity/kamakura.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>However, other forms or representations, that are in effect opportunities will be available.</p>
<p>These may start out as educational training, conference attendances, a reminder from a family member, a message from a friend, an invitation to join a team by a former colleague.</p>
<p>Therefore, by seeking the needs of God and understanding His plan, we can educate ourselves and make ourselves more suited for that role.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Can we just fast forward or skip to the next opportunities – Us</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Please give me a moment, let me check what we agreed to – God</p>
</blockquote>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>opportunities</category>
  <category>goodness of fit</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230704 Seek Opportunity/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230704 Seek Opportunity/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Canyons : Near and Far</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>I live close to a location with both a nondescript and a pedestrian name.</p>
<p>That aptly named place was accessible for nearly 40 years.</p>
<p>During those years, it was like a National Park hours away, for I visited it once a year or less.</p>
<p>I rediscovered it recently.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/flora2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>For most of those years, I was commuting to Salt Lake Valley - over a 30-mile commute.</p>
<p>A change in job to a Utah Valley location meant the commuting time spent in cars or trains/buses can be replaced by a number of activities.</p>
<p>I followed a suggestion on a website<sup>1</sup>.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>The canyon…draws thousands of people annually who seek recreation, renewal, and inspiration. It is one of the few remaining “URBAN FORESTS” in the United States</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A few times that I hiked the area, I was not impressed.</p>
<p>Aside from a few geological features, the trail was unremarkable.</p>
<p>I usually went after the sun had risen, during the summer months.</p>
<p>Afterwards, I concluded that an hour or two spent in the canyon or the forest was not worth it.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/flora1.jpeg" class="img-fluid"> Then I switched the hiking hours so that I could visit the area in the morning and still be at work</p>
<p>That meant an adjustment to the sleeping schedule.</p>
<p>The early morning hours highlighted peaks, fauna, and flora that I hadn’t noticed before.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/fauna.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>As I began to notice the small changes in the surroundings, I began to track and follow not only the sunrise and sunset information but also the moonrise and moonset data.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/moon.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>It was almost like being transported to a different location in a time capsule – and back invigorated.</p>
<p>Those trips offered visual and aural as well as tactile experiences</p>
<p>The time spent in that capsule filtered and cleared my thoughts.<br>
It allowed me to forget things I should not hold onto.<br>
Lightened my mind and my burden.</p>
<p>I have experienced some of the more established, crowd-inviting locations with more exotic offerings.</p>
<p>But it was very difficult to experience its unique offerings during the peak visiting hours with all the other guests.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/sun.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I have to agree with Mark, Mark Twain.</p>
<p>I didn’t realize I lived next door to a National Park named Rock Canyon.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>When I was a boy of fourteen, my father was so ignorant I could hardly stand to have the old man around. But when I got to be twenty-one, I was astonished at how much he had learned in seven years. – Mark Twain</p>
</blockquote>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://www.rockcanyonutah.com/↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>tales from RC</category>
  <category>renewal</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230701 Canyons/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Father’s Day 2023</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230624 Fathers Day 2023/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>There are times, during the summer, when holidays seem to run together.<br>
Each year the meaning and purpose for the celebration seem less clear.</p>
<p>Father’s Day is one of those.</p>
<p>According to Wikipedia, Father’s Day<sup>1</sup> is</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>… a holiday honoring one’s father, or relevant father figure, as well as fatherhood, paternal bonds, and the influence of fathers in society.</p>
</blockquote>
<section id="a-physical-yearly-gift" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-physical-yearly-gift">A Physical, Yearly Gift</h2>
<p>At the entrance to the church meeting hall, there were beautifully wrapped 6” cookies for all the fathers.</p>
<p>There were several scores of cookies on display</p>
<p>The individual that made these used a lot ingredients and took a long time to bake these.</p>
<p>A store bought cookies would have sufficed but the effort was certainly appreciated.</p>
<p>Thank you Sister S., the RS President</p>
<p>Receiving gift always improves one’s outlook on life.</p>
<p>Then came the spiritual gift from Sister H.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230624 Fathers Day 2023/main.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="a-spiritual-gift" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-spiritual-gift">A Spiritual Gift</h2>
<p>She didn’t grow up with a father, since her parents divorced when she was 3.</p>
<p>Her mother remarried when Sister H was a teenager.</p>
<p>During those years, her father figure was her grandfather.</p>
<p>She described a time when her grandfather went to a function that would be attended by fathers and daughters.</p>
<p>She described her giving a talk about fathers as a blind person explaining an art work.</p>
<p>But she talked to a number of her friends, not just one or two, to gather a set of traits of fathers.</p>
<p>Those traits that are manifested in our earthly father but those also reflects our celestial heritage.</p>
<p>Fathers,</p>
<ul>
<li><p>are to provide, including safety.</p></li>
<li><p>are there, their presence is important</p></li>
<li><p>are examples of long-suffering and are patient</p></li>
<li><p>have a perfect love for the children</p></li>
<li><p>teaches about the divine nature</p></li>
<li><p>don’t judge</p></li>
<li><p>just love those around him</p></li>
<li><p>don’t talk about Jesus, but be like Jesus</p></li>
</ul>
<p>Listening to these traits, I recognized that I have failed to grasp many of these, especially the last one about <code>…be like Jesus</code></p>
<p>However, my father in his own way and throughout 6 decades, exemplified many if not all of these traits.</p>
<p>Thank you dad.</p>
</section>
<section id="a-generational-gift" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-generational-gift">A Generational Gift</h2>
<p>Back in the mid 1980s, Brother L. gave a talk as part of a ward Christmas devotional, at Carrollton, Maryland.</p>
<p>I was a newly returned missionary at the time, home from school.</p>
<p>My world view consisted of information filtered through TV news, radio broadcasts, and the Washington Post. And what we discussed and lived as an immigrant family.</p>
<p>My father was in his 50s.</p>
<p>I didn’t fully understand nor appreciate the impact of what Brother L. was saying.</p>
<p>Brother L. had far greater access to information and trends as a University Professor.</p>
<p>I don’t recall all of the supporting evidence he presented but he mentioned,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Fathers are an endangered group in the United States of America.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230624 Fathers Day 2023/dad.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="a-steady-foundation" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-steady-foundation">A Steady Foundation</h2>
<p>Since then I have reflected on his observations.</p>
<p>I have a far greater appreciation for his message.<br>
And for my own father.</p>
<p>He espoused and demonstrated the role and the traits of the father .</p>
<p>For many years my father worked in a hazardous environment.<br>
But I don’t recall him complaining or wishing that he had a different role.<br>
I think he was happy to provide for the family.<br>
At the same time wishing that we realized a better living condition for ourselves and our children.</p>
<p>Thank you Sisters S and H for the cookies and the Father’s Day message.<br>
Thank you Brother L. for planting a thought that kept me thinking all these years.</p>
<p>Thank you Dad for providing all the earthly goods and means for our success.</p>
<p>For demonstrating Father’s traits and emulating the One.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230624 Fathers Day 2023/mom.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Events, gestures, and a remembrance made me realize that remembering our fathers, relevant father figures, paternal bonds, and fatherhood is still important and should be celebrated more often.</p>
<p>It is a society’s way of remembering and celebrating ones that nurtured and guided us, by setting aside a special day.</p>
<p>However, whenever we pause and remember them and renew our dedication for this life, we are celebrating and remembering our mothers and fathers.</p>
<p>Looking forward to the coming days and to next year’s celebration of both Mother’s Day, Father’s Day and all the other summer holidays.</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Father%27s_Day↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>appreciation</category>
  <category>remebrance</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230624 Fathers Day 2023/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230624 Fathers Day 2023/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Anti Social Beginning</title>
  <dc:creator>DK </dc:creator>
  <link>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>We wanted a Japanese person for the role<br>
We would have accepted an American project leader<br>
But a Korean person that doesn’t drink!?!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Thus began my 6 year assignment to coordinate a production line transfer from Fukuroi(袋井市), Japan to Utah and Texas.</p>
<p>Wondered,</p>
<p>What happened to the description of Japanese people that I had studied prior to the visit.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Japanese people are polite, shy, kind and most of the time indirect in communications.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This was not the beginning I had imagined.</p>
<p>After an 12 hour flight to Narita(成田市), we were on our way to Tokyo via Narita Express (NEX).</p>
<p>With that declaration, he single-handedly shook my confidence, as well as stirred national differences that I had not considered.</p>
<p>[For this role, I had been interviewed by a Director of R&amp;D, the VP of R&amp;D, and the President of Technology. They agreed that I could do this. I wanted this role, and believed that this was an opportunity that my previous manager predicted.]</p>
<p>Thought of going back home, crossed my mind, if there was a convenient way and if my Director and the VP hadn’t accompanied me</p>
<p>However, relying on past human relationship lessons<sup>1</sup>, I patiently listened to <code>H san</code>’s lecture on Japanese business practices for foreigners…</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Japan as a nation is a tight group. One mistake and you are branded.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I was glad that the ride was less than an hour.</p>
<section id="start-of-the-project" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="start-of-the-project">Start of the Project</h2>
<p>Next morning, <code>H san</code> looked and acted differently than the night before. Calm, with far less words.</p>
<p>I was to meet with the team I was to work with. I wasn’t as concerned about the technical aspect of the transfer. Since I had worked in the industry over 15 years.</p>
<p>I had been chosen for the role, because I knew the Asian culture, not because of the language skills, unlike my role in Korea. However, the remaining concern of the project, communicating with my counterpart, vanished when I met <code>K san</code>.</p>
<p>We had exchanged emails prior to the visit, so I knew her written English skills rivaled natives. It turns out, she had graduated from University of Warwick and had studied British Humor.</p>
<p>I was home free – almost.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/fuji2.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="a-social-lubricant" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="a-social-lubricant">A Social Lubricant</h2>
<p>I had left Korea before I became a teenager.</p>
<p>I returned 25 years later.<br>
Many things had changed. But not the pervasive use of alcohol.</p>
<p>One manager described alcohol as a social lubricant.<br>
Personal experience told me otherwise, it was neither social nor a lubricant.</p>
<p>It may seem to relax people that drink. However, I also saw individuals acting in a way that they would regret later.</p>
<p>If people asked why I didn’t drink, I gave religion as the initial answer. However, if they pressed on with the inquiry – there were additional responses.</p>
<p>There was one more reason – a family one.</p>
<p>I saw how alcohol wrecked lives of my relatives.</p>
<p>They seemed to be mild, coherent person, prior to alcohol consumption. Afterwards, it seemed a darker part of humanity took over.</p>
<p>It seemed they become more bold as restraints were removed. The alcohol laced relatives were not the people I wanted to be social with.</p>
<p>I was able to spend 4 years in Korea and another 6 years of business dealings with a Japanese firm where alcohol was offered and consumed.</p>
<p>I am glad I didn’t participate.</p>
<p>[2 years into the role, a colleague from Texas joined the project. He indicated he drank. Japanese hosts unloaded on him. He could not make it to his hotel without an incident.]</p>
<p>Grateful for the religion and the support around me that encouraged and enforced a life long decision of not drinking alcohol. Also life’s experiences that allowed a choice to pause and react appropriately to <code>H San</code>’s disappointment and the ensuing lecture.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/me.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="memories-of-visits-to-japan" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="memories-of-visits-to-japan">Memories of Visits to Japan</h2>
<p>By suppressing my initial response and overcoming jitters of the first evening in Japan, now I can recall those 6 years of working with the Japanese team.</p>
<p>We would visit Japan several times a year. <code>H San</code> continued to come to Narita to meet us and guide us through Tokyo Station. After 3rd or 4th visit, he would let us find our way to the Marunouchi (丸の内) Hotel ourselves.</p>
<p>Recall fondly his favorite restaurants in Roppongi(六本木) in Tokyo, run by his classmate, and Shabu Shabu place in Hamamatsu (浜松市).</p>
<p>These visits taught me, among others</p>
<ul>
<li>the importance of making the guest/customer welcomed and feel at ease.</li>
<li>know the target for the product and process, work at it and achieve it.<sup>2</sup></li>
<li>invest in and take part in the local food and culture</li>
</ul>
<p>Wondered whether I would have had these opportunities, and completed them, if I hadn’t had religion or had adopted alcohol drinking as a social norm.</p>
<p><img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/card1.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <img src="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/card2.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>These days, <code>H san</code> and I exchange emails regularly. He also sends me, lovely, end of the year greeting cards</p>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>by this time, I had worked in the industry in various roles in US and abroad. Had witnessed several incidences where those that kept their composure was the de facto winner, no matter the outcome↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>the Japanese and the American had a very different view on the length and scope of the training↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>opportunities</category>
  <category>friendships</category>
  <guid>https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://oakhi.github.io/Life-Begins-When/posts/20230615 opportunities pt2/intro.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
